<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:08 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 2 The FTSE 100 .FTSE index of
Britain's leading shares rose 1.1 percent on Tuesday to its
highest level since February 2001, led by mining company Lonmin
(LMI.L) as the sector gained on higher precious metal prices. Lonmin was up 2.3 percent while Anglo-American (AAL.L) rose
2.1 percent and BHP Billiton (BLT.L) gained 1.9 percent. The
gold price jumped to its highest in nearly a month as the dollar
weakened, prompting investors to build fresh trading positions
at the start of the new year, with base metals softer. By 1150 GMT, the FTSE 100 index rose 71.5 points to 6,293.3,
its highest level since 6 February 2001, when it reached
6,306.70. Traders said shares lacked direction, with U.S. markets set
to remain closed on Tuesday to mark the death of former
President Gerald Ford. "This is a good start to the year, ahead of Christmas
trading statements out from tomorrow, but it's a strange day and
shares may come back when there is no trading in New York this
afternoon," said Lawrence Peterman, investment director at Eden
Financial. The UK December Purchasing Managers Index, a gauge of
British manufacturing, came in at 51.9, compared with 52.5 in
November and a forecast 52.6, and was at its lowest since March
2006. The data slightly eased pressure for a short-term interest
rate rise, traders said. House prices in England and Wales rose 0.6 percent on the
month in November, and 6.8 percent year-on-year, according to
Land Registry data. Banks gained on the data because it showed continued growth
in the UK housing market, benefiting mortgages, traders said. Alliance &amp; Leicester AL.L rose 2.5 percent and Barclays
(BARC.L) gained 2 percent. British-based building and plumbing
supplier Wolseley (WOS.L) gained 1.9 percent on related
sentiment. Among other standout gainers, Vodafone (VOD.L) rose 2
percent on market talk that the mobile telecoms giant is less
likely to acquire Hutchison Essar after the Financial Times
reported that India's Essar group, the minority partner in the
mobile phone joint venture, has tied up financing for a
potential bid for the two thirds of the business it does not
own. Former telecoms monopoly BT Group (BT.L) rose 1.8 percent
after Goldman Sachs upped its price target on the stock, traders
said. Elsewhere, Anglo-Dutch steelmaker Corus CS.L rose 1.1
percent. Indian newspapers said that Tata Steel (TISC.BO) was in
the closing stages of putting in a final bid for Corus, which
would raise the stakes in its takeover battle with Brazil's
Companhia Siderurgica nacional (CSN) (CSNA3.SA), citing unnamed
sources close to the development. Oil giant BP (BP.L) rose 0.6 percent and rival Royal Dutch
Shell (RDSa.L) rose 1.3 percent, but they underperformed
relative to some European peers. The oil price fell below $61 a barrel, unmoved by strength
in other financial markets. British Airways BAY.L rose 2.2 percent on continued sector
consolidation talk, traders said.  Property companies were mixed after they converted on
Monday to real estate investment trust (REIT) status, which
gives them a more tax-efficient structure. British Land (BLND.L) rose 0.2 percent after it estimated a
one-off REIT conversion charge of 300 million pounds ($589.6
million), and Land Securities (LAND.L) rose 0.2  percent, but
Hammerson (HMSO.L) fell 0.4 percent.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-britain-stocks-idUSL0291621120070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>ftse rises , miners strong , lonmin leads</title></story></items>