<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:50 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Corrects "pushed" to "push" in first paragraph) By Quentin WebbLONDON Jan 2 (Reuters) - A merger boom and low borrowing
costs helped push global debt issuance to a record $6.9 trillion
in 2006, according to Thomson Financial. The blizzard of debt deals -- up 13 percent from 2005 --
helped banks to enjoy a 26 percent rise in underwriting fees to
$23.9 billion, according to calculations for Thomson by M&amp;A
consultants Freeman &amp; Co. Thomson said a 55 percent jump in global high-yield debt
issuance and increases of more than a quarter in global
investment-grade and emerging markets debt sales had helped fuel
the overall rise. "These sectors have benefited from a record-breaking merger
market, robust financing activity across many industries and
historically low interest rates," Thomson said in a report
released on Tuesday. Thomson data showed global mergers and acquisitions hit a
record $3.8 trillion in 2006, helped by a surge in
private-equity led leveraged buyouts (LBOs), to make up 19.9
percent of deals. High-yield debt issuance was swelled by a "staggering" 127
percent increase in deals to fund LBOs, including the three
largest high-yield deals ever -- from Freescale Semiconductor
Inc, NXP Semiconductors and U.S. hospital operator HCA Inc.
 Structured finance also flourished, particularly issuance of
collateralised debt obligations (CDOs), which repackage credit
risk from bonds, leveraged loans, and other debt securities.
Global CDO sales doubled to $452 billion. It was a good year for Citigroup (C.N), which kept its No. 1
position as global debt bookrunner; JP Morgan (JPM.N), which
moved to second from fourth; and Barclays Capital (BARC.L),
which leapt to seventh place from 11th a year ago. But Lehman Brothers LEH.N and Credit Suisse (CSGN.VX) both
slipped two places to fourth and eighth place, respectively. However, Freeman &amp; Co's "imputed fees," which estimate
unpublished fees using the consultancy's own algorithms,
suggested some banks had reaped the benefits of concentrating on
higher-margin work. Merrill Lynch MER.N, the top adviser on lucrative CDO
deals, ranked 6th by global debt volumes but second only to
Citigroup by imputed fees, earning an estimated $1.51 billion.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/debt-thomson-idUSL0291720920070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds, </value><value>IPOs</value></value></sectors><title>refile - global debt sales at record $ 6 . 9 tln in 06 - thomson</title></story></items>