<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:53 01 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> LOS ANGELES (Hollywood Reporter) - The story of New York it 
girl, fashion icon and Andy Warhol muse Edie Sedgwick (1943-71) 
has taken on the proportions of a cult myth, as do most true 
tales of brief, intense lives. Focusing on the year or so in the mid-1960s when she burned 
brightest and crashed most dramatically, "Factory Girl" boasts 
its own bright intensity, fueled in large part by leads Sienna 
Miller and Guy Pearce. Director George Hickenlooper captures 
the energy and ultra-irony of Warhol's scene, but his attempts 
to give the film a conventional biopic arc end up wallowing in 
dime-store psychology. The central performances will generate 
strong word-of-mouth for the picture. A work-in-progress version that the Weinstein Co. screened 
only weeks ago had a rawer, more immediate power than the final 
cut. In particular, the addition of a framing interview set in 
1970 -- with Miller's Sedgwick in scrubbed California-girl 
mode, having abandoned Manhattan, heavy eyeliner and hard drugs 
-- has a defusing effect, explaining what already is evident, 
especially when it's used in voice-over. Intercut talking-head 
comments from the likes of George Plympton and one of 
Sedgwick's brothers, which provided far more interesting 
context and commentary than the current narration by Sedgwick, 
are now relegated to the end-credits sequence. Some of the changes might have to do with Bob Dylan's 
objections to the original script and threatened legal action. 
He apparently was concerned that the film would draw a 
cause-and-effect line between the end of his relationship with 
Sedgwick and her suicide. (Sedgwick has long been viewed as a 
key inspiration to "Blonde on Blonde"-era Dylan, but whether 
they did indeed have a love affair is less certain.) Coyly 
unnamed in the film, the famous, scruffy musician who 
temporarily draws Edie out of the Warhol orbit is clearly based 
on Dylan. If anything, though, the character, played by a 
charismatic Hayden Christensen, comes across as the sole voice 
of reason in Sedgwick's increasingly out-of-control life. "Factory Girl" draws a too-easy opposition between the 
musician's authenticity and the artificiality of Warhol's world 
of surfaces. But at its strongest, it explores a timeless 
tension between style and substance, form and meaning. At the 
center of this tug of war is the blueblood gamine Sedgwick, a 
striking beauty and would-be artist whose unique glamour snags 
Warhol's heart, inasmuch as he will admit to having one. Perhaps the cruelest irony of Sedgwick's story, as it's 
presented here, is that she escapes her troubled family, albeit 
on trust-fund purse strings, only to end up in the grip of 
another ultimately poisonous clan. If there is a villain here 
besides Edie's father (James Naughton), the part goes to Warhol 
(Pearce). After making Edie the "superstar" of his 
controversial movies, he jealously guilt-trips her over her 
involvement with the rock star. He's an unlikely Oedipal figure 
for Sedgwick, whose suspicions toward happy-family facades are 
explained in all-too-familiar melodramatic fashion. Pearce, one of the most versatile of screen actors, is 
compelling and witty as the pallid Svengali, for whom society 
gossip seeps into even Catholic confession. His anxious, hungry 
gaze conveys envy, self-loathing and a childlike fascination 
with beauty. As the beauty who for a while captivated him 
beyond all others, Miller delivers a powerful performance, 
often baring all to give us Edie at her most candlelit 
exquisite as well as her most degraded. From the throaty laugh 
and old-money inflections to the extreme vulnerability, 
neediness and intelligence, she brings to life Sedgwick's 
legendary allure. Supporting performances are a mixed bag, ranging from the 
awkward (a decidedly unflamboyant Jimmy Fallon as a "flamboyant 
socialite," Mena Suvari as rich girl Richie and Illeana Douglas 
as Diana Vreeland) to the convincing (Armin Amiri as fellow 
Factory girl Ondine, Beth Grant as Andy's mother and Edward 
Herrmann as the Sedgwick family attorney). Screenwriter Captain Mauzner, who co-scripted the John 
Holmes-centered "Wonderland," indulges in too much explanatory 
psychologizing. But stripped of that overlay, his screenplay 
often sizzles with the self-conscious humor of smart 
nonconformists. Cinematographer Michael Grady ably helps 
Hickenlooper pay homage to Warhol's inventively bad-is-good 
filmmaking and renowned B&amp;W screen tests. Playing '60s New 
York, Shreveport, La., lends a fitting vintage feel, while the 
production design by Jeremy Reed and John Dunn's costumes 
create an exuberant blend of high society and underground 
scene. Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/film-film-factory-dc-idUSN2820662920070103</link><sectors><value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>Film</value></value></sectors><title>factory girl affords more fame to warhol muse</title></story></items>