<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:33 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>PARIS Jan 2 European shares kicked off the New
Year on an upbeat note on Tuesday as merger activity in the
telecoms and French utility sectors helped the region's top
stock indices march to new multi-year highs. Vodafone (VOD.L) climbed 1.8 percent on talk the cell phone
giant was less likely to acquire Hutchison Essar after the
Financial Times said India's Essar group had tied up financing
for a potential bid for the two-thirds of the business it does
not own. Strong miners such as Anglo American (AAL.L) also helped, as
did BNP Paribas (BNPP.PA), up 2.5 percent. The French bank was
France's top M&amp;A adviser in 2006 for the second year running,
ahead of U.S. rivals Goldman Sachs (GS.N) and Merrill Lynch
MER.N, a report by financial newspaper L'Agefi said. The FTSEurofirst 300 .FTEU3 index of top European shares
was up 0.96 points at 1,497.64 points, its highest intraday
level since February 2001. The FTSEurofirst 300 index ended 2006
on gains of 16 percent, bringing to 113 percent its overall
rally since the market's multi-year trough of March 2003.  European equity markets were widely expected to climb for a
fifth consecutive year in 2007, but strategists warned that
slowing earnings growth would cap rises in equity returns. "We think European equity markets will rise again over the
course of 2007. Our forecast suggests a total return of 14
percent," said Ian Scott, strategist at Lehman Brothers.
"However, we think that the internal dynamics of the market are
likely to differ substantially from those that have
characterised the rally since 2003." "While we foresee headwinds of declining earnings growth, we
believe that favourable valuations of equities relative to other
asset classes, and supportive fund flows, will provide scope for
further outperformance." Around Europe, London's FTSE 100 .FTSE index and Paris's
CAC 40 .FCHI both gained 1.2 percent, while Frankfurt's DAX
.GDAXI rose 1 percent. Trading volumes were thin as many market players were still
on holiday and U.S. stock markets were closed for a national day
of mourning for former President Gerald Ford who died last week. Investors now looked ahead to a batch of U.S. reports on
non-farm payrolls and manufacturing activity, and a Federal
Reserve's interest rate decision, and fourth-quarter corporate
results due later this month. In the meantime, merger and takeover activity gave no signs
of abating. In France, billionaire Francois Pinault declined to rule out
making an offer for Suez LYOE.PA, adding to uncertainty
surrounding the utility's plan to merge with state-controlled
Gaz de France GAZ.PA. Suez shares gained 1.4 percent. Shares in Veolia Environnement (VIE.PA), which had soared 9
percent on Friday, were down 4 percent. French press reports
have said that Pinault would sell Suez's environmental business
to Veolia. In the steel sector, Anglo-Dutch steel group Corus CS.L
added 1 percent after Indian newspapers reported Tata Steel
(TISC.BO) would raise its bid for the company. (Additional reporting by Sitaraman Shankar in London)





</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-europe-stocks-idUSL0213939120070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>european shares hit highest point in almost 6 - years</title></story></items>