<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:54 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> Market holiday - Markets and exchanges closed. Public holiday - Government offices, banks and ordinary
businesses closed. 
 REUTERS DIARY OF MIDDLE EAST/AFRICAN HOLIDAYS Double-click in brackets for Americas holidays [HOL1/DIARY],
Asian holidays [HOL2/DIARY] and European holidays [HOL3/DIARY] 
 Alternatively click on HOLIDAY to retrieve dates by
country. 
 ** Details below represent the latest information available and
will be supplemented later, particularly with updated entries
for Muslim holidays. 
 (Note: Dates for Eid al-Fitr, Eid el-Adha, Muslim New Year
and Prophet Mohammed's Birthday may differ slightly depending on
the sighting of the moon) 
 
 ****************************************************         2006/7 MARKET/PUBLIC HOLIDAYS **************************************************** 
 
 DECEMBER 
 SATURDAY, DEC 16 Bahrain - National Day - Market Holiday South Africa - Day of Reconciliation  - Market Holiday 
 SUNDAY, DEC 17 Bahrain - National Day - Market Holiday 
 MONDAY, DEC 25 South Africa - Christmas Day - Market Holiday 
 TUESDAY, DEC 26 South Africa - Day of Goodwill - Market Holiday SUNDAY, DEC 31 Egypt - Eid El Adha - Market and Public holiday (subject to
sighting of the moon) 
 * More countries will be added as and when they become
available. 
 
 MONDAY, JAN 1 
 Bahrain - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday Egypt - New year/Eid El-Adha - Market holiday(subject to
lunar sightings). Jordan - New Year/Eid El-Adha - Market Holiday Kuwait - Eid Al Adha - Market holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Oman - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) Saudi Arabia - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday South Africa - New Year's Day -  Market Holiday 
 
 TUESDAY, JAN 2 Egypt - Eid El-Adha - Market holiday(subject to lunar
sightings). Jordan - Eid El-Adha - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Kuwait - Eid Al Adha - Market holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Oman - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) Saudi Arabia - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, JAN 3 Egypt - Eid El-Adha - Market holiday(subject to lunar
sightings). Jordan - Eid El-Adha - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Saudi Arabia - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday 
 THURSDAY, JAN 4 Egypt - Eid El-Adha - Market holiday(subject to lunar
sightings). Jordan - Eid El-Adha - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) 
 SUNDAY, JAN 7 Egypt - Eastern Christmas - Market Holiday 
 THURSDAY, JAN 18 Kuwait - Islamic New Year - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) 
 SUNDAY, JAN 21 Egypt - Islamic New Year - Market Holiday Jordan - Islamic New Year - Market Holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) 
 SUNDAY, JAN 28 Bahrain - Ashura - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 TUESDAY, JAN 30 Jordan - New Kings Birthday - Market Holiday 
 SUNDAY, FEB 25 Kuwait - National/Liberation Days - Market holiday 
 MONDAY, FEB 26 Kuwait - National/Liberation Days - Market holiday 
 SUNDAY, MARCH 4 Israel - Purim - Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, MARCH 21 South Africa - Human Rights Day -  Market Holiday 
 THURSDAY, MARCH 29 Kuwait - Prophet's Birthday - Market holiday (subject
to lunar sightings) 
 SUNDAY, APRIL 1 Egypt - Prophet Mohammad's Birthday - Market Holiday
(subject lunar sightings) Jordan - Prophet Mohammad's Birthday - Market Holiday
(subject to lunar sightings) 
 MONDAY, APRIL 2 Israel - Passover I Eve - Market Holiday 
 TUESDAY, APRIL 3 Israel - Passover I - Market Holiday 
 FRIDAY, APRIL 6 South Africa - Good Friday -  Market Holiday 
 SUNDAY, APRIL 8 Egypt - Eastern Easter - Market holiday Israel - Passover II Eve - Market Holiday 
 MONDAY, APRIL 9 South Africa - Family day -  Market Holiday Israel - Passover II - Market Holiday 
 MONDAY, APRIL 23 Israel - Memorial day - Market Holiday 
 TUESDAY, APRIL 24 Israel - Independence day - Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, APRIL 25 Egypt - Sinai Liberation Day - Market holiday 
 TUESDAY, MAY 1 Bahrain - Labour day -  Market holiday Egypt - Labour Day - Market Holdiay Jordan - Labour Day - Market Holiday South Africa - Workers day -  Market Holiday 
 TUESDAY, MAY 22 Israel - Pentecost (Shavuot) Eve - Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, MAY 23 Israel - Pentecost (Shavuot) - Market Holiday 
 SATURDAY, MAY 25 Jordan - Indedpendence Day - Market holiday 
 SATURDAY, JUNE 16 South Africa - Youth Day -  Market Holiday 
 MONDAY, JULY 23 Egypt - National Day - Market Holiday Oman - Renaissance - Market Holiday 
 TUESDAY, JULY 24 Israel - Fast Day - Market Holiday 
 THURSDAY, AUG 9 Kuwait - Isra Wa Birthday - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) South Africa - National Women's Day -  Market Holiday 
 SATURDAY, AUG 11 Jordan - Isra'a and Me'raj - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) 
 WEDNESDAY, SEPT 12 Israel - Jewish New Year's Eve - Market Holiday 
 THURSDAY, SEPT 13 Israel - Jewish New Year I - Market Holiday 
 FRIDAY, SEPT 14 Israel - Jewish New Year II - Market Holiday 
 FRIDAY, SEPT 21 Israel - Yom Kippur - Market Holiday 
 MONDAY, SEPT 24 South Africa - Heritage Day -  Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, SEPT 26 Israel - Feast of Tabernacles (Sukkot) - Market Holiday 
 THURSDAY, SEPT 27 Israel - Feast of Tabernacles (Sukkot) - Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, OCT 3 Israel - Rejoicing of the Law (Simchat) - Market
Holiday 
 THURSDAY, OCT 4 Israel - Rejoicing of the Law (Simchat) - Market Holida 
 SATURDAY. OCT 13 Jordan - Al-Fiter Feast - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) 
 SUNDAY, OCT 14 Bahrain - Eid Al Fitr - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings). Egypt - Eid El-Fitr - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Jordan - Al-Fiter Feast - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) Kuwait - Eid Al Fitr - Market holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Oman - Eid Al Fitr - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 MONDAY, OCT 15 Egypt - Eid El-Fitr - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Jordan - Al-Fiter Feast - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) Kuwait - Eid Al Fitr - Market holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Oman - Eid Al Fitr - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 TUESDAY, OCT 16 Egypt - Eid El-Fitr - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Jordan - Al-Fiter Feast - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sightings) Oman - Eid Al Fitr - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 WEDNESDAY, OCT 17 Egypt - Eid El-Fitr - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) 
 WEDNESDAY, NOV 14 Jordan - King's Birthday - Market holiday 
 SUNDAY, NOV 18 Oman - National Day - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 MONDAY, NOV 19 Oman - National Day - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 SUNDAY, DEC 16 Bahrain - National Day - Market Holiday 
 MONDAY, DEC 17 Bahrain - National Day - Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, DEC 19 Bahrain - Eid Al Adha - Market holiday (subject to
lunar sighting) Kuwait - Mount Arafat Day/1st day of Eid Al Adha - Market
holiday (subject to lunar sightings) Oman - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 THURSDAY, DEC 20 Bahrain - Eid Al Adha - Market holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) Kuwait - Eid Al Adha - Market holiday (subject to lunar
sightings) Oman - Eid Al Adha - Market Holiday (subject to lunar
sighting) 
 TUESDAY, DEC 25 Jordan - X-Mas Day - Market Holiday South Africa - Christmas Day - Market Holiday 
 WEDNESDAY, DEC 26 South Africa - Day of Goodwill - Market Holiday 
 
 ** For more holidays information, double click on HOLIDAY 
 
 -------------------------------------------------------- RT users double-click on [IND/DIARY] for an index of all
diaries. -------------------------------------------------------- Reuter Diary Desk +00 44 207 542 7992, or e-mail derek.ryan@reuters.com or derek.ryan@reuters.com 
 NOTE: The inclusion of diary items does not necessarily mean
that Reuters will file a story based on the event.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/diary-mideast-african-holidays-idUSL0922378620070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>diary - mideast / african holidays to december 2007</title></story></items>