<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:48 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>FRANKFURT DaimlerChrysler DCXGn.DE and a 
group of insurers have agreed to settle a dispute over 
recovering the costs of a U.S. class-action lawsuit in 2003, 
the German car maker and insurers said on Tuesday. Spokesmen for DaimlerChrysler and U.S. insurer ACE (ACE.N), 
which led a consortium of insurers, said that an agreement had 
been reached, but declined to give details. The head of ACE's German operations, Lothar Riedle, told 
Reuters he hoped the settlement would spark a discussion in 
Germany about whether Director's &amp; Officer's liability 
insurance coverage was too broad. The Financial Times Deutschland reported on Tuesday that a 
group of insurance companies led by ACE had agreed shortly 
before the end of the year to pay DaimlerChrysler 168 million 
euros ($221.5 million) to settle the dispute. The paper did not cite sources for the story. DaimlerChrysler agreed in August 2003 to pay some U.S. 
shareholders around 275 million euros to settle allegations 
that the 1998 deal to form the world's fifth-biggest carmaker 
was a takeover of Chrysler by Daimler-Benz, not a merger of 
equals as the company had said. At the time, DaimlerChrysler said insurance would cover up 
to 200 million euros of the cost. The Financial Times Deutschland said the group of insurers 
led by ACE in the talks included France's AXA (AXAF.PA), 
Germany's Gerling and HDI, Chubb (CB.N), XL Capital (XL.N), 
Zurich Financial (ZURN.VX) and Basler (BALN.VX). Axa and Zurich Financial confirmed that they were part of 
the insurance consortium deal but declined further comment, 
Gerling and HDI declined comment, while Basler, Chubb, and XL 
were not immediately available for comment. The paper said that insurer AIG (AIG.N) had already agreed 
to pay 25 million euros to Daimler and that the late December 
agreement with ACE meant that Daimler had recovered most of the 
money it had sought. DaimlerChrysler shares were trading up 2 percent at 47.71 
euros by 1422 GMT, outpacing a 1.2 percent rise in the DJ Stoxx 
index of European automobile shares .SXAP.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/businesspro-daimlerchrysler-insurers-dc-idUSL0290207520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>insurers , daimlerchrysler settle dispute</title></story></items>