<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:36 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates prices, quotes) By Lincoln FeastLONDON Jan 2 (Reuters) - Global stock markets made a
positive start to 2007, hitting fresh record peaks on Tuesday,
while the euro rose as still solid manufacturing data supported
expectations of more euro zone interest rate rises. On the first day of trade for the year, the MSCI All-Country
World Index .MSCIWD rose 0.7 percent to a new all-time peak of
370.4 points as markets in Hong Kong .HSI and Australia
.AXJO hit record highs. In Europe, the FTSEurofirst 300 Index .FTEU3 climbed 1
percent to 1,499 points, its highest intraday level since Feb.
2001. Volumes were light with U.S. stock markets closed to mark
the death of former President Gerald Ford and Tokyo markets also
closed. Stocks ended a strong 2006 on a high and most strategists
see the potential for further gains, supported by still
reasonable valuations, earnings growth and a relatively robust
global economy. "We think European equity markets will rise again over the
course of 2007. Our forecast suggests a total return of 14
percent," said Ian Scott, a strategist at Lehman Brothers. "While we foresee headwinds of declining earnings growth, we
believe that favourable valuations of equities relative to other
asset classes, and supportive fund flows, will provide scope for
further outperformance." Others including Morgan Stanley said macro economic concerns
could cause some short-term jitters and recommended investors
buy some protection against a correction in the coming months. Early manufacturing data from the euro zone showed growth
remained strong, but off its mid-year peak.
 The RBS/NTC Eurozone Purchasing Managers' Index slipped to a
nine-month low of 56.5 in December but the average reading for
2006 of 56.3 was more than five points higher than the average
2005 reading and well above the 50 level that separates growth
from contraction. Mark Miller, an economist at HBOS Treasury Services, said an
unexpected slowdown in French manufacturing growth accounted for
much of the weakness across the euro zone.  "Encouragingly, the export component has held up even in the
face of a U.S. slowdown," he said. "There's nothing in these surveys that suggests (euro zone
interest) rates don't go up in the first quarter of this year,
probably in March."
 EURO STRONG Solid economic data and expectations of further interest
rate rises from the European Central Bank underpinned a strong
2006 for the euro which rose some 11 percent against the dollar. The euro began 2007 in a similar vein, rising against the
dollar and hitting a record high against the yen at 157.72 yen
EURJPY=. "We're starting the year very much the way we left last
year, with a high-yield/low-yield story. You've got ECB rate
expectations fairly robust and question marks about what the
Federal Reserve will do," Mellon Bank head of currency research
Ian Gunner said. The euro was 0.6 percent higher on the session at $1.3273,
while the dollar was down 0.2 percent at 118.85 yen JPY=. Currencies such as the Australian AUD= and New Zealand
dollar NZD= also made strong starts to 2007, benefiting from
their interest rate advantages over other currencies especially
the yen. The Australian dollar hit nine-year highs above 94.30 yen
AUDJPY=R as the market priced in more risk of a further
increase in Australian interest rates.
 BONDS REBOUND, COMMODITIES MIXED The firmer euro lent support to euro zone government bonds,
which were battered in December as expectations of U.S. interest
rate cuts early this year faded.  The March Bund future FGBLH7 was up 32 ticks at 116.35,
extending gains after the weaker-than-forecast PMI data. U.S. ISM manufacturing data, originally due for release on
Tuesday at 1500 GMT, was delayed until Wednesday due to the day
of mourning for President Ford, while markets were also looking
ahead to Friday's non-farm payrolls report. A robust jobs market has helped U.S. consumer spending hold
up in the face of a housing market slump, with lower energy
prices also lending support. Oil prices ticked higher in holiday-disrupted trade on
Tuesday, with U.S. light crude CLc1 up around 30 cents a
barrel to $61.35 amid forecasts of continued mild weather in the
U.S. Northeast. Other commodities were mixed, with gold hitting a one-month
high near $641 an ounce on the back of the weaker dollar, but
copper MCU3 fell as stocks in London Metal Exchange-registered
warehouses leapt to their highest since March 2004.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-global-idUSL0290679420070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>global markets - stocks start 2007 at record peaks , euro strong</title></story></items>