<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:58 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Playtech (PTEC.L) is hopeful a deal to 
power PartyGaming's PRTY.L newly acquired gambling Web sites 
could lead to further deals to sell PartyGaming its Asian 
games, Chief Executive Avigur Zmora said on Tuesday. After the United States effectively banned online gaming in 
November, both companies stated they would look to Asia to 
drive future growth, with Playtech launching online Mahjong and 
Pachinko there last month. "If they have serious aspirations in Asia, I'm sure they 
will shop for product -- it's not a product you can develop in 
one day -- and I'm sure Playtech will be one of the leading 
options," Zmora told Reuters. "The second you have a relationship, it's much easier to 
involve them with new products. Party is looking at similar 
areas geographically, with the focus in Asia, so it might lead 
to further business down the line." Playtech said earlier on Tuesday it had struck a four-year 
deal with PartyGaming to power gaming Web sites that 
PartyGaming has agreed to buy from Empire Online EOL.L and 
Intercontinental Online. The Web sites that are being acquired by PartyGaming 
include NoblePoker.com, Clubdicecasino.com, EnterCasino.com, 
MissBingo.com, FairPoker.com and MagicBoxCasino.com. Zmora said integrating the players of rival Tribeca, which 
Playtech agreed to buy in November, would probably be completed 
by the end of the first quarter of 2007. The $75 million deal brought with it a number of Internet 
gambling websites operating on Tribeca's poker software 
platform, including VCPoker, PaddyPower Poker, Blue Square 
Poker and Scandinavian group, Expekt. "There are very high margins because of the great 
synergies," said Zmora. "The vast majority of the expenses are 
going away -- the developers are already there, and it needs a 
little bit of customer support, a little bit of graphics." "They're talking about something like $4 million a quarter, 
during August, September, October, then you can expect about 
80-85 percent of that going to Playtech's bottom line." Zmora said that Playtech would also benefit from 
significant cross-selling of online games to players using 
PartyGaming's new websites. "Cross-selling will be significant," he said, adding that 
generally, roughly 10 to 30 percent of players would typically 
cross between linked sites. Zmora said there were further opportunities available for 
acquisitions in the online gaming sector.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-playtech-interview-dc-idUSWLA715020070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>playtech hopeful of asian deals with partygaming</title></story></items>