<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:08 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> TORONTO, Jan 2 The Canadian dollar was slightly
higher versus the U.S. dollar on Tuesday given the jump in gold
prices, but the broader North American economic picture weighed
on the currency in quiet trading. Domestic bonds prices hung onto slim gains in what is
expected be a quiet session given the lack of any economic data
and a U.S. treasury market scheduled to close early. At 9:00 a.m. (1400 GMT), the Canadian unit was at C$1.1645
to the U.S. dollar, or 85.87 U.S. cents, up from C$1.1654 to
the U.S. dollar, or 85.81 U.S. cents, at Friday's close. Canadian markets were closed on Monday. The commodity-linked Canadian dollar took advantage of gold
prices that reached their highest level in nearly one month as
the weaker U.S. dollar boosted demand for the metal. But the gains were limited as oil prices hovered just above
$61 a barrel as mild weather in the United States capped demand
for fuel and weighed on prices. The commodity-linked Canadian dollar often shadows the
moves in oil and gold prices since Canada is a producer and net
exporter of oil and many base metals. But many expect the Bank of Canada's Monetary Policy Report
in mid-January to reflect the recent wave of weaker economic
data, and dealers said that is keeping the Canadian dollar in
check. Concerns about a weaker North American economy and the
likelihood of lower interest rates on both sides of the border
have weighed on the Canadian and U.S. dollars recently. "We've had most of the data come out over the last couple
of months on the soft side and I think this is definitely going
to be reflected when we get the Monetary Policy Report from the
Bank of Canada," said Carolyn Kwan, markets economist at Scotia
Capital." "The fundamental story is weighing on the Canadian dollar
for sure and in addition we have commodity prices weakening off
more broadly." Giving the Canadian dollar a slight boost was news that
U.S. steelmaker Nucor Corp. (NUE.N) agreed to purchase Canada's
Harris Steel Group Inc. HSG.TO for C$1.25 billion. Foreign takeovers of Canadian companies -- and the
accompanying purchase of Canadian dollars to finance them --
have been key supports for the currency. BONDS UP IN THIN TRADE Domestic bonds prices bounced back slightly after falling
all of last week, but thin liquidity exaggerated the move. U.S. treasuries will close early for a day of mourning to
honor former U.S. President Gerald Ford, while Japanese markets
were closed for a market holiday. "We've got generally quiet conditions all around and people
are going to be taking today to reassess the picture and see
how things should be set up for the new year," said Kwan. The the two-year bond was up 4 Canadian cents at C$100.45
to yield 4.003 percent, while the 10-year bond was up 26
Canadian cents at C$99.61 to yield 4.050 percent. The yield spread between the two-year and 10-year bond
moved to 5.2 basis points from 6.2 at the previous close. The 30-year bond rose 53 Canadian cents to C$125.25 to
yield 4.111 percent. In the United States, the 30-year treasury
yielded 4.783 percent. The three-month when-issued T-bill yielded 4.16 percent, up
from 4.15 percent at the previous close.
































</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-canada-dollar-bonds-idUSN0229934320070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>canada dollar follows gold high , bonds inch higher</title></story></items>