<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:57 31 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Russian gas giant Gazprom's decision to 
take a majority stake in the Royal Dutch Shell-led Sakhalin-2 
project may save the European Bank for Reconstruction and 
Development (EBRD) from having to approve its most 
controversial loan application ever. Analysts and industry executives said the fact Gazprom is 
government-controlled means the EBRD will likely be precluded 
by its charter from extending a loan to the project. The bank was founded to help the countries of the former 
Soviet bloc move toward market economies but the Sakhalin deal 
-- which followed months of pressure on the project partners 
from the Russian government -- amounts to a renationalization 
of the Sakhalin-2 oil and gas fields, analysts say. "This new development certainly does make it more difficult 
for the bank (to participate) and it may certainly make the 
EBRD less needed in the project," said Brigid Janssen, the 
EBRD's director of communications. Shortly before Gazprom, Shell and their Japanese partners 
Mitsui and Mitsubishi in the $22 billion project announced the 
deal on December 21, Mitsui and Mitsubishi told analysts that 
the project may no longer seek financing from the EBRD and 
other western government-backed lenders. Previously, the EBRD was under pressure from its owners -- 
mainly western nations -- to approve the strategic project, 
sources inside the EBRD and industry sources said, despite 
sharp criticism from environmentalists.
 POOR RECORD The EBRD is supposed to demand strict environmental 
compliance from its borrowers and green groups said Shell's 
poor record in managing Sakhalin-2 meant the project did not 
qualify. Janssen said the EBRD had not yet decided on whether the 
project met its environmental criteria and had yet not decided 
whether Gazprom's involvement precluded a loan. Sakhalin-2 is 80 percent complete and industry executives 
and analysts expect the project to be completed irrespective of 
whether it secures a $6 billion to 7 billion finance package 
from the EBRD and others. Oil and gas production will occur near the feeding grounds 
of the endangered Western Gray Whale and pipelines transporting 
the oil and gas must cross more than 1,100 rivers and water 
courses. Shell admitted failings but said these had been rectified. EBRD insiders conceded the bank's reputation as an 
environmentally conscientious lender was on the line but the 
bank feels its involvement over recent years had prodded Shell 
to improve the project's record. The EBRD's strict environmental rules mean other lenders 
often base their lending decisions on whether the bank decides 
a project is environmentally sound. Gazprom's involvement in the project, at what analysts saw 
as a knock-down price, is a big blow for Shell. Following the 
deal, analysts at Citigroup cut their earnings forecasts for 
the Anglo-Dutch oil major by 4 percent after 2009, when the 
project comes fully onstream.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-gazprom-shell-sakhalin-dc-idUSL3188275620070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>gazprom ' s sakhalin - 2 buy may let ebrd off the hook</title></story></items>