<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:14 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TORONTO Jan 2 Canadian gold miners could be
among issues seeing a bounce in the Toronto Stock Exchange's
first trading session of 2007 on Tuesday, as bullion prices
benefit from a weaker U.S. dollar. As well, fresh merger and acquisition activity, with the
proposed C$1.25 billion purchase of Harris Steel Group Inc.HSG.TO by Nucor Corp. (NUE.N) announced before the opening
bell, could bode well for Canadian equities. The exchange's main S&amp;P/TSX composite index rose 14.5
percent in 2006, in no small part thanks to a piping hot mining
sector that helped drive the gains. "We have seen some strength on the materials side over the
course of the last week or so, and we expect to see further
strength really throughout the year," said Neil Andrew,
associate portfolio manager at Leeward Hedge Funds in Toronto. The resources-heavy materials group of the composite
returned 38 percent in 2006. The day's session could also see gold miners' gains
extended, as the price of their product rose to its highest in
nearly a month while the euro rose against the U.S. dollar. "The U.S. dollar was overdue for a bounce," Andrew said.
"Now that seems to be likely to unwind, naturally supportive to
gold prices." A weaker dollar can spur demand for gold, which in turn
could bode well for the share prices of Canadian gold miners,
which include companies such as Barrick Gold Corp. (ABX.TO) and
Agnico-Eagle Mines Ltd. (AEM.TO) Takeovers of Canadian companies also boosted the Toronto
market last year and the trend showed no sign of abating for
2007 with the Harris deal announced Tuesday. Harris said Nucor has made an all-cash offer to buy the
Canadian steel maker for C$46.25 per share. Harris closed at
C$43.49 on Dec. 29. Trading volumes may remain thin as money managers and
investors wind up extended holiday breaks. As well, stock
trading will not reopen in the United States until Wednesday,
as the country observes a day of mourning for former U.S.
President Gerald Ford. "I think we're going to see the volumes slowly pick up
throughout the week," Andrew said. ($1=$1.16 Canadian)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-canada-stocks-idUSN0247128820070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>gold miners , m &amp; a could drive toronto stocks higher</title></story></items>