<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:05 31 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text>MOSCOW Russia and Belarus announced a 
last-minute deal on gas prices on Monday, moments before Moscow 
was to start cutting off supplies with potential disruption for 
customers in Europe. Belarus Prime Minister Sergei Sidorsky arrived at Russian 
gas monopoly Gazprom's Moscow headquarters barely 30 minutes 
before Sunday's midnight deadline to sign the deal. Gazprom (GAZP.MM) had threatened to cut supplies to Belarus 
from January 1 if a deal on new gas prices to its neighbor was 
not reached by midnight. Minsk said it would retaliate by 
halting Russian gas crossing the country on its way to Western 
Europe. "A mid-term agreement was reached on gas prices to Belarus 
and on transit shipments to Europe," Gazprom boss Alexei Miller 
told a news briefing early on Monday. Russia supplies around a quarter of Europe's gas demands 
and pumps 20 percent of this amount through Belarus. The gas row revived memories of a similar dispute with 
ex-Soviet Ukraine exactly one year ago which briefly disrupted 
Russian deliveries to Europe and shook confidence in Russia's 
reliability as an energy supplier. Under the accord, Belarus agreed to pay Gazprom $100 per 
1,000 cubic meters of natural gas, up from the $46 ex-Soviet 
Belarus has been paying until now.
 VISIBLY DISPLEASED By comparison, Gazprom charges European customers over 
$250. In the past 12 months, Russia has agreed hefty price rises 
with ex-Soviet Ukraine, Georgia, Armenia and Moldova. "The terms which have been fixed in this current agreement 
are the best which exist on the territory of the Former Soviet 
Union," Miller said. Around 10 million people live in Belarus. Its economy is 
still largely run on a Soviet-style command system and its 
industry relies heavily on cheap energy imports to remain 
profitable. Western critics have accused the Kremlin of using the gas 
price increases as a political weapon to punish some of its 
neighbors for moving closer to the West. Belarus though does not fit into that category. Its 
President Alexander Lukashenko has quarreled with the West and 
wants closer ties with Moscow. At the joint press conference Belarus Prime Minister 
Sidorsky looked visibly displeased by the price rises. "We don't have much natural resources. You (Russia) have 
put us in a difficult situation, but we will stay strong," he 
said. In the deal Gazprom will also pay $2.5 billion to control 
half of Belarus's pipelines for four years and agreed to pay 
double to transit gas through Belarus to Europe. (Additional reporting by Andrei Makhovsky in Minsk)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-russia-belarus-gas-dc-idUSL3084973120070102</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>russia , belarus sign gas deal</title></story></items>