<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:38 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 2 U.S. government bond prices rose
on Tuesday in a modest recovery from last week's sell-off on
stronger than expected economic reports, traders said. Volume was light during a session shortened for a day of
mourning to honor former U.S. President Gerald Ford. Many trading
desks were thinly staffed as financial markets were either closed
or open only for a half-session on Tuesday, when the United States
holds a national funeral service for the former president. "This is that sort of bounce that you get after the pounding
the bond market took last week," said Kevin Flanagan, fixed income
strategist for global wealth management with Morgan Stanley in
Purchase, New York. "I wouldn't read too much into it and we are still at a kind
of half staffed situation," Flanagan said. The key question once the market reacts to the manufacturing
and jobs reports later this week is how U.S. government debt
investors view the 10-year note's 4.70 percent yield level after
last month's sell-off, Flanagan added. Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR were up 1/32 in price for
a yield of 4.70 percent, versus 4.70 percent late on Friday.
Markets had been closed on Monday for the New Year's Day public
holiday. Two-year notes US2YT=RR, which respond closely to
expectations for Federal Reserve interest rate moves, rose 1/32 in
price to yield 4.80 percent, compared with 4.82 percent on
Friday. The Securities Industry and Financial Markets Association has
recommended an early bond market close at 2 p.m. (1900 GMT) and
the key manufacturing report of the week, the Institute for Supply
Management (ISM)'s index has been rescheduled for Wednesday. That leaves Tuesday virtually devoid of economic data for bond
investors. The manufacturing report on Wednesday and the monthly
nonfarm payrolls report, due on Friday, could be major catalysts
for the Treasury market. "Given the proximity of ISM and nonfarm payrolls we deem it
reasonable to be neutral at current levels, albeit with a bit of a
negative bias due to the evident technical damage incurred last
month," wrote David Ader, head of government bond strategy with
RBS Greenwich Capital in Greenwich, Connecticut in a daily
research note. The 10-year note's yield, which moves inversely to its price,
jumped to 4.70 percent at the end of December from 4.46 percent at
the start of last month. Last week, stronger-than-expected U.S. economic reports on
home sales, consumer confidence and a Chicago manufacturing index
weighed on bond prices as prospects of a Federal Reserve interest
rate cut early this year appeared to dwindle. "The November data, at least, reinforces the idea the Fed's on
hold," Ader wrote. Prospects for the Fed to lower rates by June, as shown by
short-term U.S. interest rate futures, had fallen to about 58
percent late on Friday after being fully priced as recently
as Dec. 21. Further insight into the Federal Reserve's thinking may come
from the release on Wednesday of the minutes from its
last monetary policy meeting on Dec 12. The 30-year bond US30YT=RR rose 6/32 in price for a yield of
4.80 percent, versus 4.81 percent late on Friday.
 (Additional reporting by Kirsten Donovan in London)







</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-bonds-idUSN0221048720070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - prices recover from last week ' s sell - off</title></story></items>