<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:13 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts, adds quotes background) By Alister Doyle, Environment CorrespondentOSLO Jan 2 (Reuters) - Norway plans to join Britain in
offsetting greenhouse gases caused by bureaucrats jetting around
the world, announcing it will buy emissions quotas to combat
global warming. Emissions from jet fuel burnt on international flights are
among the fastest-growing sources of greenhouse gases with
cheaper flights but are exempted under the U.N.'s Kyoto Protocol
for fighting climate change until 2012. "The government has decided that when state employees travel
by plane abroad, we will buy quotas for the emissions caused by
the trip," Norwegian Prime Minister Jens Stoltenberg said in a
New Year speech. He did not say how much it would cost. Britain has been capturing emissions by government and
ministerial air travel since April 2006. The government said
last week it was spending up to 3 million pounds ($5.92 million)
to buy 255,000 tonnes of carbon credits for 2007-09. "These two governments are the only ones I know of with
these projects," said Sue Welland, founder of the British-based
CarbonNeutral Company which promotes investments in solar power,
windmills or forests to counter emissions from fossil fuels.
 COMPANIES LEAD "A lot of companies are doing this already -- in that
respect governments are behind the private sector," Welland
said. She said corporate tenders rose tenfold in late 2006 over
a year earlier and individuals were getting far more involved. Companies including car rental group Avis Europe AVE.L or
Norwegian oil group Statoil (STL.OL) are among those offsetting
emissions from employees' flights. Some airlines offer the
option of paying extra to offset emissions. A 2002 U.N. Earth Summit in Johannesburg was the first major
governmental meeting to try to be "carbon neutral", funding
renewable energy projects to soak up emissions from delegates'
use of fossil fuels in everything from transport to electricity. But only a handful of nations among 200 signed up and the
project fell far short of a $5 million target. "I think this is a very good idea when international
aviation is not a part of the Kyoto Protocol," Lars Haltbrekken,
chairman of Friends of the Earth Norway, said of the government
offsets. Still, it might smack of tokenism. Norway is the world's number three oil producer and
greenhouse gas emissions were 10.3 percent above 1990 levels in
2004. Britain's emissions were 14.3 percent below 1990 after a
sharp decline in use of polluting coal. Kyoto obliges 35 rich nations to cut emissions to 5 percent
below 1990 levels by 2008-12 as a first step to prevent a
warming that most scientists say will cause floods, heatwaves,
extinctions and raise global sea levels.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/norway-greenhouse-idUSL0285713920070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - norway , uk try to tackle planes ' greenhouse gases</title></story></items>