<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:31 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>  (Adds details, changes dateline, previous NEW YORK)CHICAGO Jan 2 (Reuters) - The Chicago Board of Trade  said
on Tuesday it logged a fifth straight year of record volume in
2006, capped off by continued strong turnover in December. In what might have been the venerable exchange's final year
as an independent entity, average daily volume rose by 40
percent in December to 2.767 million contracts, pushing total
volume for the month up 33 percent from a year before to 55.3
million contracts. There was one more trading day in December
2005. December's average daily volume gains at the No. 2 U.S.
futures exchange accelerated slightly from the 38 percent
year-on-year increase seen in November. For all of 2006, total CBOT volume reached almost 805.9
million contracts for a daily average of 3.2 million, up 20
percent from the previous year. Total fourth-quarter volume was
up 36 percent from a year earlier. CBOT's rate per contract for the three months through
November was 64.5 cents per contract, up from 63.8 cents for
the three months through October and 61.8 cents in the third
quarter. The rate per contract, a key measure of margins, is
reported on a one-month lag. December's volume rose strongly across CBOT's four product
segments. Financial futures and options turnover rose 40 percent from
December 2006 to account for almost 78 percent of exchange
volume, similar to a year before. The biggest growth was at the
short end of the yield curve, especially in two-year Treasury
notes. Average daily volume in agricultural contracts rose by 36
percent in December and by almost 85 percent in the fourth
quarter. Turnover has been boosted by the move to side-by-side
electronic and open outcry trading during the summer. Volatile trading in corn and wheat futures and options,
where volume rose by 72 percent and 58 percent respectively to
record highs, was another factor. CBOT's metals segment continued to expand sharply, with
average daily volume of 52,641 contracts in December up 332
percent on the year. Shares in CBOT Holdings Inc. BOT.N, parent of the
exchange, closed on Friday at $151.47, up 61.5 percent on the
year. CBOT shares peaked in November at $165.27, a few weeks
after the exchange's proposed merger with the Chicago
Mercantile Exchange was announced. If the merger was completed, CBOT Holdings would be merged
into Chicago Mercantile Exchange Holdings Inc. CME.N; the
combined company would be renamed CME Group Inc., with the CME
and CBOT becoming subsidiaries.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/cbot-volume-idUSN0232681320070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - cbot volume up 40 pct in dec ., caps record year</title></story></items>