<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:32 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (The following was issued by Ormat Technologies (ORA.N), a
unit of Israel's Ormat Industries ORMT.TA): Jan 2 - Ormat Technologies, Inc. (NYSE: ORA) today announced
that two of its subsidiaries have entered into Supply and
Engineering, Procurement and Construction contracts with Ngawha
Generation Ltd., a subsidiary of Top Energy Limited ("Top
Energy") for a new geothermal power plant in Ngawha, New
Zealand. The contracts are for a total of approximately $20 million,
with construction of the power plant expected to be completed
within 20 months from the contract date.  Top Energy is an
environmentally friendly, local electricity network company in
New Zealand. This is the second order for an Ormat geothermal power plant
from the company. Top Energy has been operating an Ormat 12 MW
geothermal power plant in Ngawha since June 1998.  Both plants will produce approximately 75 percent of the
electricity used by Top Energy's 26,000 consumers, thereby
further reducing the amount of electricity, which would
otherwise be generated by scarce non-renewable resources that
produce harmful greenhouse gas emissions. Upon completion of the plant, the total installed capacity
of Ormat's power plants in New Zealand will exceed 200 MW. The Ngawha plant contract is the tenth Ormat supply contract
in New Zealand, six of which are repeat contracts for the supply
of geothermal power plants in New Zealand. Lucien Y. Bronicki, Chairman of the Board and Chief
Technology Officer of Ormat Technologies, said, "This contract
brings a new geothermal power plant to New Zealand and provides
further confidence in Ormat's effectiveness and reliability. "We are more than pleased with our progress over the past 25
years in New Zealand and remain confident that the efficient and
sustainable use of geothermal resources, with its emission
reduction and the prudent and modular development, will continue
to attract medium and small developers such as medium size
utilities, land owners and private investors, as well as the
traditional large utilities". Mr. Bronicki continued, "New Zealand is a significant
resource for geothermal development, which we believe will
provide Ormat with additional growth opportunities that we look
forward to developing." The new plant will optimize energy utilization by converting
both geothermal steam and brine from geothermal wells into
electric power energy. Unlike the flash steam turbine plants that deplete the
resources by consuming water in the cooling towers, the new
plant, as all existing Ormat plants in New Zealand will reinject
100 percent of the geothermal fluid by using air-cooled
condensers. The 100 percent reinjection serves both to sustain the
reservoir and to produce electrical power with virtually no
environmental impact.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/ormat-ngawha-text-idUSL02513520070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>text - ormat technologies gets new zealand power plant deal</title></story></items>