<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:39 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Gold jumped to its highest in nearly a month as the dollar weakened, prompting investors to build fresh trading positions at the start of the new year.Sentiment remained firm and analysts said the commodities sector, which performed strongly last year, was expected to see fresh allocations of funds in the first quarter."Gold started with a very positive note and got a weak dollar as well for the start of the new year, which is encouraging people," said David Holmes, director of precious metals sales at Dresdner Kleinwort Investment Bank."The question is how far will it go. There would definitely be some resistance around $650 an ounce, but overall I am quite positive for the first quarter."Gold XAU= climbed as high as $640.80 an ounce, its strongest since December 6, and was quoted at $640.10/641.10 by 1520 GMT, up from $636.10/637.10 in New York late on Friday.The dollar fell sharply across the board, while the euro rallied broadly as investors kicked off the new year hunting for currencies with rising yields.A weaker dollar generally makes gold cheaper for holders of other currencies and lifts bullion demand.Dealers were keeping an eye on the currency market ahead of the release on Wednesday of minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's December policy meeting."Recent talk suggests that inflation might be under control again in the U.S. Consequently, that's going to help support gold in the immediate future," said Darren Heathcote of Investec Australia in Sydney.Physical buying was slow in Asia because of a holiday in Singapore, a center for bullion trading in Southeast Asia.Dealers said gold's rise at the start of the new year could encourage more investors to buy the precious metal."The market is vulnerable to a short term sell-off, however speculators/investors are likely to be keen to take advantage of the strong returns seen in the sector over the past few years with the metal set to remain in its uptrend longer term," said TheBullionDesk.com in a daily report.Gold rose 23 percent in price last year.Other precious metals tracked gold, with silver XAG= hitting a two-week high of $13.09 an ounce. It was last quoted at $13.08/13.14, up from $12.85/12.92 late in New York.Platinum XPT= rose to $1,133/1,139 from $1,132/1,137 an ounce, while palladium XPD= rose $1 to $333/338 an ounce.(Additional reporting by Lewa Pardomuan in Singapore)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-markets-precious-idUSL2977315020070102</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>gold hits one - month high on weaker dollar</title></story></items>