<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:28 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates figures, adds comment)TORONTO Jan 2 (Reuters) - The Toronto Stock Exchange's
main index kicked off the first trading session of 2007 with a
broad rally on Tuesday, as resource, financial and energy
shares helped drive morning gains. The S&amp;P/TSX composite .GSPTSE rose 76.84 points, or 0.6
percent, to 12,985.23 shortly after the opening bell. All but one of the composite's 10 key groups advanced, with
the resource-laden materials group rising 1.2 percent and
energy moving forward 0.65 percent. Financials rose 0.25
percent. Utilities and information technology declined. Given  the breadth of the rally, early 2007 could see an
extension of the strength shown by the composite in the fourth
quarter of last year, said Ian Nakamoto, director of research
at MacDougall, MacDougall &amp; MacTier. "I think...2007 is going to be another good year, but I
think a lot of it could be sort of front-end loaded in the
first few months," he said. He added that while investors realize the index returned
14.5 percent in 2006, their enthusiasm is measured. "People notice, obviously, that the market has done well,
but I don't get the general sense people are throwing caution
to the wind at all," he said, pointing to price-to-earnings
ratios which he described as relatively low. Harris Steel Group Inc. HSG.TO was among Tuesday's top
gainers after it announced a takeover offer from U.S.-based
Nucor Corp. (NUE.N) before markets opened. The all-cash offer
values Harris at C$1.25 billion ($1.08 billion). The
steelmaker's shares rose C$2.76, or 6.4 percent, to C$46.25,
matching the per-share bid price. Among energy names, Suncor Energy Inc. (SU.TO) rose 99
Canadian cents to C$92.78 and Husky Energy (HSE.TO) gained 38
Canadian cents to C$78.42. Gold issues on the rise included Agnico-Eagle Mines
Ltd.(AEM.TO), which picked up 76 Canadian cents to C$48.85, and
Barrick Gold Corp. which rose 55 Canadian cents to C$36.40. The price of gold also rose on Tuesday, as the euro gained
against the U.S. dollar. The greenback's declines can spur
demand for bullion and for the shares of companies that mine
it. New year's trades were put off one more day in the United
States, as exchanges stayed shut to observe a day of mourning
for the death of former U.S. President Gerald Ford. "The fact that the U.S. is closed means that there'll be a
cautious tone, no matter what, because we won't have that
input," said Paul Taylor, chief investment officer at BMO
Harris Private Banking. ($1=$1.16 Canadian)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-canada-stocks-idUSN0232922520070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>toronto stocks kick off 2007 with broadbased rally</title></story></items>