<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:41 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MEXICO CITY Jan 2 Mexican stocks edged higher
in early, light trading on Tuesday, pushed by gains in cement
maker Cemex on expectations that the U.S. housing market has
greater resilience than previously thought. The benchmark IPC index .MXX rose 0.68 percent and the
peso MXN= MEX01 firmed 0.24 percent to 10.7838 per dollar. Trading volume was low, with many investors in the United
States sitting out the session on an official day of mourning
for former U.S. President Gerald Ford. Data last week showed an increase in November existing home
sales in the United States, Cemex's top market for cement. The
U.S. housing market had been sluggish in 2006, though some
analysts say data is beginning to show the worst is over for
the sector. Shares for Cemex (CMXCPO.MX), the world's number three
cement maker and the biggest supplier of cement for U.S.
construction firms, rose 0.79 percent to 36.90 pesos. Analysts at Santander said on Friday more positive U.S.
housing data would be a "positive catalyst for Cemex shares,"
and the bank maintained its "buy" recommendation for the
company. The IPC index closed at a record high during the last
trading session on Friday, topping off its best year since 1999
with an advance of 48 percent over 12 months. Many analysts expect the rally to continue into this year,
though with more modest gains. Shares in leading retailer Wal-Mart de Mexico (Walmex)
WALMEXV.MX rose 1.47 percent to 48.26 pesos. Shares in America Movil (AMXL.MX), the most heavily
weighted stock in the index, rose 0.29 percent to 24.45 pesos,
while its holding company America Telecom AMTELA1.MX rose
1.11 percent to 99 pesos. Mexico's fifth largest bank Banorte (GFNORTEO.MX) rose 1.28
percent to 42.79 pesos.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-mexico-idUSN0232624420070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>mexican stocks rise , driven by cemex , walmex</title></story></items>