<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:09 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MENA, Saudi Arabia More than 2.5 million Muslim pilgrims performed final devil-stoning rites on Monday, as Saudi authorities declared the annual pilgrimage free from the tragedies that have marred haj in recent years."Praise be to God, we have had a safe haj this year. I bring my sons with me normally (for protection), but this year I found I was okay without them," said Saadiya Mustafa from Egypt."The organization has been great," said Indian pilgrim Sayed Yousef, sitting on top of a van amid severe traffic congestion on the final day of haj. "I was here two years ago, but this time there was more free food and less hassle."On Monday, pilgrims made a third and final visit to the Jamarat Bridge to throw stones at three large walls representing the spot of Satan's temptation of biblical patriarch Abraham.Then many jumped on whatever transport they could find to make a final visit to Mecca's Grand Mosque, which filled with hundreds of thousands of pilgrims into the evening."Look at the pedestrians, they are moving faster than the cars," said Hamdan bin Musaileh, a Yemeni stuck in the suffocating traffic jam. "I bet they get a better reward from God for walking to the Mosque rather than taking transport."Authorities congratulated themselves that the haj rites had passed off without incident despite a surge of pilgrims at the bridge on Monday in the rush to finish and leave."There have been no security violations at all at the Jamarat area," Interior Minister Prince Nayef told reporters, praising Saudi clerics for offering pilgrims clear advice to pace the stoning throughout the day.Hardliners of Saudi Arabia's Wahhabi school of Islam often insist stoning should take place in the afternoon to emulate to the word what they say was the practice of Prophet Mohammad.It was on the final day of the last haj that 362 pilgrims were crushed to death during the stone-throwing ritual in the worst haj tragedy in 16 years. Another such incident would have been an embarrassment for Saudi Arabia.New construction work completed in recent months allows 250,000 pilgrims to pass over the Jamarat Bridge each hour. Saudi authorities were also bolder than normal in removing pilgrim squatters who set up makeshift tents in the area.Saudi Arabia regularly deploys more than 50,000 security men to safeguard haj against militants and try to prevent disasters.SADDAM SPOILERThe 5-day rites were overshadowed by the hanging on Saturday of former Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein, a hero to some Sunni Arabs over his anti-U.S. stances, but hated by many Shi'ites.Saudi Arabia criticized Iraq for despoiling the spirit of the haj, one of the world's biggest displays of mass religious devotion which is a duty for able-bodied Muslims with the means.The execution also raised fears of clashes at the haj, where police have used force to put down protests in the past.Security was already tight during this pilgrimage season -- with apparent record numbers -- because of sectarian strife between Sunni and Shi'ite Muslims in Iraq and Lebanon.Saudi officials say 2.4 million pilgrims are officially on the haj. But with hundreds of thousands of residents and expatriates sneaking into Mecca without official permits, the total number could be closer to a record 3 million.Pilgrims, mostly on foot, cover a 44 km (28 mile) route around Mecca during the grueling rites, as well as walk some 15 km in at least three visits to the city's vast mosque complex.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-haj-idUSL3090240620070102</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>pilgrims rush to end rites on final day of haj</title></story></items>