<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:49 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 2 Harbinger Capital Partners, a
$5 billion hedge fund group, said on Tuesday it plans a proxy
campaign to elect seven new directors on the board of Ryerson
Inc. (RYI.N), a metals processing company that it says is
underperforming rivals. New York-based Harbinger, which owns a 9.7 percent stake in
Ryerson, launched its proxy campaign several weeks after
disclosing it was considering "a range of actions" to pressure
Ryerson to improve its performance. "The current board has not fulfilled its responsibility to
enhance value for shareholders," said Harbinger in a statement.
It said Ryerson has "consistently underperformed its industry
peers on a variety of key performance metrics, including gross,
operating and net margins and that peer companies have
consistently turned inventory more rapidly than Ryerson." Ryerson could not be reached immediately for comment. In early November, Ryerson reported third-quarter profit
fell to $21.6 million, or 77 cents a share, from $30.7 million,
or $1.18 a share, a year earlier. The 2005 quarter included
gains totaling 72 cents a share. Ryerson's shares closed down 30 cents at $25.09 on Friday
on the New York Stock Exchange. The shares have traded in a
range between $19.60 and $33.20 over the last 52 weeks. Harbinger operates two hedge funds, one with a strategy
that seeks to benefit from corporate restructurings and
another that takes positions in distressed company debt. The hedge fund group said it will file notification this
week with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission of plans
for the proxy campaign. It said it would also introduce a
shareholder proposal to "deter" the current board from
instituting "obstacles" to electing the Harbinger nominees. It didn't specify what issues it was concerned about, but
some common defenses to dissident shareholder proposals include
expanding a board or instituting a "staggered board" provision
to prevent the election of a whole new board in any one year. Harbinger said Ryerson has been pursing the "right"
strategy in cutting costs and improving productivity. But
current management has "failed to execute on this strategy and
requires better counsel." Harbinger will seek election of the following individuals
to the Ryerson board: Keith Butler, owner of BCS Placements
LLC, a broker dealer; Eugene Davis, chairman of Atlas Air
Worldwide Holdings Inc.; Daniel Dienst, chairman of Metal
Management Inc.; Richard Kochersperger, director of Food
Marketing Group; Larry Liebovich, retired former president of
Liebovich Steel &amp; Aluminum Co.; Gerald Morris, chief executive
of Intalite International NV, a diversified holding company;
and Allen Ritchie, a private investor. Harbinger said none of its nominees work for the fund.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/ryerson-harbinger-idUSN0232592720070102</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>harbinger hedge fund to run board slate at ryerson</title></story></items>