<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:53 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates prices, adds comment) By John ParryNEW YORK Jan 2 (Reuters) - U.S. government bond prices
rose on Tuesday in a modest recovery from last week, when the
market sold off on stronger-than-expected economic reports. Volume was light during a session shortened for a day of
mourning to honor former U.S. President Gerald Ford. Many
trading desks were thinly staffed as financial markets were
either closed or open only for a half-session on Tuesday, when
the United States holds a national funeral service for the
former president. That leaves Tuesday virtually devoid of economic data for
bond investors. The Institute for Supply Management (ISM)
manufacturing report on Wednesday and the monthly nonfarm
payrolls report, due on Friday could be major catalysts for the
Treasury market. "This is that sort of bounce that you get after the
pounding the bond market took last week," said Kevin Flanagan,
fixed income strategist for global wealth management with
Morgan Stanley in Purchase, New York. "I wouldn't read too much
into it and we are still at a kind of half staffed situation,"
Flanagan said. Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR were up 1/32 in price
for a yield of 4.69 percent, versus 4.70 percent late on
Friday. Markets had been closed on Monday for the New Year's
Day public holiday. "For the week, the big number will be the employment report
on Friday," said Don Kowalchik, a debt strategist at A.G.
Edwards &amp; Sons in St. Louis. If the jobs data surprises, the
10-year Treasury note's yield could test the upper or lower
limits of its near term range, around 4.75 percent and 4.50
percent, Kowalchik said. Two-year notes US2YT=RR, which respond closely to
expectations for Federal Reserve interest rate moves, rose 2/32
in price to yield 4.80 percent, compared with 4.82 percent on
Friday. The Securities Industry and Financial Markets Association
has recommended an early bond market close at 2 p.m. (1900 GMT)
and the key manufacturing report of the week, the Institute for
Supply Management (ISM) index, has been rescheduled for
Wednesday. The 10-year note's yield, which moves inversely to its
price, jumped to 4.70 percent at the end of December from 4.46
percent at the start of that month. Last week, stronger-than-expected U.S. economic reports on
home sales, consumer confidence and Chicago manufacturing
weighed on bond prices as prospects of a Federal Reserve
interest rate cut early this year appeared to dwindle. "The November data, at least, reinforces the idea the Fed's
on hold," wrote David Ader, head of government bond strategy
with RBS Greenwich Capital in Greenwich, Connecticut in a daily
research note. Perceived prospects for the Fed to lower rates by June, as
shown by short-term U.S. interest rate futures, had fallen to
about 58 percent late on Friday after being fully priced as
recently as Dec. 21. Further insight into the Federal Reserve's thinking may
come from the release on Wednesday of the minutes from its
last monetary policy meeting on Dec 12. The 30-year bond US30YT=RR rose 8/32 in price for a yield
of 4.80 percent, versus 4.81 percent late on Friday.







</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-bonds-idUSN0233006920070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - prices inch up after last week ' s sell - off</title></story></items>