<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:55 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds details, background, stock prices. Amounts in U.S.
dollars unless noted)MONTREAL Jan 2 (Reuters) - Alcan Inc. AL.TO (AL.N) said
on Tuesday that a British Columbia regulator's rejection of a
power-sale agreement could affect plans for a $1.8 billion
expansion of its aluminum smelter at Kitimat. Alcan, the world's second-largest maker of primary
aluminum, said the British Columbia Utilities Commission
rejected a proposed long-term energy agreement that would see
the company sell electricity from its Kitimat-area power plant
to provincially owned utility BC Hydro. "We are disappointed with the BCUC decision and will be
studying it closely to better understand the commission's
rationale and to determine the potential impact on the
feasibility and timing of the Kitimat modernization project,"
Michel Jacques, president and chief executive of Alcan Primary
Metal Group, said in a statement. Approval of the power contract was one of three conditions
Alcan set for the modernization of Kitimat, in northwestern
British Columbia. The plans would expand the smelter's annual
production capacity by more than 60 percent to about 400,000
tonnes from 245,000 tonnes. The other two conditions to be met were environmental
permits and a labor agreement with the Canadian Auto Workers
union, which represents Kitimat workers. In a letter on Friday, the commission said the power pact
should not be accepted, in part because of prices BC Hydro
would have to pay for excess energy supplied by Alcan's Kemano
hydro-electric plant near the Kitimat site. The commission said it would release the reasons for its
decision at a later date. In arguments at the commission, BC Hydro had said the power
agreement with Alcan would help the utility meets its goal of
energy self-sufficiency. But others told the commission that Alcan should use all
the power generated at Kemano to produce aluminum at Kitimat
rather than divert it for sale through the province's power
grid. When Alcan unveiled the Kitimat project in mid-August, the
company said the smelter expansion would increase its global
aluminum output by more than 4 percent. Using an upgraded version of the AP smelting technology it
acquired when it bought France's Pechiney in 2004, the first
part of the new capacity was slated to come on stream in 2009. Alcan shares were off 8 Canadian cents at C$56.70 on the
Toronto Stock Exchange on Tuesday morning. ($1=$1.17 Canadian)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/alcan-power-idUSN0232438420070102</link><sectors><value><value>Regulatory News</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - alcan says power pact refusal may affect kitimat</title></story></items>