<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:49 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds comments from Citigroup, RLPC loan figures) By Quentin WebbLONDON Jan 2 (Reuters) - A merger boom and low borrowing
costs helped push global debt issuance to a record $6.9 trillion
in 2006, data from Thomson Financial showed on Tuesday. The blizzard of debt deals -- up 13 percent from 2005 --
helped banks to enjoy a 26 percent rise in underwriting fees to
$23.9 billion, according to calculations for Thomson by M&amp;A
consultants Freeman &amp; Co. Thomson said a 55 percent jump in global high-yield debt
issuance and increases of more than a quarter in global
investment-grade and emerging markets debt sales had helped fuel
the overall rise. "These sectors have benefited from a record-breaking merger
market, robust financing activity across many industries and
historically low interest rates," Thomson said in a report. Thomson data showed global mergers and acquisitions hit a
record $3.8 trillion in 2006, helped by a surge in
private-equity led leveraged buyouts (LBOs), to make up 19.9
percent of deals. Structured finance flourished, particularly issuance of
collateralised debt obligations (CDOs), which repackage credit
risk from bonds, leveraged loans, and other debt securities.
Global CDO sales doubled to $452 billion. "There is a lot of money flowing round the system, seeking
yield and investment, and that's what's driving record figures,"
said Charlie Berman, Citigroup's co-head of fixed income capital
markets in Europe. "The distinctive feature this year has been the tremendous
amount of activity in terms of the leveraged markets," Berman
added. "We've seen extraordinary activity in the LBO (leveraged
buyout) market, and all sorts of high-yield (deals), and
transaction sizes which are much more akin to investment
grade-sized financings."
 STAGGERING INCREASE Thomson said global high-yield debt issuance hit $187
billion, swelled by a "staggering" 127 percent increase in deals
to fund LBOs, including the three largest high-yield deals ever
-- from Freescale Semiconductor Inc, NXP Semiconductors and U.S.
hospital operator HCA Inc. "The rule has always been 'high-yield, high-margin, low
volumes', but that hasn't been the case this year," Berman said. It was a good year for Citigroup (C.N), which kept its No. 1
position as global debt bookrunner; JP Morgan (JPM.N), which
moved to second from fourth in the global debt bookrunner table;
and Barclays Capital (BARC.L), which leapt to seventh place from
11th a year ago. But Lehman Brothers LEH.N and Credit Suisse (CSGN.VX) both
slipped two places, to fourth and eighth place respectively. However, Freeman &amp; Co's "imputed fees," which estimate
unpublished fees using the consultancy's own algorithms,
suggested some banks had reaped the benefits of concentrating on
higher-margin work. Merrill Lynch MER.N, the top adviser on lucrative CDO
deals, ranked 6th by global debt volumes but second only to
Citigroup by imputed fees, earning an estimated $1.51 billion. In the loan market, preliminary data from Reuters Loan
Pricing Corp. (RLPC) suggests global syndicated loan volume is
also on track to eclipse last year's record issuance of $3.2
trillion, due largely to M&amp;A, which has boosted volumes in the
United States and Asia, while Europe has maintained its pace.
 (Additional reporting by Tessa Walsh of RLPC)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/debt-thomson-idUSL0235795820070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds, </value><value>IPOs</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - global debt sales at record $ 6 . 9 tln in 06 - thomson</title></story></items>