<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:06 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 2 Financial services company Marsh &amp;
McLennan Cos. Inc. (MMC.N) has agreed in principle to sell its
Putnam Investments unit to Power Corp. of Canada (POW.TO) for $3.9
billion, according to sources familiar with the situation. A Putnam spokeswoman and a spokesman for Marsh &amp; McLennan
declined to comment. A representative for Montreal-based Power
Corp., also a financial services company, did not return a call
seeking comment. While the companies have reached agreement, the deal is not
expected to be announced immediately because final details still
need to be settled, one of the sources said. March &amp; McLennan put Putnam, its asset management unit, on the
block in September, and Marsh &amp; McLennan Chief Executive Michael
Cherkasky said in December that he would decide whether to sell
the unit by early 2007. The Putnam mutual fund board of directors is due to meet in
the second week of January. Putnam, once the country's fifth-largest mutual fund firm and
a star during the Internet boom of the 1990s, has run into
problems after being caught up in the mutual fund industry trading
scandal three years ago. Investors have pulled money out and the
performance of its top fund is lagging many of its peers. Its flagship Voyager fund, which invests in large growth
stocks, rose 5.2 percent in 2006, trailing the S&amp;P 500's .SPX
gains of 13.6 percent. Putnam's assets overall have shrunk by
about a third over the last three years to $191 billion. Still, buyers were interested in Putnam. The Wall Street
Journal, which first reported last week that a deal had been
reached, had previously reported that bidders for Putnam included
Power Corp., Italian bank UniCredito Italiano SpA (CRDI.MI) and
London-based fund manager Amvescap Plc AVZ.L, parent of Aim
Trimark. Ownership of Putnam would give Power Corp. a new
money-management platform in the United States. The company,
founded in 1925 to profit from the growing demand for electricity,
is controlled by Canada's wealthy and well-connected Desmarais
family and has grown far beyond its early hydroelectric roots. Power Corp. holds 66.4 percent of Power Financial Corp.
(PWF.TO), which controls insurer Great-West Lifeco Inc. (GWO.TO)
and IGM Financial Inc. (IGM.TO). The financial unit also owns half
the company that controls European investment firm Pargesa Holding
SA (PARG.S). Winnipeg, Manitoba-based IGM Financial has C$104.1 billion in
assets under management, mainly in its Investors Group Inc. and
Mackenzie Financial Corp. fund families. Marsh &amp; McLennan shares closed down 6 cents at $30.66 on the
New York Stock Exchange on Friday. Power Corp. shares were up 6
Canadian cents at C$35.35 in Toronto on Tuesday. (Additional reporting by Muralikumar Anantharaman in Boston,
Nicole Mordant in Toronto and Mark McSherry in New York)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/putnam-takeover-idUSN0247786820070102</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>canada ' s power corp . to buy putnam - sources</title></story></items>