<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:14 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 2 The FTSE 100 .FTSE index of
Britain's leading shares ended up 1.5 percent on Tuesday,
closing at its highest level since January 2001, after
commodities and banks boosted the market in thin volumes. With gold at a near one-month high as the dollar weakened
and the mining sector benefiting from positive 2007 sentiment
and optimism over demand from China, BHP Billiton (BLT.L)
climbed 2.9 percent, while Lonmin (LMI.L&gt; rose 2.8 percent and
Anglo American (AAL.L) gained 2.4 percent. U.S. crude oil rose above $61 a barrel as Iran refused to
comply with a United Nations resolution to stop its nuclear
programme, but mild weather in the United States limited gains.
BP (BP.L) rose 0.7 percent and rival Royal Dutch Shell (RDSa.L)
added 1.5 percent. Vague consolidation talk among utilities also helped the
upside, with Kelda Group KEL.L up 3.1 percent and Severn Trent
(SVT.L) tacking on 1.5 percent. Insurers were also many traders' top picks for the new year,
with Standard Life (SL.L) adding 3.4 percent and Royal &amp;
SunAlliance (RSA.L) up 3.1 percent. The FTSE 100 index closed up 90.1 points at 6,310.9, its
highest since January 2001, having hit an intra-day high of
6,312.5. "2007 is expected to see further strong corporate activity,
with more British companies in 2006 being taken over than in any
previous year," said David Scott, senior stockbroker at
Redmayne-Bentley. "Strong markets and an ample supply of cheap
debt have seen the likes of BAA, Scottish Power and possibly the
London Stock Exchange (LSE.L) disappearing as public limited
companies." "Deals of around 170 billion pounds occurred over the last
twelve months and this has left institutional investors with
large amounts of cash, which we believe will continue to
underpin the equity market in 2007," Scott added.
 WALL ST CLOSED With the U.S. markets closed to mark the death of former
President Gerald Ford, traders said there was little stock
specific news to offer firm direction in the UK. Earlier in the session, the UK December Purchasing Managers
Index, a gauge of British manufacturing, came in at 51.9,
compared with 52.5 in November and a forecast 52.6, and was at
its lowest since March 2006. The data slightly eased pressure
for a near-term interest rate rise, investors said. House prices in England and Wales rose 0.6 percent on the
month in November and 6.8 percent year-on-year, according to
Land Registry data. The banking sector was boosted by the data because it showed
continued growth in the UK housing market, benefiting mortgage
demand, traders said. Barclays (BARC.L) and Royal Bank of
Scotland (RBS.L) both added 2.1 percent. British-based building and plumbing supplier Wolseley
(WOS.L) gained 2.2 percent on related sentiment. "It's a little bit like before Christmas," one trader said.
"Still quite perky and all sectors are up ... still people are
talking about consolidation but the volumes are very light out
there." Among other standout gainers, Vodafone (VOD.L) rose 1.5
percent on market talk that the mobile telecoms giant is less
likely to acquire Hutchison Essar after media reports that
India's Essar group, the minority partner in the mobile phone
joint venture, has tied up financing for a potential bid for the
two thirds of the business it does not own. On the downside, Drax Group (DRX.L) fell 1.4 percent and
British Energy BGY.L dropped 3.2 percent on concerns over
future carbon emission quota plans, traders said. Among midcaps, PartyGaming PRTY.L climbed 11.8 percent
after it struck a deal with gambling software maker Playtech
(PTEC.L) for the latter to power gaming Web sites that
PartyGaming has agreed to buy from Empire Online EOL.L and
Intercontinental Online.
 (Additional reporting by Alex Davidson and Rebekah Curtis)





</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-britain-stocks-idUSL0286026020070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>ftse hits six - year closing high , commodities boost</title></story></items>