<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:07 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON Washington Redskins' head coach Joe Gibbs has said his team's bitterly disappointing season was the most difficult in his 15 years in the job."For me it was the toughest five months of my professional career as far as coaching," the three-times Super Bowl-winning coach told an end-of-season news conference. "I don't look at it so much about myself but all the people we let down."You have an owner (Dan Snyder) that is busting his hump doing everything he can to try and help us. You have fans doing everything they can."Your responsibility is to win football games and you don't."The Redskins went 10-6 last year and advanced to the second round of the playoffs before they were beaten 20-10 by the eventual NFC champion Seattle Seahawks.Fueled by a return to the playoffs for the first time since 1999 and the off-season acquisitions of Antwann Randle El, Adam Archuleta, Brandon Lloyd, Andre Carter and others, Redskins fans were delirious with thoughts of a Super Bowl season.But the Redskins stumbled out of the gate this season with a 2-5 start and never recovered. They finished 5-11 and were essentially out of the playoff hunt by mid-season."For me, during the time I have been with the Redskins this season was most disappointing," Gibbs said. "Last year we played extremely well down the stretch even though we lost some guys."I thought for us to make the playoffs last year was a step forward for the franchise. That is what we would like to be every year, a team that can do that."Had we been able to duplicate that record this year, you can see where we would have been in the NFC. That didn't happen."AWFUL STARTA 10-6 record would have given the Redskins at least a share of the East title. The New York Giants finished 8-8 in the NFC and still advanced to the playoffs.But this year's group of Washington free agents was largely a bust and 36-year-old quarterback Mark Brunell was benched by the ninth game for ineffectiveness."We got off to an awful start," said Gibbs. "That got us going in the wrong direction. It took me by surprise. Our team worked extremely hard in the off season."Down the stretch our football team showed great character and great heart. We were out of it and it was strictly a pride thing for us."Gibbs, hailed as an offensive genius, coached the Redskins for 12 years before retiring in 1992 after three Super Bowl wins. He was enshrined in the Hall of Fame in 1996.Now, the 66-year-old Gibbs, who returned to the Redskins in 2004, must prove he still has the magic. The Redskins were 20th in points scored and 27th in points allowed this season.Gibbs said he did not expected to make major changes in personnel."This year was extremely disappointing for us. We will take a long hard look at and try and do every single thing to get back to where we want to be. We are going to go after it hard."</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-nfl-redskins-idUSN0227175820070102</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>gibbs says disappointing season his toughest yet</title></story></items>