<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:31 01 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> NEW YORK (Billboard) - Following are previews of albums due 
out within the next few months from debut acts or 
under-the-radar artists due for a breakthrough.
 PAOLO NUTINI Scottish singer/songwriter Paolo Nutini, who turns 20 
January 9, was one of the most noteworthy breakout artists of 
2006 for Atlantic Records in the United Kingdom. After an 
appearance at South by Southwest in Austin last March, his 
debut single, "Last Request," reached No. 5 in July on the 
British charts and also became a substantial airplay hit. His debut album, "These Streets," subsequently opened at 
No. 3 with out-of-the-box sales of 35,000, according to his 
label, which had risen to 500,000 by December. A second single, "Jenny Don't Be Hasty," was a top 20 U.K. 
hit in early October and was followed in early December by 
"Rewind." As "New Shoes," his first U.S. radio track, made inroads at 
the triple-A format late in the year, Atlantic was developing 
its transatlantic plans for Nutini for 2007. "These Streets" is 
due for U.S. release January 30, when he performs on "Today," 
with a booking for "Late Night With Conan O'Brien" the 
following day.
 JAMES MORRISON His name may have a familiar ring for U.S. audiences. And 
by the early part of 2007, American radio listeners and record 
buyers are expected to recognize James Morrison's music. One of the big breakout success stories in the United 
Kingdom in 2006, the Polydor-signed artist is tipped for big 
things abroad. Soundwise, think James Blunt, with an edge. Interscope is setting up the smoky-toned singer's debut 
album, "Undiscovered," for U.S. release in first-quarter 2007, 
at which time Morrison will head Stateside to do promotional 
and support work. The album has shipped more than 1 million copies worldwide 
since its August release, more than half of those tallied in 
the United Kingdom.
 YOUNG LOVE Last year, Young Love -- a.k.a. Dan Keyes, former frontman 
of Texas rock band Recover -- was busing tables and working at 
American Apparel in New York, casually carting a demo of 
dance-rock tunes from one hipster club to the next. DJs dug them, especially the Bloc Party-meets-Blur 
"Discotech," a guitar-laden ode to boogie-ing in the Big Apple 
that is so joyful and unpretentious that it had to be written 
by an out-of-towner. Then Jay-Z called. "This is where it's at," Jay-Z told Keyes over brunch in 
Miami, as Beyonce lounged by the pool and paparazzi helicopters 
circled. So Keyes signed with Island Def Jam and took his demos into 
the studio. Keyes himself resembles the shaggy teen hero, fair and 
lanky with an intense gray-eyed stare. "A friend gave me Daft 
Punk's 'Discovery' for Christmas a couple of years ago, and it 
kind of destroyed my rock band," he says. "I didn't want to 
play guitar anymore, so I started experimenting with electronic 
stuff."
 THE PONYS The Ponys' first full-length album on esteemed indie 
Matador Records doesn't arrive until March 20. But judging from the Chicago-based rock band's previous 
work, its Matador debut, "Turn the Lights Out," should be worth 
the wait. The act's 2005 disc, "Celebration Castle," released on Los 
Angeles-based garage rock label In the Red, has sold 7,000 
units in the United States, according to Nielsen SoundScan. "Celebration Castle" matched a hard-rock intensity with a 
hung-over swagger, and the Ponys established themselves as one 
of the most exciting bands in underground rock. From the bluesy breakdown in shout-along anthem "Get Black" 
to the slacker wailing of frontman/guitarist Jered Gummere in 
the punk-rock strut of "Today," "Celebration Castle" flirted 
with recklessness as its tightly structured songs burst with 
pop hooks. The band is also confident enough to slow things down and 
show off some new wave influences (see the Cure-like "We Shot 
the World"). In the Red has given Matador a solid base to build 
upon in further boosting the Ponys' career.
 LEDISI R&amp;B's underground cognoscenti have carried a torch for this 
spirited singer/songwriter since 1996. Folks still wax 
rhapsodic over Ledisi's "Soulsinger," her 1998 indie debut, 
accompanied by former partner and keyboardist Sundra Manning. Now a solo artist, Ledisi is a rare but welcome commodity: 
What you hear on record is what you get live. Mixing R&amp;B, jazz, 
gospel, pop and rock with flavorful scatting, Ledisi's 
energetic live gigs are can't-miss propositions. Two years ago, this Oakland, Calif., talent offered an 
arresting interpretation of Luther Vandross' "My Sensitivity" 
that gained some national airplay, as well as the attention of 
Verve Records. Now Ledisi's sassy vocals (think Minnie Riperton meets 
Sarah Vaughan) are poised to reach a wider arena this spring 
with the release of her Verve debut. A fitting scenario, given 
that Ledisi's name means "to come forth" in Nigerian. Ledisi still isn't leaving anything to chance. She 
continues to operate her label, LeSun Music, and owns her 
masters.
 LUKE BRYAN Luke Bryan is unapologetically country in his music and 
lifestyle, which is why he stands out from the pack. "Even my friends in Nashville laugh sometimes at how 
country I am," he says. "I'm still adjusting to (living in 
Nashville) because I can't . . . just walk out my door and go 
fishing or hunting or do something outdoors." A native of Leesburg, Ga., Bryan grew up on his family's 
peanut farm. With lyrics like "I can grow my own groceries and salt-cure 
a ham/Hey baby, I'm a country man" and a stone-country 
presentation, Bryan is hatched from the same mold as Randy 
Travis and Alan Jackson. First single "All My Friends Say" is due at radio in 
February, and an album will follow in summer. Bryan co-wrote 
all 11 songs on his Capitol Records Nashville debut and also 
co-wrote Billy Currington's current single "Good Directions." In an effort to build consumer awareness, Capitol made a 
four-song EP and individual tracks available on iTunes in late 
October.
 NAOMI STRIEMER Fans of purely melodic pop music should rejoice. Naomi 
Striemer is here to offer what they crave. The singer/songwriter, whose debut album "Images" arrived 
in December on S Records, was home-schooled in her native Nova 
Scotia, Canada, but she realized she had a purpose far from the 
farm. "Thinking back to where I come from and enjoying the 
innocence of life's untouched imagination, I dreamt of being 
something that seemed so far out of reach but so close in my 
mind," Striemer says. As a teen, she signed with Epic Records, but the deal 
unraveled when then-president Polly Anthony exited. Then Steven Nowack, a hedge-fund driver, saw Striemer 
perform live in Toronto, and approached the artist and asked, 
"What are you doing for the rest of your life?" He formed S 
Records as a vehicle to launch her. Her album's first single, the melancholy ballad "Cars," 
produced by Narada Michael Walden and featuring a guitar solo 
by Carlos Santana, gained coverage from Fox News columnist 
Roger Friedman and the National Post in Canada. "I am a testament that it doesn't matter where you come 
from or how badly the world tears you down," Striemer says. "If 
you believe, life, love and God will get you through."
 JOHN WALLER When one of country music's veteran hitmakers and one of 
the Christian community's most successful artists team up to 
introduce a new act, expectations run high. And 
singer/songwriter John Waller meets and exceeds those 
expectations with thoughtful songwriting and a compelling 
voice. The former frontman for acclaimed indie band According to 
John, Waller returns on Beach Street Records, a Christian label 
owned by Sawyer Brown's Mark Miller. Mark Hall, leader of Beach 
Street's flagship act Casting Crowns, introduced Miller to 
Waller's music. Hall met Waller at a youth rally shortly after 
September 11, 2001, and recalls being immediately impressed 
with Waller's songwriting. "Then he started talking between the songs, and something 
stood out about him," Hall says. "I could tell he was reaching 
my students." After his earlier band broke up, Waller moved to Colorado 
to become a worship pastor. During a trip to Atlanta, he 
enlisted Hall to sing on a song called "The Blessing." Hall sent a CD to Miller, who signed Waller to Beach 
Street. The label is working "The Blessing" at Christian radio 
as the first single from Waller's debut album, set to arrive 
March 6.
 K-OS Toronto-bred MC Kheaven Brereton, aka K-OS, has been making 
waves in Canada and beyond since his 2002 debut album, "Exit." 
But he's poised to finally infiltrate the United States in 2007 
with "Atlantis: Hymns for Disco," which will be worked here by 
Virgin. K-OS' two prior albums were released in the States by 
Astralwerks. In Canada, the genre-bending "Atlantis" debuted in October 
at No. 5 on the album chart, the highest debut by any Canadian 
urban artist in Nielsen SoundScan history, Virgin says. In the States, the album's first single is the infectious 
"Sunday Morning," which many are likening to OutKast's "Hey 
Ya!" or Gnarls Barkley's "Crazy." Ahead of the album's February 20 U.S. release, "Sunday 
Morning" is already benefiting from airplay at NASCAR, NFL and 
NCAA events and on ESPN's "NFL Sunday Morning Countdown."
 RICH BOY Rich Boy, a.k.a. Maurice Richards, is catching everyone's 
ears with his single "Throw Some D's," which samples Switch's 
"I Call Your Name." Working with producers Butta and Polow Da Don (known for 
their tracks with the Pussycat Dolls and Fergie of the Black 
Eyed Peas), Rich Boy is cooking up debut album "A Product of 
the Hustle" for release early this year. A native of Mobile, Ala., Rich Boy began as a student at 
historically black college Tuskegee University before he 
dropped out to pursue music. Thinking he'd make it as a producer instead of mechanical 
engineer, his original major, he wrote the track "Cold As Ice," 
which garnered local radio support. After meeting Polow in 2003, Rich Boy later signed with 
Interscope and began his artist-development process. Now "Throw 
Some D's" is also garnering strong support at national radio. In addition, MTV profiled Rich on its up-and-coming artists 
series, "You Hear It First." And realizing hip-hop's high 
turnover rate, Rich Boy is rejuvenating "Throw Some D's" with a 
soon-to-be-released remix featuring the Game, Jim Jones and 
OutKast's Andre 3000. Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/music-newfaces-dc-idUSN0122555220070102</link><sectors><value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>rookie music acts to watch for in 2007</title></story></items>