<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:58 01 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> NEW YORK (Billboard) - Billboard presents a look at the 
music you'll be hearing a lot about in the first quarter:
 JOHN MELLENCAMP "Freedom's Road" (Universal, January 23) Mellencamp's first album of originals since 2001 is led by 
"Our Country," which has been prominently featured in a 
Chevrolet commercial to the chagrin of his label. In November, 
the track earned Mellencamp his first appearance on The 
Billboard Hot 100 in nine years and just the third of his 
career on Hot Country Songs. "'Our Country' is the most John Mellencamp-sounding record 
on it," he says. "I think people are gonna go, 'Wow!,' or 
they're gonna go, 'What is he trying to do?"' Elsewhere, Joan 
Baez duets with Mellencamp on the track "Jim Crow."
 THE SHINS "Wincing the Night Away" (Sub Pop, January 23) Natalie Portman's character in the 2004 film "Garden State" 
proclaimed "the Shins will change your life," which the 
Portland, Ore., indie-pop darlings hope to do with their third 
Sub Pop album, originally due last summer. "I'm constantly reminded of how much better the project 
gets as new discoveries are made," frontman James Mercer says. 
"That only happens through taking your time and being able to 
approach it with some new perspective." Indeed, "Wincing" advances the band well beyond the simple 
indie pop of its first two albums, the most recent of which, 
2003's "Chutes Too Narrow," has sold 407,000 copies in the 
United States, according to Nielsen SoundScan. Highlights include "Turn on Me," which nearly nicks the 
melody of the girl-group classic "Then He Kissed Me"; "Black 
Wave," a ghostly slice of acoustic folk that never releases its 
tension; and the jammed-out opener "Sleeping Lessons."
 NORAH JONES "Not Too Late" (Blue Note, January 30) Norah Jones kept a low profile in 2006, recording a 
collaborative album with New York-based musician friends as the 
Little Willies and guesting on the self-titled Ipecac album 
from Mike Patton's Peeping Tom project. But January 30 sees her back in the public eye with her 
third album, "Not Too Late," comprising songs all written or 
co-written by the artist. Production was handled by Jones' 
songwriting partner/bassist Lee Alexander; indie 
singer/songwriter M. Ward, Kronos Quartet cellist Jeff Ziegler 
and organist Larry Goldings make guest appearances. First single "Thinking About You" typifies an album full of 
jazz- and soul-shaded arrangements, old-school organ and horns 
and Jones' honeyed vocals. KATHARINE McPHEE Title TBA (RCA, January 30) McPhee rushed off the road with the American Idols summer 
tour to build songs from scratch with such collaborators as 
Timbaland associate Nate Hill, Babyface, Kara DioGuardi and 
Ryan Leslie. "It's rhythm pop," she says of the album's sound. 
"It's not like really R&amp;B or really poppy, but there are a 
couple of tracks that are really good for the 'American Idol' 
fans who voted for me and knew me as the 'Over the Rainbow' 
girl."
 CLAP YOUR HANDS SAY YEAH Some Loud Thunder (self-released, January 30) The indie-rock darlings headed to upstate New York to 
record their second album with producer Dave Fridmann. Like the 
band's 2005 self-titled debut, "Thunder" will bypass a label 
and be worked directly through the Alternative Distribution 
Alliance. Look for plenty of what the Talking Heads-influenced 
rock bloggers have come to love, particularly the danceable 
title track.
 FALL OUT BOY Infinity on High (Island, February 6) Fall Out Boy thinks its third album will surprise its fans 
-- but hopefully in a good way. Vocalist/guitarist Patrick 
Stump says the Chicago band's second major label set, the 
follow-up to 2005's double-platinum "From Under the Cork Tree," 
cuts a broader swath than its predecessors. "From song to song there's a completely different feel, but 
they all make sense in context," he says. "They've got a few 
common points, but overall there's a lot of different voices 
and perspectives and styles. It would be dishonest for us to 
hold back any of these elements." As for the funky single "This Ain't a Scene, It's an Arms 
Race," Stump enthuses, "It's basically a hip-hop/R&amp;B song but 
written as a punk song."
 LUCINDA WILLIAMS West (Lost Highway, February 13) Loss and loneliness are at the core of Lucinda Williams' 
eighth album, which finds her coping with another painful 
breakup and the passing of her mother, about whom she 
reminisces in songs like "Mama You Sweet" and "Fancy Funeral." 
Williams says, "It's probably been the most prolific time in my 
life as a writer. I'd been through so many changes, so 
obviously there's a lot of pain and struggling, but it ends 
with a look toward the future."
 CHARLIE LOUVIN Charlie Louvin (Tompkins Square, February 20) Wilco's Jeff Tweedy, Elvis Costello and George Jones are 
among the artists pitching in on country legend Louvin's first 
new album in more than a decade. The artist, who turns 80 in 
July, also netted contributions from Will Oldham, Tom T. Hall, 
Bobby Bare Sr., Marty Stuart, the Clean's David Kilgour and 
members of Lambchop, Superchunk, Bright Eyes and Clem Snide.
 LIL JON Crunk Rock (TVT, date TBA) Lil Jon is hard at work on "Crunk Rock," for which the 
Atlanta producer is hoping to collaborate with Rick Rubin, Good 
Charlotte, Korn's Jonathan Davis and Green Day producer Rob 
Cavallo. "I ain't trying to save the world, and I ain't trying to 
reinvent the wheel," he says. "I'm a give people what they know 
and love me for -- the crunk s--- and the nice club records for 
the ladies to dance to. But also on this record, I've got live 
bands, crazy heavy metal and rock guitars, so it's a mixture." The track "Act the Fool" featuring Three 6 Mafia was 
recently leaked on Jon's MySpace page.
 MODEST MOUSE We Were Dead Before the Ship Even Sank (Epic, date TBA) Modest Mouse reached previously unknown commercial heights 
with 2004's "Good News for People Who Love Bad News" and its 
ubiquitous hit "Float On." But there are no mainstream-courting 
maneuvers on its third Epic album, which introduces former 
Smiths guitarist Johnny Marr into the fold. Album opener/first single "Dashboard" rides in on a boogie 
riff and thudding kick drum, while "Florida" is a tight rocker 
with a prominent hook and "Fire It Up" conjures vintage Modest 
Mouse melancholy. But the best of the bunch is the 
eight-minute-plus "Spitting Venom," which blooms from a sleepy 
acoustic intro into a full-on psychedelic jam. The Shins' James 
Mercer sings backup on three cuts.
 THE ARCADE FIRE Neon Bible (Merge, March 6) The Arcade Fire's "Funeral" was the runaway indie-rock 
success story of 2005, selling 310,000 copies for Merge and 
attracting the support of Bono and David Bowie. The 
Montreal-based band spent significant chunks of 2006 working on 
"Neon Bible" and opted to self-produce the set. "We kind of 
realized that we already know how we want things to sound so we 
should just run after that sound as fast as we can and not rely 
on someone else to guide the good ship Arcade Fire," frontman 
Win Butler says. The pipe organ-laced "Intervention" was made available for 
sampling via a toll-free number on December 15, sending 
indie-rock blogs into a tizzy, and five London shows in late 
January/early February sold out in two minutes.
 GUNS N' ROSES Chinese Democracy (Geffen, March 6) In late December, Axl Rose broke his silence to announce he 
had parted ways with manager Merck Mercuriadis and that the 
decade-in-the-making "Chinese Democracy" would finally arrive 
March 6. It's anybody's guess if the date will hold, but a 
monster first week is a fair bet.
 AIR Pocket Symphony (Astralweks, March 6) Pulp's Jarvis Cocker and the Divine Comedy's Neil Hannon 
lend vocals to the French duo's latest, which is highlighted by 
the sexy instrumental opener "Space Maker" and the 
pulse-quickening electro-pop of "Mer du Japon." Drown yourself 
in the bottle during the Cocker-sung "Hell of a Party," a 
somber reflection on the morning after.
 GOOD CHARLOTTE Good Morning Revival (Epic, March 20) "It sounds like Good Charlotte," frontman Joel Madden says 
matter-of-factly about the Don Gilmore-produced "Good Morning 
Revival." "It sounds older. We sound more comfortable." Indeed, 
the first taste of new music was "Keep Your Hands Off My Girl," 
which Madden wrote after deciding, "I want to make a song I can 
hear in the club." The set also includes "I Don't Want to Be Loved," a heavily 
produced rocker in the vein of the Killers' "Jenny Was a Friend 
of Mine," and first single "The River," which features metal 
act Avenged Sevenfold.
 THE STOOGES The Weirdness (Virgin, March 20) So what does the first Stooges album since 1973 sound like? 
According to Iggy Pop, it sounds like, er, the Stooges. "You 
put it on and right away you'd know, well, that's them. There 
they go," he says of the project, which was recorded by Steve 
Albini and finds bassist Mike Watt filling in for the late Dave 
Alexander.
 AVRIL LAVIGNE The Best Dam Thing (RCA, date TBA) This curiously spelled April release will be preceded by 
the single "Girlfriend" in February and also features 
contributions from Lavigne's husband, Sum 41's Derryck Whibley, 
as well as +44 drummer Travis Barker. "It is really fast, fun, young, bratty, aggressive, 
confident (and) cocky in a playful way . . . all the good 
stuff," Lavigne wrote on her MySpace page earlier this month, 
adding that she was inspired to make a more uptempo album after 
spending "so much of my time playing live shows. I wanted to 
make sure the songs were fun -- fun for the fans and myself. I 
will only have, like, three slow songs on the record." "The Best Dam Thing" will be the follow-up to 2004's "Under 
My Skin," which debuted at No. 1 on The Billboard 200 and has 
sold 2.93 million copies.
 MANDY MOORE Wild Hope (Firm Music, date TBA) "It means a lot to me to make something that's mine," 
stresses Moore, who has forgone music for acting during the 
past four years. "It's a passion project," she says of "Wild 
Hope," her debut on the Firm's label. "It won't matter if it 
doesn't sell tons or have this high level of success." Moore's new set strips away the gloss from her earlier Sony 
Music recordings and finds her collaborating with such acts as 
the Weepies (on "Extraordinary" and the pop hit-in-waiting "All 
Good Things"), Lori McKenna ("Most of Me"), Rachael Yamagata 
("Ladies Choice") and Chantal Kreviazuk ("Gardenia").
 THREE 6 MAFIA Title TBA (Sony, date TBA) In February, Three 6 Mafia became the first rap act to win 
a best song Academy Award with "It's Hard Out Here for a Pimp," 
but what does it have cooking for its next album? "So far, 
we've got Chamillionaire, Lyfe Jennings, Paul Wall and Keke," 
DJ Paul says of contributors to the follow-up to 2005's "Most 
Known Unknown," which spawned the hits "Stay Fly" and "Poppin' 
My Collar." "Mainly just friends -- people we actually hang out 
with and go to bars with." Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/music-bestbets-dc-idUSN0126591620070102</link><sectors><value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>mellencamp , jones albums among early ' 07 releases</title></story></items>