<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:40 01 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> NEW YORK (Billboard) - Sick of the music scene in New York 
or London? It may be time to savor the delights of five 
unlikely cities spawning exciting new sounds.
 BEIJING Population: 14 million Main Language: Mandarin Chinese Shanghai may have become China's business heart, but 
Beijing remains its political and cultural capital -- and home 
to a burgeoning modern music scene eager to reach audiences 
outside the People's Republic. In the past, domestically successful rock bands like Tang 
Dynasty, Spring Autumn and AK-47 have emerged from Beijing, as 
did the "godfather" of Chinese rock, Cui Jian. Now a new 
generation of alternative acts is appearing. "Beijing has solidified its place as the locus of modern 
music on the mainland," says Shen Lihui, CEO of leading Beijing 
independent label Modern Sky. The healthy live scene is also starting to attract 
international acts such as U.S.-based banjo star Bela Fleck and 
U.K. alt-rockers Maximo Park. "At the moment it's uncharted territory," says Maximo Park 
manager Colin Schaverien. "But in five years it will be a 
natural routing point stop-off on the way to, or back from, 
Japan." The current crop of home-grown Beijing talent includes 
Modern Sky's goth-influenced "post-rock" act the Retros, who 
will appear at the South by Southwest confab in Austin, while 
ambient/electronic rock duo FM3 -- which has been picked up 
internationally after it was championed by Brian Eno -- has 
scheduled 30 European dates for 2007.
 BERLIN Population: 3.5 million Main Language: German Berlin's central role in the international dance music 
scene has been well-known since the Berlin Wall came down in 
1989. But now the relocated likes of electro artist Peaches; 
her fellow Canadian, techno pioneer Richie Hawtin (a.k.a. 
Plastikman); and U.S. DJ/producers Jay Haze and Stewart Walker 
are rubbing up against a burgeoning rock and pop scene as well. Metal act Rammstein blazed the trail, selling 10 million 
albums worldwide. Now, with support from a network of 16 local 
radio stations, a new generation of local acts is following in 
Rammstein's footsteps. Berlin boy band Tokio Hotel is the 
latest Pan-European pop sensation, with global sales of more 
than 2.4 million albums. Alt-rock act Virginia Jetzt has sold 20,000 copies of its 
debut album, while rock bands El*ke and Superleutnaant and pop 
outfit Naomi are all hot 2007 tips. "If you live in Berlin," Universal Music Germany CEO Frank 
Briegmann says, "you are at the very heart of modern music."
 BIRMINGHAM, ENGLAND Population: 1 million Main Language: English In a U.K. music scene perennially dominated by London and 
Manchester, England's "second city" has struggled, musically, 
in recent years. Yet Birmingham and the surrounding West Midlands region has 
produced acts ranging from rock monsters Led Zeppelin and Black 
Sabbath to Duran Duran. Now, the city -- long derided as an 
industrial wasteland -- has undergone hefty redevelopment and 
its music scene seems similarly re-energized. Locals say the 
success of the Birmingham-based Editors, whose 2005 debut album 
"The Back Room" is BPI-certified platinum (300,000 units), 
helped shift labels' talent-scouting focus to the city's 
independent/alt-rock sector. Birmingham alt-rock act the Twang just signed a label deal 
with B-Unique, the Polydor imprint that's home to the Kaiser 
Chiefs. Unsigned acts that could be next in line include the 
Weezer-influenced Murdoch and punky trio the Untitled Musical 
Project, plus the Enemy (from nearby Coventry) and Ripchord 
(from Wolverhampton).
 BRISBANE, AUSTRALIA Population: 2 million Main Language: English The eastern city of Brisbane has launched successful bands 
before -- from the Bee Gees in the '60s to Savage Garden in the 
'90s -- but now it has hit such a rich vein of talent that it's 
threatening Melbourne's traditional role as Australia's main 
music city. The city has spawned both of Australia's current biggest 
home-grown rock and pop groups: Powderfinger (1 million career 
sales) and the Veronicas (350,000 units), as well as solo 
sensation Pete Murray (600,000). Major label execs are now 
regulars in town, looking to do battle with local imprints. "Brisbane's always a city I keep my eye on," says Michael 
Parisi, Melbourne-based president of A&amp;R (artists and 
repertoire) at Warner Music, who helped put the city on the map 
when he signed art rock act Regurgitator in the mid-'90s. Parisi's new hip-hop signing Butterfingers heads the pack 
of new, young Brisbane bands looking to break out in 2007; it 
is followed by heavy-rock band the Butterfly Effect and 
singer/songwriters Andrew Morris, Katie Miller-Heidke and Kate 
Bradley. The live scene, based around the city's famous Fortitude 
Valley nightclub district, is also booming.
 MARSEILLE, FRANCE Population: 1.2 million Main Language: French This bustling Mediterranean port is France's second city in 
terms of population, behind Paris -- and it's growing, at more 
than 100,000 people per year. A large population of North African origin, along with the 
native French and a substantial community from sub-Saharan 
Africa, make this soccer-mad city an ethno-musical melting pot, 
where cheerleaders at Stade Velodrome -- home to leading team 
Olympique Marseille -- use decks and soundsystems. More and more, French promoters describe Marseille's 
10,000-capacity main venue Le Dome as "a must" for visiting 
urban talent -- Snoop Dogg and the Roots played there recently, 
with Beyonce booked for 2007. Following established local rap and reggae acts like IAM 
and Massilia Sound System, politicized female rapper Keny 
Arkana has sold 50,000 copies of her debut album "Entre Ciment 
et Belles Etoiles" despite a refusal to do mainstream 
promotion. Other names to watch include quirky rock/hip-hop duo Oai 
Star, eclectic reggae/Cajun trio Moussu Te Lei Jovents and 
Aliman Staff. Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/music-global-dc-idUSN0126189720070102</link><sectors><value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>beijing , berlin among music hot spots in 2007</title></story></items>