<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:16 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> The Times ITV INVESTS 20 MILLION POUNDS IN BROADBAND TELEVISION
ENTERPRISE ITV (ITV.L) is investing 20 million pounds in broadband
television, which it plans to launch at the end of March despite
believing viewers may not be willing to pay to watch much
television online. The commercial broadcaster, which has been
criticised for being slow to develop its Internet presence
compared particularly with the BBC, is hoping a "mixed economy"
of paid for and free programming will emerge, providing new
revenue stream to offset weak television advertising revenues. HOUSING DOUBT Recent figures from the Land Registry show house price
increases may be slowing, with the cost of the average home in
England and Wales rising by 6.8 percent to 172,000 pounds in the
year to November compared to the seven percent annual price
inflation reported for October. Nationwide had recorded a 10.5
percent increase in house prices as a whole. SKY PLUS GROWS BSkyB BSY.L, the satellite broadcaster, which is 39.1
percent owned by News Corporation, has reported a 56 percent
increase in the number of homes that took a subscription to its
premium Sky Plus personal video recorder service. The
broadcaster also unveiled plans to launch a video-on-demand
service later this year. The Daily Telegraph BARCLAYS RAISES SAVERS' RATES Barclays Bank (BARC.L) has increased the rate on its Regular
Saver account to enable savers to earn up to 12.5 percent gross
interest a year. However, this is applicable only to the bank's
current account customers and the maximum permissible
contribution is 250 pounds a month for a year. S&amp;N RAISES CHINESE BEER MAKER STAKE Scottish &amp; Newcastle SCTN.L is to spend up to 100 million
pounds to bolster its stake in Chongqing Brewery Company (CBC),
one of China's leading brewers, to just under 20 percent. The
additional investment, which was prompted by a proposed
restructuring of CBC that will see its brewing subsidiaries
injected into its Shanghai-listed parent, comes after an initial
35 million pound outlay in February. S&amp;N trails SAB Miller in
China, where the Anglo-South African company has invested
heavily in partnership with China Resources Snow Breweries. LITTLE CHEF FINDS BUYER Little Chef, the troubled roadside restaurant chain, is
expected to announce it has signed an 11th hour rescue deal with
two new investors -- the Israeli property group Arazim, which
owns 65 of the company's restaurant sites, and the turn-round
specialist R capital. The two are to invest 10 million pounds to
buy at least a majority stake in the chain. The Guardian SWITCH TO REITS WILL COST BIGGEST FIRMS 300 MILLION POUNDS
EACH Britain's biggest quoted property companies, British Land
(BLND.L) and Land Securities (LAND.L) have estimated the
required one-off payment of two percent of the value of their
property portfolio to be paid to the Treasury for converting
from corporations to real estate investment trusts (Reits) will
cost each company about 300 million pounds. Reit status enables
property firms to avoid corporation and capital gains tax, and
means dividends can be paid out of untaxed income if at least 90
percent goes to shareholders. ROLLS-ROYCE MAN TAKES FRONT-SEAT ROLE AT HSBC Simon Robertson, chairman of Rolls-Royce (RR.L), who joined
the board of HSBC (HSBA.L) a year ago, is to become senior
independent non-executive director at the bank. The position,
which includes having discussions with shareholders, is
particularly significant at HSBC, which has both an executive
chairman and a chief executive. VODAFONE'S AMBITIONS IN INDIA THREATENED BY ESSAR BUYOUT
OFFER Plans by Vodafone (VOD.L) to acquire India's Hutchison Essar
were yesterday dealt a blow after minority shareholder Essar
Teleholdings reportedly offered 5.6 billion pounds for the 67
percent stake owned by joint venture partner Hutchison Telecom.
The reported offer pitches the Indian firm against a number of
companies including Vodafone and the Indian mobile operator
Reliance, which has been bullish about acquiring the operator. The Independent RECORD NUMBER OF UK INSOLVENCIES ANTICIPATED AFTER CHRISTMAS
SPREE Grant Thornton, a leading firm of accountants, has predicted
the number of people declaring themselves insolvent over the
next three months will soar following Christmas over-spending.
The firm said it expected 30,000 individuals to become insolvent
during the first quarter of 2007, with many being the result of
excessive spending in the festive season. A spokeswoman for
Citizens Advice said: "We do see evidence of Christmas debt
hangover, and this month we expect to exceed the 140,000
problems that Citizens Advice bureaux dealt with in January
2006." BANKS JOIN THE CRUSH FOR JANUARY SALES Three of Britain's big four banks -- HSBC (HSBA.L), Barclays
(BARC.L) and Lloyds TSB (LLOY.L) -- this week resorted to high
street retailer-style New Year sales in a bid to retain market
share and win business from each other. For instance, HSBC this
week launched the Green Sale, offering cheap deals on mortgages
and credit cards as well as higher savings rates. Barclays Bank
yesterday announced it would offer an annual interest rate of
12.5 percent to current account customers opening a Regular
Saver account before Feb. 28, while Lloyds TSB launched a new
fixed-rate mortgage costing just 1.99 percent in the first 12
months. PARTYGAMING IN DEAL WITH PLAYTECH Shares in PartyGaming PRTY.L surged 12 percent to 35.5
pence yesterday after the online gaming company announced a
four-year licensing agreement with the Aim-listed software
provider Playtech that could lead to future deals in Asia
between the two firms. Under the deal, Playtech will power the
gaming Web sites that PartyGaming agreed to buy last month from
Empire Online and InterContinental Online for 36.6 million
pounds in shares. Analysts said if PartyGaming were to move into
China, then Playtech would be well placed to provide the
software for its sites. Prepared for Reuters by Durrants. </text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/press-digest-british-business-jan-idUSL0349114420070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>press digest - british business - jan 3</title></story></items>