<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:42 31 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text> NEW YORK (Billboard) - You can't blame U2's concert 
promoter for wondering just how big the band's Vertigo world 
tour could have been if it had simply kept on playing. After all, not one ticket went unsold for the 131 shows on 
the trek, which began March 28, 2005, in San Diego and wrapped 
December 9 in front of 47,000 fans at Honolulu's Aloha Stadium. Having been on the road in fits and starts since March 
2005, U2 was clearly in a celebratory mood in Hawaii, as Bono 
danced onstage with a woman from the crowd during "Mysterious 
Ways" and even pulled a lucky guy out of the audience to play 
piano with the band during "Who's Gonna Ride Your Wild Horses." 
Whether waving the American flag high above his head amid 
opener "City of Blinding Lights" or writhing on the stage 
blindfolded for "Bullet the Blue Sky," the frontman was holding 
nothing back. When all was said and done, Vertigo clocked in as the 
second-highest grossing tour of all time: $389 million from an 
astonishing audience of 4,619,021, second only to the Rolling 
Stones' concurrent A Bigger Bang trek, which may continue into 
2007, and has grossed more. "I sometimes try and visualize, what would be the 
universe?" promoter Arthur Fogel told Billboard. "In other 
words, what if you could just play and play and play? We sold 
over four-and-a-half million tickets on this tour, but we still 
underplayed basically everywhere we've gone." Vertigo visited arenas in North America through late May 
2005, then played stadiums in Europe throughout that summer. In 
the fall, it was back to North America for a run that included 
six shows at Toronto's Air Canada Center and six at New York's 
Madison Square Garden. February and March took U2 to South America, which was 
originally to be followed by dates in Australia, New Zealand 
and Japan. Those shows, however, were postponed until the fall 
due to a serious illness that struck within the immediate 
family of a band member. Details have never been publicly 
disclosed. Getting Vertigo back on track was the final hurdle for 
Fogel. He and U2 manager Paul McGuinness say they're in contact 
all the time, even a year before the first fan has filed into a 
venue. "As the record develops, the production develops," 
McGuinness said. "And depending on when the record is finished, 
we have an imaginary start date. That's subject to change, but 
the thinking about the production is always simultaneous with 
the making of the album." The Vertigo stage set featured an ellipse-shaped extension 
that allowed band members to travel far into the 
general-admission crowd on the floor. It required 30 semi 
trucks to get from place to place, according to stage manager 
Rocko Reedy. On a good day, it took two-and-a-half hours to 
assemble, but that duration could nearly double depending on 
weather and venue configurations. After being loaded post-show 
onto the trucks, the stage was packed onto three 747s to travel 
to the next venue. Early in the tour, U2 performed in front of seven 
see-through LED curtains, onto which images and patterns were 
projected. Later, a giant, super high-tech LED screen was used 
instead to form the backdrop. "All the stuff we use is always serial number 001," Reedy 
said. "The first time they create this type of technology, it's 
U2 that uses it. Then everybody else under the sun goes out and 
gets it, so we just have to come up with something new." That said, Vertigo has not been without its share of drama. 
The tour got off to a rocky start after a disastrous presale 
for paid members of u2.com in January 2005, when demand far 
exceeded the ticket allotment, prompting shut-out fans to blast 
management and even band members themselves on Internet forums. "The demand was artificially stimulated because, quite 
honestly, a lot of ticket scalpers had joined u2.com planning 
to trade the tickets," McGuinness said. "It was clear very 
early those tickets would have a higher resale value than face 
value. We got caught by that, and we certainly underestimated 
the demand that would arise through the fan club. We did the 
best we could to meet it. But we'll be a little more careful 
next time." Then, in the wake of the Asia-Pacific postponements, Fogel 
spent months dealing with insurance issues. "That process took 
a very long time and was very difficult in complex, but 
ultimately resulted favorably," he says. "That probably was a 
much greater challenge than the actual logistics of bringing 
the production and personnel back together. "We had a few venue issues (rescheduling) in Japan, because 
originally we were playing outdoors at Yokohama Stadium," he 
added. "Given we were now in early December, the weather is 
such that we had to then look to go indoors. So, we had to 
basically refund 60,000 tickets and then resell for three shows 
at an arena." But, to the surprise of nobody, the fans were still right 
there waiting to attend the makeup dates. "In Australia, even 
though we were postponing the shows by six months or so, almost 
no customers asked for a refund," McGuinness said. And indeed, 
the time off allowed U2 to rejigger the tour set list, as well 
as record "The Saints Are Coming" and the new song "Window in 
the Skies" with producer Rick Rubin. Both were released on the 
compilation "U218 Singles" in November. While it may have been tempting to entertain adding still 
more shows to the itinerary after the fall leg, McGuinness said 
this was "a logical point to stop. We're obviously aware we 
could go on and on and on, but selling out (venues) is actually 
more important to us than the gross." So where does the U2 go from here? The first destination is 
the recording studio, sometime in 2007, with an eye on 
releasing a new album by the end of the year. McGuinness 
predicted the next tour would then begin in 2008. "All I can say is it will be completely different the next 
time, but it will be big," he said. "I think our audience 
expects very big productions. We've become good at doing that, 
and I think it is part of U2's reputation." The band may even 
experiment with commercially releasing select concerts as 
downloads shortly after their completion. "That's something 
we're exploring," McGuinness acknowledged. "In the future there 
will be more what we call 'band-to-fan activity."' Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/music-u2-dc-idUSN2925649020070102</link><sectors><value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>u2 : from joshua trees to palm trees</title></story></items>