<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:35 31 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text> NASHVILLE (Billboard) - We know that the Rolling Stones, 
Kenny Chesney, Tim McGraw/Faith Hill and Dave Matthews Band 
will sell the heck out of tickets in 2007. But there is always a dark horse that rises seemingly out 
of nowhere to become a huge seller each year. In 2005 it was 
Motley Crue. Last year it was the Def Leppard/Journey package. 
Here we'll take a look at who we might be talking about in 
December as exceeding expectations at the box office.
 KEITH URBAN 2006 boxscore: $10.2 million, 32 shows Reason to watch in 2007: His recent stint in rehab 
notwithstanding, Keith Urban is a country music headliner whose 
time has come. And while the tour has been delayed from its planned 
kickoff of mid-February (June is more likely now), he will 
likely be met with a dynamic reception at the box office. 
Country fans are a pretty forgiving bunch (as long as you're 
not perceived as unpatriotic), and Urban's album sales have 
been strong, even with zero promotion from the artist. Besides 
that, Urban's much-publicized marriage to Nicole Kidman, and 
even publicity from his recent stint in rehab, have greatly 
raised his profile beyond country music circles.
 BRAD PAISLEY 2006 boxscore: $28 million, 97 shows Reason to watch in 2007: Country music's most dangerous 
triple threat -- singer/songwriter/guitar slinger -- since 
Vince Gill, Brad Paisley has been a true road warrior in 
working his way to headlining status. In 2006, he entered 
Billboard Boxscore's yearly Top 25 Tour list for the first 
time.
 TOOL 2006 boxscore: $20.6 million, 39 shows Reason to watch in 2007: Tool has found another gear. One of the most strived-for dynamics in the touring 
business is when a veteran band not only maintains its 
popularity, but then develops a surge in popularity built by 
word-of-mouth and consistently strong performances. That is the 
case with Tool, which released its first album in 1992. The 
band's 2006 tour behind its "10,000 Days" release was its most 
successful yet. Tool wrapped up 2006 with a European trek, and is set to 
tour the Pacific Rim in early 2007. Promoters are now booking 
North American dates for the spring.
 ROGER WATERS 2006 boxscore: $13 million, 10 shows Reason to watch in 2007: Pink Floyd's "The Dark Side of the 
Moon" has been on the Billboard charts for more than 1,500 
weeks and counting. And Roger Waters, a founding member of the group and key 
developer of the album's concept, is playing it in its entirety 
in concert, to critical acclaim. Plans are under way for a 2007 North American tour for 
Waters, who will probably play a mixture of indoor and outdoor 
dates. The Achilles heel of a Waters tour may be the ticket 
price. With a high of $260 in 2006, Waters is a little pricey, 
even though he rarely tours the United States.
 LINKIN PARK 2006 boxscore: N/A Reason to watch in 2007: Fresh markets and a 
much-anticipated new album. Linkin Park has not toured since 2004, when the Los Angeles 
band grossed $35 million and drew nearly 1 million fans to 67 
shows. Now a new Linkin Park album, co-produced with Rick Rubin, 
will be released this spring. The band will headline a fourth 
Projekt Revolution tour -- its self-branded, multi-act, 
genre-bending festival-style extravaganza that in the past has 
included such acts as Cypress Hill, the Apex Theory, Xzibit, 
Snoop Dogg, the Used and Less Than Jake. Linkin Park will kick off its touring cycle May 6 in the 
United States with a headline performance at the Bamboozle 
Festival at Giants Stadium in East Rutherford, N.J. Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/music-tours-dc-idUSN3146980420070102</link><sectors><value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>urban , paisley , waters set to hit road in 2007</title></story></items>