<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:19 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Low market volatility and a yen that refused to budge even as the Japanese economy strengthened made last year difficult for foreign exchange traders.In 2007, a firmer yen, a possible dollar rebound and a resurgent U.S. economy are among the themes coming into focus."It's not a stretch to say it's been the toughest year in a long time," said Richard Franulovich, currency strategist at Westpac Banking Corp. in New York. "Month after month, the low-volatility environment has caused returns to fall."Analysts give a variety of explanations for lack of volatility, including the increasing prevalence of electronic trading systems and trading by central banks with massive currency reserves at their disposal.But even the craftiest of trading strategies ran into trouble when it came to the yen.Merrill Lynch, which reported returns of 4.6 percent on a portfolio of 2006 G10 and emerging market discretionary trade recommendations, said in a year-end note that the dollar-yen rate "probably confounded expectations the most."Earlier in the year, the yen briefly increased in value to about 110 per dollar from 118 after the Bank of Japan ended its zero-interest-rate policy and leaders from Group of Seven advanced economies urged faster Asian currency appreciation.But the move didn't last, and the Bank of Japan confounded markets by raising rates only once in 2006. That kept the yen under pressure by preserving the carry trade in which investors borrow cheap yen to buy higher-yielding assets.The median forecast of 16 banks polled by Reuters in December 2005 put the dollar at 108 yen by the end of 2006.Instead, the yen ended the year at 119 per dollar, little changed from late 2005. It was near an all-time high above 157 per euro, 12 percent weaker than when 2006 began.With the Bank of Japan seen raising rates more aggressively in 2007 and the European Central Bank likely to extend its tightening campaign in the first half of the year, analysts expect carry trades to unwind in 2007 and the yen to rise.But strategists at Goldman Sachs, who got 58 percent of their short-term trade recommendations right to net a total return of 12.2 percent, warned in a research note that "getting the timing right on such an unwinding is tricky."For one thing, those who were burned in 2006 may not be as eager to jump on the yen bandwagon this time around, especially given that the Bank of Japan has taken its time raising rates.Indeed, while markets are gearing up for a possible rate hike in late January, speculators continue to bet against the currency, keeping it under steady pressure."The market has sounded the death knell of the yen carry trade many times, but people continue to be short the yen," said Marc Chandler, senior currency strategist at Brown Brothers Harriman in New York.Deutsche Bank strategists, who reported returns in excess of 3.4 percent on a package of G10 trade recommendations in 2006, forecast "back-loaded" yen strength in 2007, with a move to 98 yen per dollar by year-end.Strategists at BNP Paribas were more aggressive. In a year-end note to clients, they said a sharper-than-expected U.S. slowdown will push the euro to $1.40 and the dollar to 105 yen by midyear.The euro was another troublemaker for investors as it spent much of the year trapped in a $1.25-$1.29 range. It failed to get much mileage out of a steady stream of rate hikes from the European Central Bank and a pause in the Federal Reserve's own tightening campaign in August.Only in late November did the euro break above $1.30, helped by expectations that the Fed may have to cut rates next year to give a jolt to a faltering U.S. economy.THE BOY SCOUT APPROACH: 'BE PREPARED'There are those, though, that highlight a number of risks that could make currency trading as difficult in 2007 as it was in 2006.In what they called an "alternative 2007" forecast, strategists at State Street Global Markets in Boston highlight a number of risks that could upset the emerging consensus view of a stronger yen and euro, a weaker dollar and tighter global liquidity.Among them are a stabilization of the U.S. housing market, Federal Reserve interest rate hikes rather than cuts, dollar strength rather than weakness, and a sudden slowdown in the euro zone economy."As all good Boy Scouts know, 'be prepared' is not a bad rule to live by," they wrote in a note to clients.Recent U.S. economic data has been surprisingly robust, particularly reports on home sales that suggest the worst of the housing slump may have already passed.Chandler said a U.S. economic rebound is likely to surprise the market in 2007. "The one bet that has proven wrong time and again is a bet against the U.S. consumer," he said.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-usa-forex-idUSN0233761820070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>fx market ready for higher ' 07 returns</title></story></items>