<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:34 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WARSAW Poland's top oil group PKN Orlen PKNA.WA aims to expand further in central and eastern Europe and may take part in the privatization of Serbian state oil monopoly NIS this year, its chief executive said on Tuesday."I hope that PKN Orlen will be present in more countries and will not lose sight of the chances for further expansion," Igor Chalupec told Reuters in an interview."I can't rule out that if we see the opportunity for acquisitions in the Balkans and Romania or for boosting our share in the home markets we will make use of it," he added.PKN, which controls Czech downstream oil processor Unipetrol UNPEsp.PR, in December completed the $2.3 billion takeover of Lithuania's refiner Mazeikiu Nafta MNF1L.VL.Chalupec said PKN would consider buying into NIS in a sale which officials have said Serbia should carry out in early 2007. Belgrade expects to get at least $300 million for a 25 percent stake in the company."We will be looking at the privatization of NIS, but in that case the schedule will be decided by the seller," he said.Chalupec said he hoped for a positive contribution to group results from Mazeikiu despite a fire in mid-October that cut the Baltic states' sole refiner's production by just over half its capacity."I hope that Mazeikiu's impact on PKN group results this year will be positive. But it will be difficult and will depend on the pace at which the burned down installation will be rebuilt," he said.RECORD YEARChalupec said he expected PKN's full-year profits for 2006 to hit record highs despite a weaker fourth quarter."I expect the fourth quarter will be weaker than earlier quarters," Chalupec said. "But even despite the weaker last quarter, we could see a record year on the operating level after excluding the effects of negative goodwill on 2005 results."Chalupec said market conditions in refining could prove to be tougher than last year, but the company should benefit from a more favorable environment for its petrochemicals business."We expect that oil prices will this year fluctuate within a 55-65 dollars per barrel range," he said. "We expect greater stability of refining margins, although their average level and (Ural/Brent) differential could be lower than last year."PKN suffered from a narrower price differential between Ural crude it refines and Brent North Sea, used as a benchmark for product prices, in the third quarter last year, but it managed to more than offset this effect with higher retail margins.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-pkn-ceo-idUSL0293557620070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>pkn plans further expansion , eyes serbia</title></story></items>