<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:36 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MADRID Spain's government said on Tuesday that a car bombing at Madrid airport blamed on Basque separatists ETA has ended the country's peace process.Officials however believe that a weakened ETA is incapable of a sustained bombing campaign."ETA has broken, has liquidated, has finished the process," Interior Minister Alfredo Perez Rubalcaba told a news conference as rescuers using heavy lifters continued searching for the bodies of two men believed killed in Saturday's attack.It was the strongest language by a government minister since the car bomb wrecked a multi-storey carpark at the ultra-modern Terminal Four of Madrid's Barajas airport.ETA has not claimed responsibility for the bomb, but police said one of three callers making anonymous telephone warnings before the explosion identified him or herself as an ETA member.Hours after the bomb, Prime Minister Jose Luis Rodriguez Zapatero suspended all efforts to seek dialogue with ETA, effectively ending a peace process he had started in June after the guerrillas declared a ceasefire in March.But Zapatero's response was criticized by the conservative opposition Popular Party, which had opposed talks with ETA from the start and demanded the government now unequivocally declare the peace process dead."Obviously the process has finished," Rubalcaba said, adding a barb for the opposition, "And now I've cleared that up, it would be fantastic if we could all work together to put an end to violence in Spain."TIME HAS RUN OUTETA killed over 800 people in four decades of violent struggle for independence for the Basque Country in northern Spain and southwest France. Its fight began during the Franco dictatorship when the Basque language and culture were suppressed but, in today's democratic Spain, only a minority of Basques want full independence, according to polls.In recent years, Spanish and French police arrested hundreds of suspected guerrillas, gutting the operational ability of a group which never reached the critical mass of public support it needed to generate momentum toward independence.ETA is no longer capable of a major bombing campaign, according to Attorney General Candido Conde-Pumpido"I think that ETA's time of terrorism has run out forever and the situation is irreversible. I think ETA has been defeated, and we are at its funeral," Conde-Pumpido told newspaper El Mundo."That doesn't mean we can't have tragedies or setbacks, like the Barajas bomb," he said,ETA's political ally Batasuna, a party banned for its links to the guerrillas, insists it still wanted to negotiate peace.But Basque separatists have been frustrated that the ceasefire did not lead to an easing of police pressure on ETA or the transfer of guerrilla prisoners to jails nearer their homes. They were also angered at the continuing ban on Batasuna."Ultimately they would prefer the peaceful road, not to be letting off car bombs, but they feel that in the circumstances they have been betrayed," said Alec Reid, an Irish priest who has been involved with peace efforts in both the Basque Country and Northern Ireland."I am certain that the peace process will go ahead at the end of the day, with the Lord's help," he told Reuters by telephone, adding that Saturday's bomb reminded him of when the IRA broke a ceasefire in 1996 before returning to talks.(Additional reporting by Ben Harding)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-spain-eta-idUSL024808020070102</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>spain says peace process broken by eta bomb</title></story></items>