<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:04 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> The Financial Times NEW PLASTIC MICROCHIP COULD BE THE LAST WORD IN TECHNOLOGY Plastic Logic, a Cambridge-based British company, is
expected to announce today it has secured 50.6 million pounds to
build the world's first plant for making semiconductors out of
plastic rather than silicon. The plant is to be built by the end
of next year in Dresden, Germany with financial backing from the
U.S. groups Oak Investment Partners and Tudor Investment
Corporation. Jim Tully, head of semiconductors at the U.S.
market research group Gartners, said while silicon chips were
unlikely to be superseded, plastic chips could emerge as an
important sector. HOUSE PRICES REVEAL "CALMER MARKET" Latest figures from the Land Registry show house prices rose
by 0.6 percent in November to take the annual pace of house
price inflation to 6.8 percent. The figures also showed prices
fell in London by 0.6 percent over the month in what could be a
sign the long-buoyant market has started cooling. The best
performer over the month was the West Midlands where prices rose
by two percent. CONVICTIONS FOR FRAUD SHOW STEEP RISE Annual research carried out by BDO Stoy Hayward, a leading
accounting firm, has found a sharp rise last year in the volume
of fraud successfully prosecuted in the courts. The firm said it
expected to see growth this year in fraud related to corporate
lending as false claims were exposed in business plans used by
companies to attract capital for investment and acquisitions.
The research, which excluded benefit fraud and cases involving
less than 50,000 pounds, found the value of fraud in court cases
which resulted in convictions rose almost 40 percent to 1.37
billion pounds. CHRISTMAS EXCESS SET TO BOOST INSOLVENCY NUMBERS Grant Thornton, a financial consultancy, has estimated some
30,000 consumers in England and Wales will become insolvent in
the first quarter of the year, with a third of these resulting
from excessive spending over Christmas. The number of consumers
opting for insolvency has been fuelled by more people opting for
individual voluntary arrangement (IVAs), which is being marketed
as an easy way of offloading debt. BSKYB TO OFFER VIDEO ON DEMAND British Sky Broadcasting BSY.L is to launch a new service
later in the year that will allow more than one million of its
users to access a selection of popular programmes at any time.
The service, the first step towards offering video on demand
services, makes use of the spare hard disk capacity on newer
Sky+ and high-definition set-top boxes -- the video recorders
that already allow viewers to record, rewind, fast-forward and
pause programmes. BSkyB also published research showing 12.2
percent of its Sky+ customers' viewing was "time-shifted". BT BROADBAND ON 10 MILLION TARGET Ben Verwaayen, chief executive of BT (BT.L), said the
telephone company added more than 700,000 broadband connections
in the last quarter of 2006, putting it on course to have 10
million connections this week -- double the original target the
company had set in April 2002. Verwaayen said the broadband
market had undergone a "dramatic" shift, from cable companies
shaving a 60 percent share of the market in 2002 to just 24
percent of customers getting their broadband connection from NTL
Telwest now. UK PROPERTY GROUPS WARM TO REIT STATUS Nine of Britain's biggest property companies including Land
Securities (LAND.L) and British Land (BLND.L) yesterday took
advantage of new government legislation and began a new life as
tax free real estate investment trusts (Reits). Some of the new
Reits enjoyed gains in their share prices on their first day of
trading as investors sized up the potential for higher dividend
payouts. However, some experts have cautioned the arrival of
Reits might coincide with the top of the investment cycle in
property. LITTLE CHEF POISED TO ESCAPE COLLAPSE THROUGH TEN MILLION
POUND BID The troubled UK roadside restaurant chain Little Chef is
believed to have narrowly escaped collapse last night after two
investors -- the Israeli property company Arazim Investments and
a UK-based private equity firm RCapital -- made a bid of less
than 10 million pounds to acquire the chain. The investors will
close 40 of the company's 234 restaurants, keeping the remaining
194 open for business. Little Chef has been adding healthier
food to its menus and slashing prices in an attempt to revive
its fortunes and help it compete with new entrants into the
market such as Marks and Spencer (MKS.L). BOARDROOM SHAKE-UP AT HSBC Simon Robertson, a former Goldman Sachs investment banker
and chairman of Rolls-Royce (RR.L) was yesterday appointed by
HSBC (HSBA.L) as its leading non-executive director. The
appointment, part of the bank's boardroom reshuffle, appears
designed to appease some anxious shareholders after the world's
fourth largest bank suffered a sharp share price dip at the end
of 2006. The share price fall was triggered by concerns about
the bank's exposure to sub-prime mortgage lending in the United
States, where borrowers have been squeezed by rising interest
rates. Prepared for Reuters by Durrants. </text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/press-digest-financial-times-jan-idUSL037977620070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>press digest - financial times - jan 3</title></story></items>