<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:49 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>CHICAGO U.S. home builder Lennar Corp. (LEN.N) and a Cerberus Capital Management holding said on Tuesday they will sell a 62 percent stake in a joint venture that owns 15,000 acres in southern California for more than $1.3 billion.Lennar also slashed its forecast for a fourth-quarter profit before one-time items by as much as 46 percent, citing lower profit margins amid the deteriorating U.S. housing market.It will record a net loss due to pretax charges of up to $500 million to write off deposits and pre-acquisition costs for land under option it doesn't intend to buy.Home builders have cut forecasts and posted lower earnings over the last several quarters as demand has slumped, and Lennar Chief Executive Stuart Miller sees no end in sight."Market conditions continued to weaken throughout the fourth quarter and we have not yet seen tangible evidence of a market recovery," he said in a statement.Under the deal with MW Housing Partners, Lennar and Cerberus's LNR Property Corp. each will receive a cash distribution of about $660 million from the newly restructured LandSource Communities Development LLC, which owns 15,000 acres of land in Santa Clarita Valley, about 30 miles north of downtown Los Angeles, Lennar said.MW Housing will contribute cash and property to the venture with a combined value of about $900 million in exchange for the 62 percent financial interest in LandSource, Lennar said.MW Housing is co-managed by real estate investment management company MacFarlane Partners and includes the California Public Employees' Retirement System (CalPERS).As of July 1, LandSource had assets with a book value of about $1.3 billion, with its primary investment being the Newhall Land and Farming Co., which owns the Santa Clarita land that includes 23,000 residential home sites and 700 acres of commercial land and other property.The MW Housing property, on which Lennar has options, is being contributed based on fair market value, Lennar said. The home builder will continue to have options to purchase those home sites at market prices.While MW Housing will hold the 62 percent financial interest, it will have 50 percent voting control of the venture, which will continue to be jointly operated by Lennar and LNR, Lennar said.The deal is expected to close in February, Lennar said.Lennar will see about $500 million in profit from the transaction, of which about $125 million will be recognized at closing and about $375 million will be deferred over future years.It also will receive management fees over the next 11 years and retain an interest in LandSource of about 19 percent.Under terms of the deal, LandSource assets are valued at about $2.6 billion, with a potential increase adjustment to that value of over $600 million, Lennar said.For the fourth quarter, Lennar cut its profit outlook because of "materially lower gross margins on home sales ... as a result of deteriorating market conditions in the home building industry."Excluding charges of between $400 million and $500 million related to the land-related write-offs, the Miami-based company now expects fourth-quarter earnings in the range of 70 to 75 cents a share.In September, Lennar had cut its forecast to a range of $1 to $1.30 a share from a range of $2.55 to $2.60 a share. Analysts already had cut their consensus estimate to $1.07 a share, according to Reuters Estimates.After the charges, Lennar expects a loss in the range of 88 cents to $1.28 a share.Lennar said deliveries fell 2.8 percent to 14,403 homes in the quarter, while new orders declined 6 percent and backlog slumped 42 percent from a year ago to $4 billion at the end of November.(Additional reporting by Lilla Zuill and Chris Kaufman in New York)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-caneylennar-lnr-idUSN0231889320070102</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Markets</value></value></sectors><title>lennar to cut stake in venture , slashes outlook</title></story></items>