<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:20 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds comments, quotes from trade official, changes dateline,
previous SAO PAULO)BRASILIA Jan 2 (Reuters) - Brazil posted a record $46.08
billion trade surplus for 2006 due to growing demand for the
products it sells abroad, the trade ministry said on Tuesday. Exports grew 16 percent in 2006 to $137 billion and imports
rose 24 percent to $91 billion. But the government expects the surplus to shrink in 2007 as
imports keep growing faster than exports, said Ivan Ramalho,
the trade ministry's executive secretary. Exports should rise 10.5 percent to $152 billion in 2007 as
a wider group of countries buys Brazil's products, Ramalho
predicted. "The market diversification that occurred in 2006 should
continue in 2007," he said, adding that the government has no
set target for imports. In December, the surplus BRTBAL=ECI was $5.01 billion, an
increase from $4.33 billion in December 2005. In 2005, the surplus was $44.71 billion, Brazil's largest
ever surplus at the time. The country is an agricultural and mining giant that also
exports manufactured goods such as airplanes and cars. Even though the local currency is near its strongest level
in years, Brazil's trade surplus has widened in recent years
because of strong commodities prices and a bigger pool of
countries that buy its exports, especially in Asia. Brazil's trade performance has improved since 1999 when a
gaping current account deficit triggered the devaluation of the
local currency, the real BRBY. The wider trade surpluses have closed the current account
gap, and for 2006 Brazil is widely expected to post a current
account surplus for the fourth straight year. ($1 = 2.15 reais)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/brazil-economy-trade-idUSN0232256020070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 4 - brazil posts record trade surplus in 2006</title></story></items>