<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:47 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> LOS ANGELES (Billboard) - The anti-digital rights 
management (DRM) bandwagon is getting more crowded by the day. 
Even some major-label executives are pushing for the right to 
sell digital downloads as unprotected MP3s. In 2007, the majors will get the message, and the DRM wall 
will begin to crumble. Why? Because they'll no longer be able 
to point to a growing digital marketplace as justification that 
DRM works. Revenue from digital downloads and mobile content is 
expected to be flat or, in some cases, decline next year. If 
the digital market does in fact stall, alternatives to DRM will 
look much more attractive. Revenue from digital music has yet to offset losses from 
still-declining CD sales, and digital track sales remain a 
cause for concern. Month-over-month download figures were 
largely flat through 2006, even in the face of year-over-year 
gains. If the expected post-holiday spike in download numbers 
that has occurred in the past two years is weak, look for the 
glass on the panic button to break. "People in the industry will have a very different 
conversation in January when the dust clears and they realize 
just how bad this year really was," says Eric Garland, CEO of 
peer-to-peer (P2P) tracking firm BigChampagne. Even more of a concern is mobile. According to Gartner G2 
analyst Mike McGuire, the ringtone market -- currently 
contributing more than half of all digital revenue -- will 
soften during the next 12-18 months as it matures. Meanwhile, the music industry wants a strong competitor to 
the monster it created called iTunes. Forcing would-be 
competitors to sell music incompatible with the popular iPod is 
not showing any signs of working. Removing DRM would attract 
powerful new players to the market, and that -- the theory goes 
-- will result in more buyers. "The majors . . . have got to capitulate, or they will 
continue to have a fractured digital media market that will 
slow down and stagnate," says Terry McBride, president of 
Nettwerk Music Group, management home of such acts as Sarah 
McLachlan and Avril Lavigne. Here are five places to watch this year's DRM developments:
 AMAZON The online retailer reportedly is itching to get into 
digital downloads but is holding out for a DRM-free service. It 
sells as many iPods as anybody and is a haven for music that is 
disappearing from physical retail shelves. "They already have a 
relationship with our consumer the way that a lot of others 
don't," Blue Note GM Zach Hochkeppel says. Viewed as the 
biggest threat to iTunes, Amazon has the power to force a DRM 
strategy shift.
 LIMEWIRE Still in the process of settling with the music industry, 
the P2P file-sharing service wants to start charging its 40 
million users $1 per download and share the revenue and 
user-behavior information with the music industry. But it wants 
to stay DRM-free. The company hired TAG Strategic consultant 
Ted Cohen, a former EMI exec, to convince the majors to at 
least test the idea for six months.
 MYSPACE The most popular Internet destination in the world is 
working with SnoCap to launch a music download service that 
would let musicians sell music directly from their profiles and 
that of their fans. But it will only sell files as MP3s. It is 
moving ahead by focusing on independent and unsigned artists 
willing to release unprotected music, and a successful showing 
would make the majors take notice.
 EMUSIC The indie-only specialist just surpassed 100 million 
downloads; it's the second-largest digital music retailer after 
iTunes, all sans DRM. CEO David Packman says he is not 
interested in selling major-label fare, but he may have no 
choice if majors suddenly allow his competitors to sell in MP3 
as well. But even if the majors did relent to MP3 sales on 
eMusic, the company's business model would have to change--no 
label will agree to 50 downloads for $15 per month.
 YAHOO MUSIC GM David Goldberg has convinced Sony BMG and EMI Music 
Group to test the DRM-free waters with limited, promotional 
"experiments" involving Jessica Simpson, Jesse McCartney, 
Relient K and Norah Jones. The lessons learned from these tests 
will either speed or slow their path to eliminating DRM. Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-digital-dc-idUSN0229577320070102</link><sectors><value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>Tech, </value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>ailing music biz set to relax digital restrictions</title></story></items>