<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:23 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>DETROIT Jan 2 General Motors Corp. (GM.N) on
Tuesday unveiled details of its new Chevrolet Malibu, a car
aimed at grabbing market share from its Japanese rivals. GM, which has dominated the sport utility vehicle and truck
market for years but has steadily lost share to Asian
competitors in the car category, plans to launch its redesigned
2008 Malibu in early 2008. Industry analysts have said GM needs a strong entry in the
mid-size sedan market, where its largest brand, Chevrolet, has
lagged for years. GM, which lost $10.6 billion in 2005, is in
the middle of a broad turnaround that involves cutting jobs,
closing plants, reducing structural costs and increasing its
focus on cars and crossover vehicles. The Malibu, which will be unveiled at the North American
International Auto Show in Detroit later this month, will
compete with Toyota Motor Corp.'s (7203.T) Camry and Honda
Motor Co. Ltd. (7267.T) Accord. GM sold 100,000 to 125,000 current-model Malibus in the
past year, less than a third of the Camry's total annual
sales. The Malibu sold for an average of $17,939 in December,
after an average cash rebate of $2,438, according to data
collected from dealers by the Power Information Network. In the
same period, the Accord sold for an average of $22,402 while
the Camry averaged $23,441 -- both without cash rebates. But analysts say the new Malibu is much better than the
current version, with a  sleeker outer appearance and better
quality interiors. GM said the redesigned car will compete with the Camry on
fuel economy and price. The Camry starts at $18,720. The new Malibu will be quieter inside and have new standard
safety equipment such as side curtain airbags and stability
control, GM said. GM will launch a number of redesigned vehicles this year,
including the Cadillac CTS and the new GMC Acadia, Saturn
Outlook and Buick Enclave crossovers.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/gm-malibu-idUSN0248990120070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>gm unveils details on 2008 malibu</title></story></items>