<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:27 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates prices, adds detail and quote, chnages byline) By Nick OlivariNEW YORK Jan 2 (Reuters) - The dollar declined across the
board on Tuesday, while the euro rallied as investors began
the new year hunting currencies with rising yields. The dollar's losses were most pronounced against European
currencies such as the euro, sterling and the Swedish crown,
where central banks are seen as likely to keep raising interest
rates in 2007, narrowing the gap with U.S. interest rates. Liquidity was significantly thinned on Tuesday by a market
holiday in Japan and closure of the U.S. stock market to
commemorate the death of former President Gerald Ford. Currency
trading also wound down early in the United States, analysts
said. "At this juncture of the new year, it's a yield story,"
said Ron Simpson, director of currency research at Action
Economics in Tampa, Florida. But "there was very little
indication overnight of significant flows and people are just
jockeying for position." The euro EUR= was up 0.6 percent at $1.3274 late
afternoon in New York, adding to an 11.5 percent gain against
the dollar in 2006, its best performance in three years. The euro also rose to yet another record peak against the
Japanese yen EURJPY=, rising as high as 157.90 yen, according
to EBS, an electronic trading platform. It also rose to a near
seven-year high of 1.6121 Swiss francs EURCHF=, according to
Reuters data. "The Swiss franc and the yen are still fairly weak versus
the euro, indicating that risk appetite in the market is high
and carry trades are very much in vogue," said Michael
Klawitter, currency strategist at Dresdner Kleinwort in
Frankfurt. Indicating the continued popularity of carry trades, in
which investors sell low-yielding currencies for high yielders,
the Australian dollar hit nine-year highs above 94.50 yen
AUDJPY=R. The dollar was down 0.2 percent at 118.85 yen JPY=. Japan's Yomiuri newspaper reported on Tuesday that the Bank
of Japan would consider raising rates at its policy meeting on
Jan. 17-18, but added a hike might be delayed depending on
"adjustments" between the BOJ and the nation's ruling parties. Meanwhile, financial markets are pricing in at least one
rate cut for the United States in 2007, although surprising
strength in some recent data has pushed out the expected timing
of such a move. "Another few rounds of decent data and Treasury yields will
price out a rate cut and that will be good for the dollar,"
said Action's Simpson. The minutes of the Federal Reserve's December policy
meeting may help shed some light on the outlook for rates. The
minutes had been due to be released on Tuesday but the release
was pushed back to Wednesday due to the national holiday. The Institute for Supply Management's reading on the U.S.
manufacturing sector is also due on Wednesday, while Friday
brings the closely watched nonfarm payrolls report for
December. A reading below 50 in the manufacturing ISM index -- which
dipped below the boom-or-bust level for the first time in three
and a half years in November -- would likely reinforce concerns
about an economic slowdown, hurting the dollar further,
analysts said. "This week's ISM reports on manufacturing and services will
be crucial in determining the euro's momentum towards last
year's 1.3367 highs," said Ashraf Laidi, chief FX analyst at
CMC Markets in New York. (Additional reporting by Toni Vorobyova in London)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-forex-idUSN0234618920070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - dollar starts new year on a weak note</title></story></items>