<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:27 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds details, Dec sales of other auto makers, analysts,
shares) By Cheon Jong-wooSEOUL Jan 2 (Reuters) - Top South Korean auto maker
Hyundai Motor Co. (005380.KS) said on Tuesday it expected
global revenue growth to more than double in 2007, boosted by
higher sales abroad and increase in sales of high-end models. The world's No. 6 carmaker, also announcing a small fall in
December 2006 car sales volume, said it expected revenue to
jump by 13.5 percent to 42 trillion won ($45 billion) after it
rose 5.7 percent in 2006. Hyundai envisages a brighter year in 2007 after it saw
profits last year squeezed by losses from labour unrest and
stronger won currency KRW=. Growth in overall sales at Hyundai is expected to
accelerate this year, fuelled by healthy overseas sales of
premium cars recently launched including the Santa Fe sport
utility vehicle (SUV), analysts said. "Hyundai is expected to accomplish the target as
productions at home and abroad will be able to meet demand
abroad," said Yong Dae-in, an auto analyst at Goodmorning
Shinhan Securities. Hyundai Motor's global sales rose to 37 trillion won in
2006 from 35 trillion in 2005, a Hyundai official said. The 2007 revenue forecast includes sales at Hyundai's
overseas units. Sales from its South Korean based production
units only are expected to rise 7.3 percent this year to about
31 trillion won, according to analysts polled by Reuters
Estimates. But some analysts said Hyundai's sales target was too
aggressive as local sales were seen under pressure amid
sluggish domestic demand in Asia's third-largest economy and
lack of new models. "There is no room for Hyundai's sales to increase as
Hyundai does not have a specific new model to boost sales and
as consumer sentiment is still weak," said Choi Dae-sik, an
analyst at CJ Investment Securities. Hyundai aims to sell 2.735 million vehicles in 2007, up 9.4
percent from 2.501 million sold last year. "We will meet the target by growth in overseas sales as we
plan to ship the Veracruz SUV to the U.S. in March and to
launch the 'FD' in May," Jake Jang, a Hyundai spokesman said,
referring a compact model for the European market. "We also aim to increase sales at home with aggressive
marketing although domestic consumption has not revived yet,"
he added. In December 2006, Hyundai sold 247,254 vehicles, 1.5
percent lower than a year ago when South Korea's customers
rushed to show rooms for new cars before a tax benefit expired. But South Korea's five auto makers reported a 4.5 percent
rise in sales volume last month, helped by higher exports. Hyundai's affiliate Kia Motors Corp. (000270.KS), the
country's No. 2 auto maker, said it aimed to sell 1.54 million
vehicles in 2007, up 22.1 percent from 2006. It targets 22
trillion won in revenue, up 15.8 percent. Neither company provided profit forecasts and officials
from the auto makers declined to comment on profits. Hyundai Motor group, which includes affiliates such as
Hyundai Steel Co. (004020.KS) and parts maker Hyundai Mobis Co.
(012330.KS), aims to increase its group-wide sales by 14
percent to 106 trillion won, with exports of $40.1 billion. Shares in Hyundai rose 0.15 percent to 67,500 won compared
with a 0.06 percent gain in the broader market .KS11. Kia was
up 0.4 percent up at 13,500 won. Hit by weaker profits, shares in Hyundai fell 30.7 percent
in all of 2006, lagging the wider market's .KS11 4 percent
gain. Kia shares dropped 49.3 percent last year. The breakdown of carmakers' sales in December:              Dec 06   Nov 06 vs Dec 05   Dec   vs yr-ago              sales           (% change)  exports  (%
change)
 Hyundai         247,254  259,453    -1.5    187,078     +1.9
 Kia             136,653  140,097    +6.6    108,798     +7.5
 GM Daewoo       140,619  150,742   +12.7    125,470     +9.8
 Renault Samsung  17,429   13,442   +29.7      6,344 +4,215.6
 Ssangyong Motor  13,489   11,169   -12.9      6,955    +17.0
 ($1=929.5 Won)
 (Additional reporting by Rhee So-eui and Jang Se-ra)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/hyundaimotor-sales-idUSSEO13117220070102</link><sectors><value><value>Markets</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - hyundai targets 2007 revenue growth spurt</title></story></items>