<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:27 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> By Cameron French TORONTO, Jan 2 The Canadian dollar rose
slightly against the greenback on Tuesday, but fell versus
overseas currencies, as the market's "sell North America"
mantra extended into the new year. Domestic bond prices rose modestly, rebounding somewhat
from last week's sharp fall. The currency finished at C$1.1636 to the U.S. dollar, or
85.94 U.S. cents, up from C$1.1654 to the U.S. dollar, or 85.81
U.S. cents, at Friday's close. Canadian markets were closed on
Monday for the New Year holiday. Fears of a steep U.S. slowdown have pressured both the
Canadian and U.S. dollars, as any U.S. woes would translate
into weaker demand for Canadian exports and for commodities,
whose prices generally support the Canadian currency. "It seems that the U.S.-negative sentiment that prevailed
since late November is carrying through to the beginning of
2007," said Matthew Strauss, senior currency strategist at RBC
Capital Markets. The Canadian dollar stayed just above nine-month lows hit
last week against the greenback, but volumes were thin as U.S.
markets were closed and bond market trading shortened for a day
of mourning to honor former U.S. President Gerald Ford. "We're not seeing normal liquidity yet," said Strauss. Versus overseas currencies, the Canadian dollar's move was
more pronounced, as yield-seeking investors continued to warm
to the prospects of higher interest rates in Europe. The currency touched a 19-month low against the euro and
pound, and a two-week low against the Swiss franc. Bank of Canada interest rates are expected to be cut later
this year, although analysts are split on the timing and will
continue to focus on major pieces of economic data, such as
Friday's release of December jobs data. The central bank next sets policy on Jan. 16, but is
expected to leave its overnight rate unchanged at 4.25 percent
at that time. BONDS RISE Domestic bonds prices rose alongside U.S. treasuries,
rebounding slightly from the market's steep losses last week. Liquidity was thin with the U.S. bond market closing early
and with many traders still not back from holidays. Along with jobs data, the market will welcome November
producer and raw materials prices, as well as the December Ivey
Purchasing Managers index this week. The the two-year bond climbed 5 Canadian cents to C$100.46
to yield 3.999 percent, while the 10-year bond rose 16 Canadian
cents to C$99.51 to yield 4.063 percent. The yield spread between the two-year and 10-year bond
moved to 6.4 basis points from 5.7 at the previous close. The 30-year bond rose 43 Canadian cents to C$126.15 to
yield 4.116 percent. In the United States, the 30-year treasury
yielded 4.790 percent. The three-month when-issued T-bill yielded 4.15 percent,
unchanged the previous close.
































</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-canada-dollar-bonds-idUSN0234681220070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>canadian dollar rises versus us $, bonds climb</title></story></items>