<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:16 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds comments by Connecticut attorney general)NEW YORK Jan 2 (Reuters) - St. Paul Travelers Cos. Inc.
STA.N will stop paying contingent commissions to insurance
agents and brokers by the start of 2008, according to a
statement by Connecticut Attorney General Richard Blumenthal on
Tuesday. Blumenthal said that St. Paul, one of the largest property
casualty insurers, had said in a letter to his office that it
would comply with a settlement reached last year with
Connecticut, Illinois and New York to ban the practice for
certain coverages. A spokeswoman for St. Paul could not be reached for comment
immediately. Contingent commissions are monies given by insurers to
agents who steer large amounts of business to those insurers.
But they also represent a conflict of interest, regulators say,
because brokers are supposed to be working for the client
company, not the insurer. Blumenthal said St. Paul told him in its letter that it
would provide a fixed-commission option for all agents on all
lines of business and encourage brokers to accept that in lieu
of contingent commissions in 2007. St. Paul will have all of
its agents on a fixed-commission schedule by 2008, the attorney
general said. "St. Paul Travelers is doing the right thing, voluntarily
agreeing to stop paying contingent commissions," said
Blumenthal. "Insurance carriers do not need to pay contingent
compensation to profitably compete in the insurance industry." Blumenthal said he expected contingent commission bans to
be "contagious" in the industry, eventually ending a
"pay-to-play culture." Major insurance brokers including Marsh &amp; McLennan Cos.
Inc. (MMC.N), Aon Corp. AOC.N and Willis Group Holdings Ltd.
(WSH.N) have eliminated contingent commissions, but smaller
insurance brokers continue to take them. Regulators such as former New York Attorney General Eliot
Spitzer have gone after insurers, trying to get them to stop
paying these commissions to brokers. Last week Chubb Corp. (CB.N), another major property
casualty insurer, paid $17 million to settle allegations from
attorneys general in three states that it paid secret
commissions to win business. Chubb said it will reform its
practices to keep it from happening again.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/stpaultravelers-commissions-idUSN0228086820070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - st . paul to stop paying contingent commissions</title></story></items>