<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:32 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds layoffs, company and analyst comments) By Jonathan StempelNEW YORK Jan 2 (Reuters) - Mortgage Lenders Network USA, a
large U.S. subprime lender, said it has stopped funding loans
and accepting applications for loans, citing deteriorating
conditions in the mortgage market, and has temporarily laid off
about 80 percent of its 1,800 employees. Privately held Mortgage Lenders also said it is in
"strategic negotiations" with several Wall Street firms
regarding its loan operations. Roughly four-fifths, or about 1,440, of the Middletown,
Connecticut-based firm's employees are on "temporary furlough,"
spokesman James Pedrick said in an interview. Mortgage Lenders said it has five regional lending offices
and employs about 950 people in its home state. The retrenchment is the latest sign of stress among
subprime lenders, which make higher-cost loans to people with
weaker credit histories. It comes less than a week after similar-sized rival Ownit
Mortgage Solutions Inc. filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy
protection. Mortgage Lenders disclosed the changes on its Web site, in
phone recordings at several offices, and in a statement. Rising interest rates and home prices have led to growing
competition for a shrinking pool of borrowers, and defaults are
rising as the economy slows and rates reset higher. Meanwhile, some lenders have been pinched by being forced
to buy back loans they sold because of rising delinquencies,
and as "warehouse" lenders pull credit lines, analysts said. Unlike most subprime rivals, Mortgage Lenders increased its
lending throughout 2006. It made $3.31 billion of subprime
loans in the third quarter, ranking 15th nationwide, according
to data from National Mortgage News. The firm, however, said wholesale market conditions have
"deteriorated dramatically" in the last two months. Chief Executive Mitchell Heffernan said wholesale broker
originations will stop until credit quality and margins return
to "acceptable levels." The firm said it plans to maintain its
$17.8 billion servicing portfolio. Heffernan had said on Dec. 8 that the firm viewed 2007 as a
year of growth, including plans to build new headquarters in
Wallingford, Connecticut. INDUSTRY STRUGGLES Mortgage Lenders' third-quarter loan volume tripled from a
year earlier though industrywide lending fell 9 percent. Among
larger subprime lenders, only Wells Fargo &amp; Co. (WFC.N) and
Citigroup Inc. (C.N) boosted loan volumes. David Olson, president of Wholesale Access, which tracks
the mortgage industry, said Mortgage Lenders' retrenchment was
unsurprising in light of subprime lenders' struggles. "Profits are way down, and margins are razor-thin or even
negative," he said. Pedrick said Mortgage Lenders' warehouse lines of credit
"have not been pulled and not been shut down." Last Thursday, 16th-ranked Ownit, based in Agoura Hills,
California, listed in its bankruptcy filing more than $170
million of debt, including $93 million owed to Merrill Lynch &amp;
Co. MER.N. Sebring Capital Partners, a Texas-based subprime lender,
ceased operations on Dec. 1, according to its Web site. Several Wall Street firms have made mortgage acquisitions
in the last year, including Merrill Lynch and Morgan Stanley
(MS.N) last month.






</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/mortgagelendersnetwork-idUSN0234272120070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - mortgage lenders network stops loans , sets layoffs</title></story></items>