<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>20:22 30 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text>LOS ANGELES Tiger Woods had double cause to 
celebrate on Saturday when he announced on his 31st birthday 
that his wife Elin will give birth to their first child next 
year. "We are expecting our first child this summer," the 
American world number one said on his official Web site. "Obviously, we couldn't be happier and our families are 
thrilled. I have always wanted to be a dad. I just wish my 
father could be around to share the experience." Woods's father Earl died in early May this year after a 
long battle with cancer. His son took a nine-week break from golf to deal with his 
father's illness and subsequent death before ending the 2006 
PGA Tour with eight victories, including two majors. Despite his remarkable golfing form in a season he rates as 
his best ever, Woods described the year overall as one of loss. "Certainly (this was) the most difficult season I've ever 
had," he said before winning the Target World Challenge in 
California earlier this month, his final tournament of the 
year. "You don't ever want to lose a parent, your father, your 
mentor, your best friend. "When that day happens ... you think you can handle it and 
all of a sudden it happens and you find out it affects you much 
deeper than you thought previously." Woods, who married Swede Elin Nordegren in October 2004, 
has frequently spoken about becoming a father for the first 
time. He has decided to skip next week's season-opening Mercedes 
Championship in Hawaii to spend more time with his family. The 12-times major winner will launch his 2007 PGA Tour 
campaign with his title defense at the Buick Invitational 
outside San Diego from January 25-28.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/people-golf-tiger-dc-idUSSP14931120070102</link><sectors><value><value>Sports, </value><value>People</value></value></sectors><title>birthday boy tiger to become father next year</title></story></items>