<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:54 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK The number of U.S. securities fraud 
class-action lawsuits dropped last year, a study released on 
Tuesday found, even as investors pursued a new avenue of 
litigation involving the timing of stock options grants at big 
companies. Federal securities fraud class actions plunged 38 percent 
to 110 last year based on filings through December 11, compared 
with 178 lawsuits in 2005 and as many as 267 in 2002, according 
to a study by Stanford Law School and Cornerstone Research, a 
research firm for litigators. Filings are at the lowest level since Congress passed a 
major class-action reform law in 1995, the study said. The declines come even as a new area emerged for investor 
lawsuits -- fraud cases related to options awarded to top 
corporate executives. Twenty options-related lawsuits were 
filed in 2006 against companies such as Apple Computer Inc. 
(AAPL.O), UnitedHealth Group Inc. (UNH.N) and Juniper Networks JNPR.O. There is no single reason for the overall drop, but 
increased corporate enforcement activity by the U.S. Securities 
and Exchange Commission and the Justice Department is a likely 
explanation, said Stanford law professor Joseph Grundfest. "One explanation is that there is simply less fraud in the 
market," he said. The stock market also has been strong 
recently, though "it will take us several years to figure out 
whether that is really the cause of the decline," he added. The report comes as class-action lawyers are under heavy 
fire from business interest groups and politicians who argue 
that shareholder litigation is growing out of control. Class-action lawyers have been dealt some big blows, 
including a December ruling by a federal appeals court that 
said 12 securities firms will not have to face a class-action 
suit accusing them of manipulating the pricing of initial 
public offerings in the late 1990s. The report released on Tuesday found that when class-action 
suits are filed, the dollar amounts at stake are often smaller 
than they were in prior years. Alleged investor losses, 
measured by stock market declines at the time the fraud 
allegations were disclosed, fell 44 percent to $52 billion in 
2006, from $93 billion in 2005. Proponents of class-action reform say the report shows no 
evidence that the trends are here to stay. In a statement, the U.S. Chamber of Commerce said that 
"although we applaud the decrease in filings, there is still a 
long way to go to fix a broken securities litigation system, in 
which shareholders basically end up suing themselves with the 
lawyers raking huge sums off the top." Separately on Tuesday, a survey of large U.S. companies 
from BTI Consulting Group found that these businesses spent 
$56.4 billion on outside counsel last year, up 19.6 percent 
from 2005. The Chamber of Commerce said the fall-off in lawsuits can 
partially be attributed to the travails of once dominant 
class-action litigation firm Milberg Weiss Bershad &amp; Schulman 
LLP, which was indicted in May on criminal charges that it paid 
kickbacks to plaintiffs. Milberg, which has denied the charges, filed 73 fewer cases 
in 2006 than in 2005, according to the Chamber of Commerce. But the study from Stanford and Cornerstone said the 
Milberg indictment probably had no big impact on the overall 
decline in class-action lawsuits. "There is no shortage of plaintiffs' lawyers in the United 
States and there are no barriers to entry," Grundfest said. 
"All of the lawyers that know how to file these cases are still 
in business." While the number of new class actions is declining, another 
report released on Tuesday showed that the size of settlements 
of existing cases is getting bigger. The report from NERA 
Economic Consulting said that the average shareholder 
class-action settlement rose to $86.7 million last year, up 
from $73.6 million in 2005.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-law-classactions-dc-idUSN0234826920070102</link><sectors><value><value>Regulatory News, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>u . s . securities class - actions down sharply : study</title></story></items>