<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:34 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK A healthy economy will fuel growth in 
the U.S. office market in 2007, although the outlook for 
commercial real estate markets exposed to the weak housing 
market isn't as bright, according to a new report. This year, businesses will add staff and lease more space, 
helped by an economy that will strike a balance between 
recession and inflationary expansion, according to the 2007 
Global Real Estate Forecast from real estate company Grubb &amp; 
Ellis Co. GBE.N. About 300,000 of the year's expected new jobs will be 
located in office buildings, the report said. Rental rates for the most prestigious buildings should rise 
by 5 percent or more in 20 central business districts including 
those in Washington, D.C. and Los Angeles -- expected to be the 
two top U.S. office markets through 2011, the report predicted. "The future of the office market looks bright," said Grubb 
&amp; Ellis vice president Robert Bach in a statement. "Business 
capital spending and the expanding global economy will power 
demand for space even if the U.S. economy remains sluggish in 
the first half of 2007 as expected." In the industrial market, however, demand for space is 
expected to fall 17.6 percent from a year ago to 140 million 
square feet. If the weak housing market constrained consumer 
spending and puts pressure on retailers, demand for retail 
distribution centers could drop, possibly handicapping the 
industrial market further, the report said. Construction companies shrinking in response to the housing 
downturn could also result in a decreased demand for industrial 
space. Yet demand for industrial space remains high in popular 
markets such as Los Angeles County, named the nation's No. 1 
industrial market in the report. Los Angeles has the lowest 
industrial vacancy rate in the country, and Grubb &amp; Ellis 
projects double-digit rent growth there in 2007. Washington, D.C.'s fast-growing median income puts it at 
the top of the report's list of retail markets as well. Overall, however, the retail market is expected to 
experience a slight drop in construction this year, the report 
said. Until home construction and sales improve, retail 
development in new neighborhoods could slow, the report said. On the other hand, the housing downturn should boost the 
market for apartments and cause apartment rental rates to rise 
modestly, according to the report.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-grubbellis-report-dc-idUSN0233196220070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>office rents to rise on healthy economy : report</title></story></items>