<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:14 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts, adds details on production, background)CHICAGO Jan 2 (Reuters) - Goodyear Tire &amp; Rubber Co.
GT.N said on Tuesday it expects to ramp up production over
the next few weeks at facilities in the U.S. and Canada after a
United Steelworkers strike that lasted nearly three months. Goodyear and the United Steelworkers union reached
agreements on Dec. 22 covering about 15,000 hourly workers who
had been on strike since Oct. 5. Union members ratified the
deals last week and workers began returning to the plants on
Tuesday. A full supply of tires and engineered products is expected
to be available soon thereafter, Goodyear said. "I have no doubt our associates will quickly return to
their normal high levels of performance and productivity," said
Jon Rich, president of Goodyear's North American Tire unit. Following the workers return, Standard &amp; Poor's Rating
Services affirmed its 'B+' rating on Goodyear's corporate
credit and removed the company's debt from negative
CreditWatch. Plant security and preservation of retiree health care
coverage were key issues for the steelworkers, while Akron,
Ohio-based Goodyear had said it needed to cut costs and
capacity in North America to compete with low-cost imports. Goodyear, one of the world's largest tire makers, expects
to save up to $610 million in costs over the three-year master
agreement that covers 12 tire and engineered products plants in
the United States. The Canadian facilities are covered by a
separate agreement. The agreement delays Goodyear's planned closing of a Tyler,
Texas, plant by several months to at least the end of 2007, and
establishes a trust fund to resolve Goodyear's retiree health
care liabilities for steelworker union members in the U.S. Goodyear agreed to contribute $1 billion to establish the
trust, which requires court and regulatory approvals, including
at least $700 million cash and the balance in common stock. The agreement also allows Goodyear to pay lower wages and
benefits to new hires, while requiring certain capital
investment for North American plants and some profit-sharing.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/goodyear-idUSN0234867020070102</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - goodyear begins to ramp up production after strike</title></story></items>