<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:21 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>UNITED NATIONS U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-Moon started his first day on the job on Tuesday by promising immediate attention to the crisis in Darfur but backing off traditional U.N. opposition to capital punishment.Ban, a former South Korean foreign minister succeeding Kofi Annan of Ghana, was greeted by a U.N. honor guard and then went to a U.N. meditation chapel to honor fallen peacekeepers.Asked about the weekend execution of Saddam Hussein, Ban, 62, told reporters the former Iraqi leader was responsible "for committing heinous crimes and unspeakable atrocities against the Iraqi people and we should never forget the victims of these crimes."But he said, "The issue of capital punishment is for each and every member state to decide" in conformity with international law. South Korea has the death penalty although it is considering abolishing it.However, his special representative in Iraq, Ashraf Qazi, released a statement saying that the world body "remains opposed to capital punishment, even in the case of war crimes, crimes against humanity and genocide."Ban said the crisis in Sudan's Darfur region was "very high on my agenda" and he would meet with his special envoy Jan Eliasson of Sweden on Wednesday morning and had already spoken by telephone with him.He also announced he would attend an African Union summit at the end of January in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, and talk to Sudan's President Omar Hassan al-Bashir there."By engaging myself in the diplomatic process I hope that we will be able to resolve peacefully as soon as possible on these serious issues," Ban said.The United Nations is seeking to get a peacekeeping force in Sudan's western arid Darfur region, where violence has escalated, rapes have multiplied and more than 2.5 million people have lost their homes. Bashir has put conditions on a U.N. peacekeeping force to bolster the under-financed 7,000 African Union troops, now in Darfur.NORTH KOREA,On North Korea, Ban said it was a priority on his agenda, especially since he had been deeply involved in diplomacy on Pyongyang's nuclear ambitions as South Korea's foreign minister.But Ban was mindful of the daunting challenges and the limitations of the United Nations as well as his job."Not a single person, including the secretary-general of the United Nations, not a single country, however strong, powerful, resourceful, cannot address (these issues)," he said. We need to have some common effort."Ban also pledged to encourage senior staff members to talk to the media as well as member states."In a closed meeting with U.N. staff members, he said the bureaucracy had come under harsh and sometimes unfair criticism, according to his speaking notes."Not all the criticisms are justified but some of them warrant our urgent attention, and we must take bold steps to dispel them," he said, referring to Annan's unsuccessful effort to get U.N. General Assembly approval for management reforms.In turn, Stephen Kisambira, president of the U.N. staff union, said "a fundamental change in the mindset of senior management is required, from a relationship based on dominance, disregard and fear, to a real partnership," according to a text of his speech.Ban's spokeswoman, Michele Montas, said Annan, before leaving New York for Europe on Monday, visited Ban at his hotel, and the White House said Annan also telephoned President George W. Bush to say good-bye.So far Ban has only announced his chief of staff, Indian Vijay Nambiar, who was a special adviser to Annan, and the appointment of Montas, an award-winning Haitian broadcaster, also a current U.N. staff member.But France is expected to have its candidate head peacekeeping, U.N. sources said, with the United States and Britain lobbying for their nationals to oversee the political affairs department. A Briton may be given the humanitarian affairs job, they said.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-un-leader-idUSN0232801820070102</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>new u . n . chief pledges attention to darfur , n korea</title></story></items>