<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:21 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>BUENOS AIRES Jan 2 Argentine stocks started
the new year with a fresh record on Tuesday in light trade that
was driven by gains in energy shares, traders said. The MerVal index .MERV of the 15 leading stocks closed up
2.32 percent at 2,139.14 points -- pipping the previous record
close on Thursday. Trade volume was a light 51.1 million pesos ($16.6
million), compared with Thursday's 77.6 million pesos. "We've got a new MerVal record due to Petrobras
Participaciones and TGS, which were the motor of the
bullishness," said Jorge Alberti of online brokerage
Elaccionista.com, adding that the gains were based on the
strong performance of American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) in
the United States on Friday. Argentina's stock market was closed on Friday ahead of the
New Year holiday, but the U.S.-listed shares of local firms
made gains on Friday in the United States. Petrobras Energia Participaciones PCH.BA, the local unit
of Brazil's state-run energy company Petrobras, ended the
session up 5.41 percent to 3.7 pesos per share, while natural
gas carrier TGS (TGS2.BA) saw its stock climb 9.07 percent to
4.57 pesos per share. Traders said the day's business was thin because U.S.
markets were closed for a national day of mourning for former
President Gerald Ford. "We've got a market that's open in terms of prices, but not
in relation to volume, so it's basically been replicating the
closes of the ADRs on Friday," said Francisco Marra, a trader
at Bull Market Brokers. In the foreign exchange market, the peso firmed by 0.08
percent against the dollar in trade between foreign exchange
houses ARSB= to close at 3.085/3.0875 per U.S. dollar. In interbank trade, where the central bank intervenes, the
peso ended at 3.055/3.0575 against the dollar ARS=RASL.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-argentina-idUSN0234241520070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>argentine stocks start year with new record high</title></story></items>