<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:36 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON President Bush, former presidents and Washington veterans remembered Gerald Ford on Tuesday as a "rock of stability" whose pardon of scandal-tarred Richard Nixon helped heal a divided country.Cabinet secretaries, Supreme Court justices and military leaders joined Ford's widow, Betty, 88, inside Washington's cavernous National Cathedral to honor the memory of Ford, the 38th president who died a week ago.Bush, speaking with Ford's flag-draped casket lying before him, said Ford's decision to pardon Nixon in 1974 after replacing him in the White House probably cost him the presidency.The pardon is now seen by many historians as essential to having ended America's greatest political crisis that had divided the country. But at the time, Ford was assailed for it and lost the 1976 election to Democrat Jimmy Carter.Carter, now 82, attended the memorial service along with the remaining former presidents, Bill Clinton, 60, and Bush's father, George H.W. Bush, 82."President Ford's time in office was brief, but history will long remember the courage and common sense that helped restore trust in the workings of our democracy," Bush said.Or as his father put it: "Jerry Ford's decency was the ideal remedy for the deception of Watergate," the scandal that drove Nixon to resign the presidency.With the Iraq war looming as a source of Washington combat in 2007, a political truce was in effect for a national day of mourning for Ford, whose body later was flown to Grand Rapids, Michigan, for burial.CRITICISM OF THE IRAQ WARIn the Washington audience were many critics of Bush's Iraq policy. Seated near Bush in the front pew was Carter, a frequent critic. Honorary pallbearers included Brent Scowcroft, who was former President Bush's national security adviser and cautioned him against sending U.S. troops into Baghdad in the first Gulf War in 1991.Nearby was former Secretary of State James Baker, whose Iraq Study Group report offering Bush recommendations for changing course in Iraq seems to have largely been ignored by Bush as he considers a change in policy to be announced soon.Elsewhere were former Secretary of State Colin Powell, who has been critical of Iraq, as well as former Vice President Al Gore.Even Ford himself had managed to get some criticism of the Iraq war on the record from beyond the grave, telling The Washington Post's Bob Woodward that "I don't think I would have gone to war." The 2004 and 2005 interviews were not published until after Ford's death.Bush, who sees himself as having a bit of Harry Truman's feistiness and firmness despite low public support, said Ford took office "because America needed him, not because he wanted the office," at a time of economic inflation and political turmoil and the end of the Vietnam War."Amid all the turmoil, Gerald Ford was a rock of stability," Bush said.Speakers, including former Secretary of State Henry Kissinger and former NBC television anchor Tom Brokaw, praised Ford for bringing small-town American values to the White House.Brokaw said Ford stood in deep contrast to other politicians, without mentioning Nixon or others by name."Gerald Ford brought to the political arena no demons, no hidden agenda, no hit list or acts of vengeance. He knew who he was, and he didn't require consultants or gurus to change him," he said.Kissinger said Ford deserved credit for helping end the Cold War. Former President Bush recalled Ford's foibles on the golf course:"'I know I'm playing better golf,'" President Ford once reported to friends, 'because I'm hitting fewer spectators.'"</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-ford-funeral-idUSN0233068120070102</link><sectors><value><value>Politics</value></value></sectors><title>ex - u . s . president ford called rock of stability</title></story></items>