<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>20:18 29 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON AT&amp;T Inc. closed its $86 billion 
purchase of BellSouth Corp. on Friday after getting final 
regulatory approval, in a deal that will widen its lead in U.S. 
phone and Internet services. The U.S. Federal Communications Commission voted 4-0 to 
approve the deal after AT&amp;T promised to maintain "network 
neutrality" of its high-speed Internet platform for two years, 
meaning it will not charge certain Web media providers more to 
carry data-heavy Internet content such as video. It was one of several key concessions that the top U.S. 
phone provider pledged late on Thursday to quiet concerns that 
the takeover would stifle competition. Some investors had begun 
to expect a delay into 2007 as talks with the FCC dragged on. The San Antonio, Texas-based company also reaffirmed 
forecasts it gave when the merger was announced in March, 
saying it expected total cost savings of $18 billion from the 
deal, with $2 billion of that coming in 2008. Shares in AT&amp;T rose 28 cents, or 0.7 percent, to $36.03 in 
after-hours trading. Since hitting a trough in mid-May, AT&amp;T 
shares have climbed more than 40 percent and closed at $35.75 
on the New York Stock Exchange on Friday. AT&amp;T, which dates back more than 125 years to the invention 
of the telephone, has been trying to bolster its bottom line 
through acquisitions and expand into the television business as 
profits from traditional phone service have waned. The company was formed in 2005 when local phone carrier SBC 
Communications Inc. acquired AT&amp;T and kept that name. Now four of the seven companies that were spun off from the 
original AT&amp;T in 1984 are back under one roof, and it includes 
66.1 million telephone lines, 58.7 million Cingular Wireless 
customers and 11.6 million high-speed Internet customers. That clout is viewed as key to profitability in a 
consolidating telecoms industry, as everyone from cable 
operators to Internet phone companies offer combined voice, 
video and Web services. AT&amp;T's concession on net neutrality was of particular note 
because it had strenuously objected to any restriction on how 
it charged for services. The provision was praised by the FCC's two Democratic 
commissioners and criticized by Chairman Kevin Martin and 
Commissioner Deborah Taylor Tate. "Today's order does not mean that the commission has 
adopted an additional net neutrality principle," the two 
Republicans said in a joint statement. "We continue to believe such a requirement is not necessary 
and may impede infrastructure deployment," they said. "Thus, 
although AT&amp;T may make a voluntary business decision, it cannot 
dictate or bind government policy."
 CONCESSIONS ON INTERNET, WHOLESALE RATES A new legislative push to require net neutrality is 
expected in 2007 from Rep. Edward Markey, the top Democrat on 
the House subcommittee on telecommunications. In a statement, 
Markey said the AT&amp;T concession would be an "important 
keystone" for future legislation. To win FCC approval, AT&amp;T agreed to offer Internet access 
for $10 a month and broadband for $19.95 per month. It also 
agreed to freeze prices and to price caps for some wholesale 
rates to give competitors access to its network for 48 months, 
longer than an initial offer of 30 months. Rivals had complained that the initial conditions would 
undermine competition, particularly for high-speed Internet 
service. They advocated restrictions lasting several years. By buying Atlanta, Georgia-based BellSouth, AT&amp;T gets a 
foothold in the southeastern United States. "Moving forward, AT&amp;T will work to integrate these services 
for customers in the southeast, across the country and around 
the world," said AT&amp;T Chief Executive Ed Whitacre, who will be 
chairman and CEO of the combined company. AT&amp;T's closest rival is Verizon Communications Inc. with 
almost 46 million access lines, 56.7 million wireless 
subscribers, and 6.6 million broadband customers. That company 
is also moving into the television business. Cable TV provider Comcast Corp. has about 11 million 
broadband subscribers and 2.1 million voice customers. AT&amp;T said it would repatriate 3,000 jobs outsourced by 
BellSouth, but did not give details or say how that would 
affect its expectation, announced in March, that the deal would 
result in 10,000 job cuts by 2009. (Additional reporting by Jeremy Pelofsky in Washington and 
Scott Hillis in San Francisco)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-bellsouth-fcc-dc-idUSWBT00636120070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>at &amp; t closes $ 86 billion bellsouth deal</title></story></items>