<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:26 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>Property prices in India are going through the roof as the economy blossoms and foreign companies and businessmen pour into the country. Here are some key facts on India's booming property market:Size:India's real estate market is currently estimated at $16 billion and is forecast to reach $60 billion by 2010.The real estate sector could attract a quarter of an estimated $8 billion in long-term foreign investment bound for India in 2006-2007, according to a study by industry lobby the Associated Chambers of Commerce and Industry of India (ASSOCHAM).Office property space:In the last two years the value of commercial office space has increased by 40 percent.It is expected that the demand for office spaces alone will grow to over 19 million square feet in 2006 to 2007. The outsourcing sector would account for approximately 75 percent of the demand and by 2010 would need 200 million square feet of office space in major metropolitan cities.Malls:The number of shopping malls in the major cities of Kolkata, Mumbai, Bangalore, New Delhi, Hyderabad and Pune is expected to grow to 300 by 2010 from the current 50. The total mall space currently available in these cities is around 12.4 million square feet.Foreign Investments:In 2005-06, the real estate sector tapped 16 percent of the $5.54 billion of foreign investment attracted to India, compared to 10.6 percent of the $3.75 billion foreign investment in India in 2004-05.Morgan Stanley's real estate investment arm has invested $68 million in Mantri Developers Private Ltd. which is based in Bangalore, while JP Morgan Chase's Principal Real Estate Investments has invested $60 million in a residential project in Mumbai with Lodha Builders.Hilton International Corp. plans to invest $143 million for a 26 percent stake in the joint venture company with domestic real estate firm DLF Universal Ltd for hotel and real estate activities.India's first property trust is due to be launched early next year when business park developer Embassy group spins off buildings in a Singapore IPO.Roadblocks:Investors betting on the sector have to bear the cumbersome bureaucracy. India has poor foreclosure laws and property registration processes are tedious. Property tax and document systems vary from state to state and the government does not allow foreign investors to own buildings that they don't occupy.Sources: Reuters; ASSOCHAM (/www.assocham.org)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-india-property-facts-idUSSP11643220070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>factbox : facts on india ' s booming property sector</title></story></items>