<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:27 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds details, quotes)TORONTO Jan 2 (Reuters) - Toronto stocks ended the first
session of 2007 with a modest gain on Tuesday, getting a lift
from the materials sector in holiday-quietened trade. The Toronto Stock Exchange S&amp;P/TSX composite index
.GSPTSE closed up 15.27 points, or 0.1 percent, at
12,923.66. All but one of the TSX's 10 main sectors were up, with the
resource-laden materials group leading the gainers with a 0.7
percent rise. The price of gold also rose on Tuesday, as the
euro gained against the U.S. dollar. The influential energy sector closed down 0.33 percent,
following oil's fall below $61 a barrel in thin trade, while
the financials group was unchanged for the day. "I think it's a decent start given that U.S. markets are
closed," said Elvis Picardo, chief market strategist at Global
Securities Corp. in Vancouver. U.S. stock and commodity markets remained shuttered to
observe a day of mourning for former President Gerald Ford. Although the main TSX index returned a 14.5 percent gain in
2006, investors should proceed into the new year with caution,
said Picardo. "The point is that investors are usually bullish at the
start of the year, but that bullishness needs to be tempered
with some caution because it's going to be a fairly choppy
year," said Picardo. Shares of Barrick Gold Corp. (ABX.TO) rose 33 Canadian
cents, or 0.92 percent, to close at C$36.18, while fertilizer
company Agrium Inc. (AGU.TO) jumped C$1.37, or 3.75 percent, to
end at C$37.91. Despite the overall dip in the energy group, EnCana Corp.
(ECA.TO) rose 69 Canadian cents, or 1.3 percent, to close at
C$54.34, while Shell Canada Ltd. SHC.TO eked out a gain of 20
Canadian cents to close at C$43.70. In company news, Harris Steel Group Inc. HSG.TO saw a
boost after it said on Tuesday it had agreed to a C$1.25
billion ($1.07 billion) takeover by U.S. steelmaker Nucor Corp.
(NUE.N). Harris shares closed up C$2.55, or 5.9 percent, at
C$46.06. CoolBrands International Inc. COBa.TO said it has agreed
to sell its yogurt division for $45 million in cash, boosting
its shares 14 Canadian cents, or 10.9 percent, to C$1.43. "It always starts back slow coming back from vacation, and
today is another example of that -- light volumes, not a lot
direction," said Paul Hand, managing director at RBC Capital
Markets. "In general, a lackluster day. It will slowly build over
the week." Market volume was just 148 million shares worth C$2.1
billion. Decliners outpaced advancer 755 to 727. The blue chip
S&amp;P/TSX 60 index .TSE60 closed 1.38 points higher, or 0.2
percent, at 744.15. ($1=$1.16 Canadian)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-canada-stocks-idUSN0235164620070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>toronto stocks kick off new year with modest gain</title></story></items>