<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:15 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> TORONTO (Hollywood Reporter) - Canada's actors union and 
North American producers will return to the bargaining table 
Wednesday in a last-ditch attempt to forge a new labor deal and 
avert a planned industry shutdown next Monday. On Friday, representatives for ACTRA, which represents 
21,000 domestic performers, met informally with negotiators 
representing various producer groups, agreeing to resume talks 
Wednesday. ACTRA (the Alliance of Canadian Cinema Television and Radio 
Artists) also agreed to delay plans for industrial action to 
back its demands. The current Independent Production Agreement 
expired Sunday, and the performers union is now in a legal 
position to strike in much of the country for the first time. But Stephen Waddell, ACTRA's chief negotiator, said the 
actors union agreed to more talks after receiving assurances 
from producers that an increased-wage proposal was possible. "(It is) only on the basis that there had been some 
off-the-record discussions and that it appears the CFTPA 
(Canadian Film and Television Production Assn.) is willing to 
... put more money on the table, that we are agreeing to 
postpone the declaration of the strike," he said Friday. Waddell added that ACTRA will serve 72-hour strike notice 
Wednesday and will carry through on its threat Monday at 
midnight should no agreement on a new production agreement be 
reached in time. John Barrack, the CFTPA's chief negotiator, offered no 
details on the producers' latest bargaining strategy, but 
welcomed ACTRA's assurance that it will strike only if next 
week's crunch talks broke down. The most recent round of talks between ACTRA and the 
producers stalled after the performers rejected a proposed wage 
increase of 4% over three years, subject to certain deferrals. 
ACTRA is demanding a 15% wage increase over three years and 
new-media residuals, among other demands. Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/industry-canada-dc-idUSN0226952120070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>canada actors talking one more time before strike</title></story></items>