<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:55 01 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> LOS ANGELES (Hollywood Reporter) - One can imagine the 
pained expression on the face of Howard Morris, the creator of 
ABC's "In Case of Emergency," when CBS premiered "The Class" 
last fall. One of the fall's better sitcoms, "The Class" is about 
former classmates who reunite after not seeing each other for 
years. They've had varying degrees of success but never quite 
measured up to the promise of their school years. At the center 
of the group is a genuinely nice guy who's been dumped by his 
girl. Another classmate is on the verge of suicide. "Emergency" has enough similarities -- right down to the 
dumped guy and the near-suicide -- that it could be a response 
to the same classroom assignment. The similarity of the two 
premises makes comparison inevitable which is too bad because 
"Emergency," especially the pilot episode, is a solid sitcom 
with a strong cast and a lot of potential. There's room for improvement, of course. Jonathan 
Silverman, who plays jilted greeting card writer and all-around 
nice guy Harry Kennison, needs to take his performance down a 
notch or two. Also, there's no clear need for Dr. Joanna, the 
character played by Lori Loughlin. She catches the eye of Jason 
Ventress (David Arquette) after she patches him up following 
the suicide scene but the relationship is forced and awkward, a 
speed bump in an otherwise smooth and well-paced show. The others in the ensemble are Kelly Lee (Kelly Hu), the 
class valedictorian who ended up providing sensual Korean 
massages, and Sherman Yablonsky (Greg Germann), who shed his 
high school girth and became the author of a bestselling diet 
book. When Sherman's wife splits unexpectedly, the shock sends 
him back to binge eating. The show operates at a frantic pace -- sometimes too 
frantic -- but it has its funny moments as well. Hu is adept at 
physical comedy and "Ally McBeal" alumnus Germann makes his 
pathetic character oddly appealing. Morris mixes heart with 
humor and blends smart dialogue with visual gags so that you 
never have to wait long for the next laugh. You get the feeling 
that if this show is given enough time to find its strengths 
and understand its characters, it could be around for quite 
some time. Wednesday night has been in desperate need of comedy. At 
the start of the season, the only two broadcast sitcoms were 
NBC's "Twenty Good Years" and "30 Rock." The former is gone and 
the latter has been moved to Thursday. That should create an 
opportunity for ABC's duo of "The Knights of Prosperity" and 
"Emergency." Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/television-television-case-dc-idUSN2821845620070102</link><sectors><value><value>Television</value></value></sectors><title>make way for emergency on abc</title></story></items>