<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:06 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>DETROIT Jan 2 Japanese automaker Toyota Motor
Corp. (7203.T) will likely surge past Ford Motor Co. (F.N) to
the No. 2  spot in the U.S. auto market in December for the
third time in 2006, analysts said. Automakers release their December sales results on
Wednesday. Toyota, which is expected again to grow faster than all the
other automakers, passed Ford in U.S. sales for the first time
in July and again in November. Most analysts expect Ford sales to slip between 13 percent
and 17 percent in December. "The decrease is mostly a result of tough year end
competition coupled with a weak product cadence," Merrill Lynch
analyst John Murphy said in a note to investors on Friday.
Murphy estimates Ford will lose 1.2 percentage points of market
share in 2006. Calyon Securities analyst Joseph Amaturo said on Friday
that Ford's December sales would drop in part because it
stopped producing the Taurus sedan, once the top-selling car in
the United States. Also, truck sales will likely decline during the month,
hitting Ford hard because its F-Series trucks are the top-
selling vehicles in that segment, analysts said. General Motors Corp. (GM.N) sales are expected to be down
as much as 2 percent in December, while sales for
DaimlerChrysler AG's DCXGn.DE Chrysler unit are expected to
fall about 2 percent, according to analysts. "The reason for the softness we are seeing is that October
and November comps were so easy because of the pull-ahead
created by summer discounts," IRN Inc. analyst Erich Merkle
said last week. "But December last year started a recovery. Next year,
comps are going to get much more difficult. You are going to
see some pretty dramatic declines on a percentage basis." The combined monthly U.S. market share for Detroit's Big
Three is estimated to be 54.3 percent in December, down from
56.6 percent a year earlier and up slightly from 53.2 percent
last month, according to Edmunds.com, which tracks the
industry. New U.S vehicle sales for December are expected to be a
seasonally adjusted annual rate of between 16.5 million and
16.8 million vehicles, according to analysts. That would be
down from last December's 17.1 million vehicle rate and an
increase from the 16 million rate posted in November. Both GM and Ford have launched year-end incentives to boost
sales. Both programs, which run through Jan. 2, offer cash
incentives. Ford's program also includes interest-free
financing for up to 60 months on some 2006 vehicles. WINNERS OF '06 Toyota is the big winner in 2006 with sales up 12.5 percent
through November. Analysts expect the Japanese automaker to be
up about 12 percent in December. "Toyota should be the strongest foreign (automaker) in
December, as its year-over-year sales should benefit from its
popular, fuel-efficient small and mid-sized passenger cars as
well as its typical year-end sales event," Calyon's Amaturo
said. Asian automakers gained in 2006 because customers preferred
smaller SUVs and cars over larger gas-guzzling sport utility
vehicles, partly due to high gasoline prices. Toyota, Nissan Motor Co. Ltd.  (7201.T), Honda Motor Co.
Ltd. (7267.T) and Hyundai Motor Co. Ltd. 005380.K have a
strong car line-up. U.S. automakers, on the other hand, have
relied to a greater extent on the large SUVs.
  (Additional reporting by Jui Chakravorty)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/auto-sales-us-idUSN0233975820070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>toyota seen outpacing ford in u . s . december sales</title></story></items>