<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:57 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK New York Giants coach Tom Coughlin said on Tuesday his team belonged in the National Football League playoffs despite posting the worst record of the eight teams who have qualified for the Super Bowl tournament."I think everybody starts zero-zero. That's the way this is designed. The important thing is to get into the playoffs and we've accomplished that," Couglin told WFAN radio."We're apologizing to no one. We're here."The Giants, who began the season 6-2 before a series of injuries led to an unraveling, beat the Washington Redskins 34-28 in their regular season finale to reach the playoffs with an 8-8 record."That really was a playoff game for us," Coughlin said. "Win and you're in. Lose and you go home. And that serves us well right now."New York go to Philadelphia for Sunday's game against division rival Eagles, the hottest team in the National Football Conference (NFC) after winning their last five games with back-up quarterback Jeff Garcia in place of injured Donovan McNabb to finish at 10-6.The Giants split their home-and-home series against the Eagles, making a big comeback to win early in the season in Philadelphia and losing 36-22 to them at home last month."Obviously both teams know each other well. We played each other just a couple of weeks ago. There were things to be learned obviously from that game," the Giants coach said. "We did so many things to hurt ourselves."The Giants, who have lost possession receiver Amani Toomer, left tackle Luke Petitgout, defensive end Michael Strahan and linebacker LaVar Arrington for the season among others, were down a touchdown late against the Eagles before a tipped pass was intercepted and run in for a decisive touchdown.Coughlin said the play of the Eagles big offensive line was the key to their resurgence and number two offensive ranking."They are playing extremely well up front," he said."They are keeping people off the quarterback, they are running the ball very well and spreading the ball around in the passing game."</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-nfl-giants-idUSN0235416320070102</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>giants coach says mediocre record irrelevant in playoffs</title></story></items>