<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:16 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TAIPEI Jan 3 Global semiconductor revenues are
expected to grow 10.6 percent this year thanks to a healthier
market for electronic equipment and more stable chip prices, a
U.S. research firm said on Wednesday. This is good news for top memory chip makers like South
Korea's Samsung Electronics (005930.KS) and Hynix Semiconductor
(000660.KS) and contract chip makers such as Taiwan
Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. Ltd. (TSMC) (2330.TW) (TSM.N)
and United Microelectronics Corp. (UMC) (2303.TW) (UMC.N). Revenue will expand to US$285.8 billion in 2007, up 10.6
percent from 2006, representing a moderate rise for a
semiconductor business that has seen expansion growth as high
as 30-40 percent during its best years, according to iSuppli. Semiconductor revenue grew 9 percent in 2006, it said. "Factors contributing to the semiconductor market's more
moderate cycles include improved inventory practices, better
management of manufacturing capacity and greater flexibility in
memory production," iSuppli analyst Gary Grandbois said. While TSMC, UMC and other contract chip makers are
suffering from high inventories caused by slower than expected
demand for personal computers and some consumer products, the
foundry industry is widely expected to hit bottom early this
year. Chip makers are positioning themselves for the next wave of
growth by developing and making cutting-edge chips used in
new-generation electronics devices, such as mobile phones and
game consoles. Semiconductor demand from all major applications will rise
in 2007, with data processing, wired communications and
consumer electronics showing the strongest growth, the firm
said. Semiconductor revenue derived from the market for wired
communications gear will grow by 18.2 percent in 2007, faster
than the 9.9 percent growth in 2006. Revenue for
consumer-electronics oriented chips will grow by 14.4 percent
in 2007, compared with 10.3 percent in 2006, iSuppli said. However, iSuppli said growth would slow to 8.7 percent in
2008 and then bottom out at 3.7 percent in 2009, before
bouncing back to a 7.4 percent rise in 2010.
 (US$1=T$32.5)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/chips-forecast-idUSTP14067520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>global chip sales to rise 11 pct in 2007 - isuppli</title></story></items>