<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:37 31 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text> MIAMI (Billboard) - In the Latin music world, international 
hits come from unexpected places, with slickly produced pop 
often vying for the top spot in the charts with the most 
regional of sounds. As the new year kicks off, Billboard queried executives and 
industry observers in the United States and Latin America to 
come up with a list of acts with a good chance of succeeding 
beyond their borders in the first quarter.
 VALERIA GASTALDI (ARGENTINA) Gastaldi comes from Bandana, a reality-show-spawned girl 
group which became an Argentine phenomenon between 2002 and 
2003, selling almost 500,000 copies. In her debut, slated for 
May, Gastaldi pens her own songs and works with Latin 
Grammy-winning producer Cachorro Lopez.
 PAPAS DA LINGUA (BRAZIL) This witty 13-year-old pop-rock band had a loyal following 
limited mostly to the south of Brazil. But then its CD/DVD 
"Papas da Lingua ao Vivo Acustico" was picked up by EMI, and 
the track "Eu Sei" was featured in the soap opera "Paginas da 
Vida." In December, the track was No. 1 on Brazil's radio 
charts, paving the way for a surge in 2007.
 KUDAI (CHILE) Chile, long without a major international success, now has 
co-ed quartet Kudai, who have sold more than 120,000 copies in 
Latin America. A sophomore album, "Vuelve," was released last 
fall in Chile and Argentina and will hit Colombia, Mexico and 
the United States this spring. An MTV Latin America award for 
best pop artist as well as a theme song on MTV show "Quiero Mis 
Quinces" should propel sales.
 ANDRES CEPEDA (COLOMBIA) Big in Colombia with his mix of boleros, ballads and world 
beats, the endearing Cepeda has never broken ground here. 
George Zamora, the president of his La Calle Records label, 
says he's committed to doing that in the first quarter, 
reworking his single "Para Amarte Mejor," from his 2006 
self-titled album.
 MIGUEL &amp; BERNIE (DOMINICAN REPUBLIC) New York-based J&amp;N Records is home to a slew of successful 
tropical acts. Now, president Juan Hidalgo is psyched about 
bachata duo Miguel &amp; Bernie, whom he singles out for their 
distinctive vocal timbre and songwriting skills; the siblings 
have penned tracks for the likes of Frank Reyes and Monchy &amp; 
Alexandra. Their debut album is due in the first quarter.
 YURIDIA (MEXICO) An unassuming girl with a glorious voice, Yuridia is the 
top-selling alumna of TV reality show "La Academia," having 
moved nearly 1 million albums in Mexico alone. She has yet to 
do promotion in the United States, but early sales point to 
huge possibilities. A newly released album of international pop 
covers, "Habla el Corazon," paves the way for a disc of 
previously unreleased material later in 2007.
 LA SISTA (PUERTO RICO) Forget sexy reggaeton chicks in micro-shorts. Reggaeton act 
La Sista is short, chubby and proud to exult in her African 
roots, which she plays up on her newly released debut, 
"Majestad Negroide."
 RAFA VERGARA (SPAIN) After writing songs for countless acts, including David 
Bisbal, Rafa Vergara gets his turn. The native of Spain was 
signed in Miami by EMI Televisa, which will release his debut 
album, "Ojo por Ojo," in March. Expect lush ballads, performed 
and arranged in a contemporary manner.
 LOS CREADOREZ (UNITED STATES) Formed by former members of multimillion selling Grupo 
Montez de Durango, their full name is Los Creadorez del Pasito 
Duranguense de Alfredo Ramirez. A debut album, "Recio Recio," 
is due January 30.
 HECTOR MONTANER (VENEZUELA) The debut album by the son of balladeer Ricardo Montaner 
did well in Venezuela, but had little impact in the United 
States. Vene Music plans to give a heavy stateside push to his 
new March release, produced by Carlos Vives collaborator Andres 
Castro. Exposure on television, thanks to parent company 
Venevision, should help. Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/music-latin-dc-idUSN3146991620070102</link><sectors><value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>latin balladeers , reality stars eye breakthrough</title></story></items>