<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>02:01 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 2 Britain's FTSE 100 index .FTSE is seen opening 2
to 6 points higher on Tuesday, the first trading session of 2007, according to
financial bookmakers, having closed 20.1 points or 0.32 percent lower at 6,220.8
on Friday. With national holidays closing markets in the United States and Japan among
other countries, traders expect investors in the UK to focus on manufacturing
PMI data for December due at 0930 GMT and November UK house price index data due
at 1100 GMT. "Expectations are for equities to start 2007 in good health which should see
at least some of Friday's losses being recouped in early trade,"  a trader said. "However, in the bigger picture, after 4 straight years of gains, 2007 will
doubtless prove to be an interesting year for equity markets," he added.
 * Euro hits yen peak, high yielders in demand          [ID:nSYD32834] * Treasuries held down by upbeat econ views for 2007   [ID:nN29258117] * Gold hits 1-month high on weak dollar; trade slow    [ID:nSP135969] * Oil dips on mild weather, muted reaction to Saddam   [ID:nSP152887]
 UK stocks to watch on Tuesday are:
 EASYJET (EZJ.L) Malaysian budget carrier AirAsia (AIRA.KL) said on Tuesday it would make a
major announcement on a new service on Friday after a report that it was
considering an alliance with Britain's easyJet (EZJ.L) and the Virgin group
[VA.UL]. To read more please click on [ID:nKLR134773]
 VODAFONE (VOD.L) The Financial Times reported that India's Essar group has tied up financing
for a potential bid for the two-thirds of Hutchison Essar that the Indian group
does not own. Vodafone has expressed interest in acquiring Hutchison Essar.
 ROYAL BANK OF SCOTLAND (RBS.L)  The bank has offloaded 47 Marriott hotels, including the Grosvenor House on
London's Park Lane, to the Israeli property company Delek Real Estate DLKR.TA
in a deal thought to be worth 1.1 billion pounds, the Financial Times reported. 
 LSE (LSE.L) The London Stock Exchange (LSE), currently being stalked by U.S. rival
Nasdaq Stock Markets (NDAQ.O), said on Sunday companies listing on its markets
raised a record 27.9 billion pounds ($54.83 billion) in 2006. The stock exchange is an attraction for Borsa Italiana but any move would
have to come from London, the Italian stock market's head said in a newspaper
interview published on Saturday. To read more please double click on [RTRS-LSE.L]
 ROYAL DUTCH SHELL (RDSa.L) Russian gas giant Gazprom's (GAZP.MM) decision to take a majority stake in
the Royal Dutch Shell-led (RDSa.L) Sakhalin-2 project may save the European Bank
for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) from having to approve its most
controversial loan application ever.
 INTERSERVE (IRV.L) Energy services firm Cape (CIU.L) has made an informal approach to building
and maintenance company Interserve (IRV.L) to buy its industrial services
division, the Financial Times reports. To read more on this story, click on
[ID:nL02870412].
 BRITISH LAND (BLND.L), LAND SECURITIES (LAND.L), BRIXTON BXTN.L The Independent reported that eight of Britain's biggest property companies,
including Land Securities, British Land and Brixton, on Monday converted into
real estate investment trusts (REITs) to take immediate advantage of new tax
regulations that came into effect yesterday, and which allowed companies to
escape corporate tax on earnings from their property holdings. 
 NORDIC PANORAMA Shares in the Norwegian ski resort operator begin trading on AIM.
</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-britain-factors-idUSL0291193420070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>uk stocks - factors to watch on jan 2</title></story></items>