<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:53 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 2 European shares were set to make
a positive start to 2007 on Tuesday, buoyed by strength in Asian
markets, but volumes were expected to remain light with Wall
Street still closed. The euro hit a fresh record high against the yen and rose
against the dollar, while forecasts for continued warm weather
helped push oil back below $61 a barrel. Stock markets in the United States are closed to mark the
death of President Gerald Ford, while markets in Tokyo are also
closed for a holiday.
 Here's how the day looks: * Spread betters in London are calling the FTSE 100 .FTSE
5-6 points higher, the CAC 40 .FCHI 4-12 points firmer and DAX
.GDAXI between 17 and 18 points higher. * The FTSEurofirst 300 .FTEU3 index of leading European
shares closed 0.3 percent lower at 1,483.5 points on Friday in
thin trade, but up 16 percent for 2006. Double click on [.EU] to
read the closing European market report. * U.S. stocks also dipped on Friday but racked up impressive
gains in 2006. The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI ended at
12,463.2 points and the Nasdaq .IXIC was at 2,415.3 points.
Double click on [.N] to read the closing Wall Street report. * U.S. Treasuries stayed on the defensive on the last
trading day of 2006, reflecting the view that the economy may be
stronger than previously thought. Benchmark U.S. 10-year yields
were trading at around 4.682 percent. Comparable 10-year euro zone government bonds yielded 3.954
percent. Double click on [US/] for the latest Treasury market
report and [EUR/GVD] for the latest euro zone debt report. * NYMEX crude oil futures dipped below $61 a barrel as mild
weather conditions were expected to persist in the United
States. Double click on [O/R] to read the latest oil market
report. * The euro hit a record high against the yen and gained
against the dollar, buoyed in part by expectations for further
euro zone rate rises. The euro hit 157.24 yen EURJPY=, while
the dollar was trading at $1.3240 per euro EUR= and was buying
118.70 yen JPY=. Double click on [USD/] to read the latest
forex market report. * Markets were closed in Japan, while other Asian indexes
like the Kospi .KS11, Hang Seng .HSI and Straits Times
.STI were mostly firmer. Double click on [MARKETS/AS] to read
a wrap of the action in Asian asset markets. * Gold hit its highest in almost a month around $637.50 an
ounce. Double click on [GOL/] to read the latest gold market
report.
 COMPANIES ROYAL BANK OF SCOTLAND (RBS.L) The bank has offloaded 47 Marriott hotels, including the
Grosvenor House on London's Park Lane, to the Israeli property
company Delek Real Estate DLKR.TA in a deal thought to be
worth 1.1 billion pounds, the FT reported. For more, double click on [RBS.L-RTRS-LEN]
 VODAFONE (VOD.L)  India's Essar group has tied up financing for a potential
bid for the two-thirds of India's Hutchison Essar is does not
own,  the Financial Times reported on Tuesday.
 SUEZ LYOE.PA Billionaire Francois Pinault does not plan to bid for
France's Suez, LYOE.PA and will tell French regulators this
week, the Wall Street Journal reported, citing a person familiar
with the matter. For more, double click on [LYOE.PA-RTRS-LEN] LONDON STOCK EXCHANGE (LSE.L) The London Stock Exchange, currently being stalked by U.S.
rival Nasdaq Stock Markets (NDAQ.O), said on Sunday companies
listing on its markets raised a record 27.9 billion pounds
($54.83 billion) in 2006. For more, double click on [LSE.L-RTRS-LEN]
 PARMALAT (PLT.MI) Parmalat has reached a settlement for 112 million euros
($147.7 million) with bank BNL and Ifitalia over revocatory and
damages claims which the Italian food company had brought
following its collapse in 2003. For more, double click on [PLT.MI-RTRS-LEN]
 SANTANDER (SAN.MC) Spanish bank Santander, one of the biggest shareholders in
Sanpaolo IMI SPI.MI, said on Friday it had sold 4.8 percent of
the Italian bank's stock ahead of its merger with rival Banca
Intesa BIN.MI. For more on this story, click on [ID:nL29830698]
 INTESA SANPAOLO (ISP.MI) It is the first day of trading for the newly-merged bank.
The Reuters Instrument Code (RIC) for ordinary shares will be
(ISP.MI) and for savings shares (ISPn.MI). The banks said on Friday they confirmed objectives for net
income of about 7 billion euros in 2009 after taking into
account conditions required by antitrust authorities.
 BUZZI UNICEM (BZU.MI) The cement maker replaces Sanpaolo in the S&amp;P/MIB index. FIAT FIA.MI Car sales for 2006 and December will be published at 1700
GMT by the transport ministry. Fiat targets a 30 percent market
share and had secured this every month through to November. GENERALI (GASI.MI) The insurer continues to be at the centre of speculation
there could be a realignment among key shareholders. Il Messaggero said on Saturday there had been talks between
Cesare Geronzi, currently suspended from his position as
chairman of shareholder Capitalia CPTA.MI, and Giovanni
Bazoli, who heads the supervisory board at Intesa Sanpaolo,
which has distribution agreements with Generali. For more, double click on [GASI.MI-RTRS-LEN]
</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-europe-factors-idUSL0277576820070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>european stocks -- factors to watch on jan 2</title></story></items>