<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>03:06 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>SINGAPORE The euro started the year on a firm note on Tuesday, hitting a record high against the yen, but financial markets in general were subdued and many Asian bourses remained closed for holidays.U.S. light crude oil CLc1 traded 42 cents below pre-holiday levels at $60.63 in electronic trading at 05:45 GMT, with mild weather expected in the United States.The few Asian stock markets that were open moved higher, extending strong runs seen last year, with Hong Kong and Australia hitting record highs.Shares in China's top lender, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (1398.HK)(601398.SS), gained 4.6 percent after news that it was buying a 90 percent stake in PT Bank Halim Indonesia, its first overseas acquisition.The prospect of higher euro zone interest rates pushed the euro up to $1.3238 EUR= from $1.3196 in late New York trade on Friday and to a record high of 157.24 yen EURJPY=."The market's betting the ECB (European Central Bank) will keep tightening," said John Kyriakopoulos, a currency strategist at National Australia Bank."But people are less sure about the Bank of Japan. BOJ officials don't sound like they are in any hurry to hike."The euro rose more than 11 percent against the dollar in 2006 and almost 13 percent against the Japanese currency.Gold XAU= rose to $638 an ounce, its highest level in nearly a month, from $636.10/637.10 late in New York on Friday, benefiting from the weakness of the dollar.Australia's S&amp;P/ASX 200 index .AXJO ended the day just 0.01 percent higher, but that was enough to make it four record closing highs in a row."Most people are coming back with a strong attitude of injecting more money into the market and there is a bit of fresh buying out there," said Lucinda Chan, a division director at Macquarie Equities in Sydney.Macquarie Bank, Australia's top listed investment bank, added 0.9 percent to a record close of A$79.65 on expectations that a flurry of mergers and acquisitions in 2007 would help it outperform the market.Hong Kong's Hang Seng index .HSI was 1.26 percent higher at the midsession break. The index of Hong Kong-listed Chinese shares .HSCE, which nearly doubled in 2006, was up 2.1 percent.Taiwan's TAIEX share index .TWII ended 1.24 percent higher, while South Korea's KOSPI .KS11 was up 0.2 percent at 05:55 GMT.Hyundai Motor (005380.KS), South Korea's top car maker, rose 0.15 percent, losing most of its early gains even though it said it expected revenue to jump 13.5 percent in 2007, helped by higher sales in overseas markets and in high-end models.MSCI's index of Asian shares outside Japan .MSCIAPJ was up 1 percent.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-markets-global-idUSSP14700720070102</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>euro firm , oil back below $ 61</title></story></items>