<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>02:30 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates comments by analysts, details, closing prices) By Faith Hung TAIPEI, Jan 2 Taishin (2887.TW), Taiwan's No. 2
financial holding firm, said on Tuesday it would book a T$9.7
billion (US$298 million) loss in 2006 from the sale of bad debt,
sending its stock to a six-month high on investor hopes the firm
would recover from its worst year ever. The board of Taishin, whose foreign investors include private
equity fund Newbridge Capital [NB.UL] and a fund managed by
billionaire George Soros, approved the loss to be booked in its
2006 financial statements, according to a company statement. The move would pave the way for an improvement in its asset
quality because Taishin had earlier planned to book the loss over
the next five years, some analysts said. "This is a very positive step. It helps ensure common
shareholders like Soros would receive dividends in 2007," said
analyst Nora Hou of Nomura Securities, which has a target price
of T$24 on Taishin stock. The move also bodes well for Taishin's merger with Chang Hwa
Bank (2801.TW), a state-run lender in which Taishin has a 25
percent stake. "Taishin can get better terms when it negotiates with the
government about the stock swap ratio with Chang Hwa," Hou said,
adding that the merger could be completed sooner, in the first
half of this year rather than the second half.
 But some other analysts were less optimistic. "The surge of Taishin stock today is probably getting
speculative," said Dexter Hsu, an analyst for JP Morgan. "The merger's synergy would not kick in for at least another
year, since Taishin has to go through a painful process to
integrate Chang Hwa," Hsu said. TURNING AROUND Taishin also planned to raise up to T$17 billion by selling a
subordinate bond in the first quarter as Taishin seeks to improve
its financial health, the statement said. Taishin would turn profitable with a net profit of T$11.5
billion in 2007, some analysts said. Taishin was forecast to have
a full-year loss of T$14.7 billion in 2006, marking its worst
year since it was established in 2002. Taishin had said it sold a 4.67 percent stake at T$15 per
share to QE International, a subsidiary of Soros' Quantum
Partners LDC in a T$4 billion deal. On Tuesday, share of Taishin soared by the daily 7-percent
limit to close at T$20.40, its highest level since June, and was
the sixth most actively traded issue by volume. The jump means a 36 percent quick paper profit for Soros'
investment in less than two weeks. Taishin stock beat both the main stock index .TWII and the
financial sub-index .TFNI, which rose 1.24 percent and 2.58
percent, respectively. For the first nine months last year, the company had a T$4.84
billion net loss.Taishin and its peers suffered the losses after extending too
much credit to consumers who failed to pay the money back.
(US$1=T$32.48)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/taishin-taiwan-idUSTP18138920070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - taiwan taishin says to book loss , stock jumps</title></story></items>