<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>03:02 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>OSLO Jan 2 Norway plans to offset the
greenhouse gases caused by state employees' flights abroad by
buying emissions quotas to help combat global warming, Prime
Minister Jens Stoltenberg said. His office said Norway was probably the first country in the
world to buy such quotas. "The government has decided that when state employees travel
by plane abroad, we will buy quotas for the emissions caused by
the trip," Stoltenberg said in a New Year speech on Monday
night.  "We want to set an example. We hope that companies,
organisations and other countries will follow," he said. Emissions by planes on international flights are excluded
from the goals of the U.N.'s Kyoto Protocol, a plan that binds
35 rich nations to cut emissions from burning oil, coal and
natural gas by five percent below 1990 levels by 2008-12. Stoltenberg did not say how much his plan would cost.
Norway's NTB news agency estimated the cost at about $400,000 a
year. Most scientists say emissions from burning oil, coal and
natural gas are to blame for a global rise in temperatures that
may wreak havoc with the climate by causing more floods,
desertification, heatwaves, spreading disease and raising sea
levels. Some companies, including Norway's oil group Statoil,
already have similar policies of paying for emissions caused by
employees' flights. According to the Carbon Neutral Company, a passenger
travelling one way from Oslo to Washington would account for
emissions of 0.7 tonnes of carbon dioxide. It suggests a
compensating investment of about $12 in windmills or planting
trees. "In many parts of the country we have had the warmest autumn
and winter months for 100 years," Stoltenberg said. "We notice it in our daily lives -- skis are standing
unused. Children are not making snowmen. Researchers say polar
bears are threatened," he said.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/norway-greenhouse-idUSL0279772220070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>oslo to buy greenhouse quotas when bureaucrats fly</title></story></items>