<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>04:28 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>REMBANG, Indonesia Indonesia intensified on Tuesday its search and rescue effort for survivors after a ferry carrying more than 600 people sank in stormy seas off the coast of the main island of Java.Some survivors are still on life rafts in the open water, with food being airdropped to them as rough seas and bad weather prevent rescue craft from reaching them.At least 200 passengers survived the early Saturday sinking of the Senopati Nusantara ferry, a health ministry official said, but more than 400 people remain missing. Local media reported at least 60 passengers were confirmed dead."The search and rescue efforts are focused on saving the living first. The search is concentrated on areas in East Java province until seven days after the accident date," Central Java province rescue coordinator Eko Prayitno told Reuters.He said high waves and strong sea currents were pushing the bodies of the dead and the living eastwards in the direction of Surabaya, the capital of East Java province and Indonesia's second largest city.On Monday, bad weather was also linked to the crash of a domestic commercial airliner on Sulawesi island, killing 90 people.Officials said dozens of the ferry passengers had been picked up by passing ships and rescuers were also trying to reach several life rafts with people on board."Because of the bad weather, SAR (Search and Rescue) is using a fixed-wing plane for searching, and a helicopter for dropping food," Prayitno told Reuters.He said in one area alone 30 survivors remain on life rafts.Tony Syaiful, a spokesman for the Indonesian navy, said 33 survivors had been found on Tuesday. Two corpses were also recovered.Strong winds and high seas continued to hamper rescue efforts, he said.SURVIVORS PICKED UPOne survivor, a 32-year-old man with badly injured legs who gave his name as Fadlan, recounted on Tuesday his escape from the sinking vessel."I broke the windows of the deck and jumped out. It was raining hard and the waves were high. For two days I floated clinging on to foam (from life buoys) before a fishing boat found me and transported me to a navy ship," he said, shortly after arriving in the Central Java port of Rembang.According to the manifest, the Senopati Nusantara ferry was carrying 628 people, including 57 crew.Transportation Minister Hatta Rajasa has said the Japanese-built, 2,178-ton ferry was seaworthy and had a capacity of more than 850 passengers.The ship had been heading from Kalimantan on Borneo island to Semarang. It was the second ferry disaster in the last week of 2006 after a vessel overturned on Thursday in rough seas off Sumatra. Two people on that ferry died and 26 were missing as of late Sunday, a rescue official said.Ships and ferries are a popular means of transport among Indonesia's 17,000 islands. However, safety standards are not always enforced, and accidents occur fairly often.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-indonesia-sinking-idUSJAK15094820070102</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>rescuers search rough java seas for ferry survivors</title></story></items>