<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>04:36 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>An Adam Air passenger plane on an internal flight in Indonesia crashed on Sulawesi island on Monday with 96 passengers and six crew on board. Officials say 12 people survived but some are in critical condition.Following is a list of some of Indonesia's worst air disasters:* September 26, 1997 - A Garuda Airbus A-300B4 crashes in a mountainous area of northern Sumatra near Medan. All 222 passengers and 12 crew are killed in the nation's worst air disaster.* Dec 19, 1997 - All 104 people aboard a Singapore SilkAir Boeing 737-300 are killed when it crashes near the Sumatran city of Palembang.* October 12, 2004 - An Indonesian military helicopter crashes in the northern province of Aceh on Sumatra, killing all eight soldiers on board, with bad weather a possible cause.* November 30, 2004 - A Lion Air MD-82 plane carrying 146 passengers and seven crew skids off a rain-slick runway at Solo in central Java, killing 31 people and injuring dozens.* December 23, 2004 - An Indonesian military helicopter crashes in central Java, killing all 14 air force personnel on board. Bad weather was cited as the cause.* April 2, 2005 - An Australian Sea King helicopter on an aid mission to Indonesia's quake-hit Nias island crashes, killing nine.* September 5, 2005 - A Boeing 737-200 belonging to Indonesian carrier Mandala Airlines crashes in a residential area of Medan, Indonesia's third biggest city, killing 102 aboard and 47 local residents in an inferno on the ground.* January 1, 2007 - An Adam Air passenger plane flying from Surabaya to Manado with 96 passengers and six crew aboard crashes on Sulawesi island. Officials say 12 people survived but some are in critical condition.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-indonesia-plane-chronology-idUSL0188670820070102</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>factbox : indonesian air disasters</title></story></items>