<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:49 29 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text>SAN FRANCISCO U.S. comic actor Chevy Chase, who 
portrayed Gerald Ford as a klutz on the 1975-76 "Saturday Night 
Live" television shows, says he does not enjoy the renewed 
attention the ex-president's death brought him. "I'm just a guy who made some fun of Gerald Ford in 1976 
and I prefer to be left alone, really," the 63-year-old 
comedian told Reuters this week from a Colorado ski resort 
where he had been skiing with his daughter. Chase, who has starred in many Hollywood film comedies and 
written for television shows, said he gets upset when people 
say that Ford "made" his career. "The man who 'made my career' did not do 'Fletch,' did not 
do 'Caddyshack,' did not write for the 'Smothers Brothers' 
before he wrote for 'Saturday Night Live,' did not write for 12 
years before that and win Writers Guild awards. "It's that kind of thing that comes out in the press that 
perpetuates myths about me that are disgusting, that hurt my 
feelings, that hurt my family's feelings." Chase and other original cast member of "Saturday Night 
Live" once relished the national publicity that the show's 
irreverent comedy generated. But since Ford's death at age 93 on Tuesday, Chase has 
declined interview requests from the nation's top newspapers 
and television news programs, which have repeatedly played 
excerpts of his old skits. Pundits and Internet blogs also have 
been debating Chase's impact on the Ford presidency. "He did not make my career," said Chase, who spoke to 
Reuters twice this week by telephone. "If anything, I took his 
career and put it in the dumper because I did not want him to 
be president of this country, that's the way it really should 
be written." Chase said he later became friendly with Ford and called 
the Republican "a very, very sweet man." "He took my wife and I on a whole lovely trip through Grand 
Rapids to show us where he had been as a child and what not. We 
kept in touch and he was just a terrific guy," he said.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/people-ford-chevy-dc-idUSN2926781420070102</link><sectors><value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>People</value></value></sectors><title>ford didn ' t make his career , actor chase says</title></story></items>