<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>06:22 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MANILA A row has broken out in the Philippines over the transfer of a U.S. marine convicted of rape into U.S. custody, but President Gloria Macapagal Arroyo said on Tuesday the move was aimed at preserving bilateral ties.Critics say the transfer of Lance-Corporal Daniel Smith from a Manila jail to the custody of the U.S. embassy on December 29 amounted to contempt of court since no tribunal had granted the required permission.Arroyo said it was a decision by the executive."The government had to take this action in order to forestall the further deterioration in our strategic relationship with the United States, which was being rapidly eroded by our non-compliance with the Visiting Forces Agreement," she said in a statement.Although the two governments agreed Smith should be in U.S. custody pending an appeal, under the bilateral Visiting Forces Agreement, the local court had sent him to jail."The executive branch is prepared to face legal challenges to this decision and we are confident that its legitimacy and wisdom will be upheld," Arroyo said."This difficult decision was made and taken with only the best interest of the Philippines in mind."Arroyo issued the statement as the rape victim, a young Filipina known as Nicole, filed a case of contempt of court against government officials involved in the transfer of Smith.Evalyn Ursua, the lawyer for Nicole, said the transfer was "tantamount to rape of the law and of the Philippine Constitution".The case has aroused strong nationalistic sentiment in the Philippines, a former U.S. colony.Smith and three other marines who took part in bilateral military exercises in 2005 were charged with the rape of a 23-year-old management accounting graduate in a van in a former U.S. navy base while on shore leave.The other three were acquitted but Smith was sentenced to life in prison by a Manila court in early December.Washington later said it was cancelling military exercises with the Philippines because of the row over Smith's custody.But on Tuesday, U.S. embassy spokesman Matthew Lussenhop said his government had decided to proceed with the war games."We will proceed with Balikatan 2007, but the dates and places will be announced soon," he told Reuters by telephone.The annual "Balikatan" (shoulder-to-shoulder) war games are the center piece of the two countries' close security alliance and usually involve up to 5,000 U.S. soldiers and around 3,000 Filipino troops over a two-week period.The war games which took place last year from February 20 to March 5 consisted of command post exercises, field and cross-training activities, live-fire drills and humanitarian and civil assistance such as road repairs and engineering works.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-philippines-marine-idUSMAN13499820070102</link><sectors><value><value>U.S.</value></value></sectors><title>arroyo justifies transfer of convicted marine</title></story></items>