<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>04:38 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 2 European shares hit their highest
level in almost six years on Tuesday, after gains in Asia and
helped by mining and telecoms stocks, but volumes were expected
to be thin as U.S. markets were closed to mourn the death of
former President Gerald Ford. At 0849 GMT the FTSEurofirst 300 .FTEU3 index of top
European shares was up 0.9 points at 1,496.61 points in the
first trading session of the new year, its highest since Feb.
2001, as stocks followed Asian shares higher. Among major national indexes, the UK's FTSE 100 was up 0.9
percent, Germany's DAX .GDAXI was up 1 percent, also at their
highest since Feb. 2001, and France's CAC 40 gained 1.2 percent. The euro hit a record high against the yen, and gained
against the dollar, buying $1.3278. The weak dollar lifted gold
to its highest level in nearly a month, and oil prices stayed
below $61 a barrel. "We remain positive for the year as a whole," said Deutsche
Bank European strategist Bernd Meyer. "But macroeconomic
uncertainties might result in a more bumpy ride in the next
couple of weeks." Meyer said a lot depended on macroeconomic news such as
interest rate decisions in the United States and the impact of
the housing market, and fourth-quarter corporate results due
later this month. "There were quite a lot of special factors that helped Q3
reporting. The fourth quarter could easily be less supportive of
the market," he said. Among miners, BHP Billiton (BLT.L) was up 1.8 percent and
Anglo American (AAL.L) rose 1.6 percent. Activity in Germany's manufacturing sector hit a six-month
high in December, supported by accelerating growth in orders and
output, a survey of purchasing managers released on Tuesday
showed. But growth in French manufacturing slowed to its weakest in
10 months in December. Shares in French utility Suez LYOE.PA were up 1.8 percent
after French billionaire Francois Pinault declined to rule out a
possible bid for the company, adding to uncertainty around
Suez's plan to merge with Gaz de France GAZ.PA. Shares in Veolia Environnement (VIE.PA), which had soared 9
percent on Friday, were the top losers in Europe. French press
reports have said that Pinault will sell Suez's environmental
business to Veolia. Shares in Anglo-Dutch steel group Corus CS.L were up 0.9
percent after Indian newspapers reported Tata Steel (TISC.BO)
would raise its bid for the company.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/markets-europe-stocks-idUSL0290232020070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>european shares hit new highs , mining stocks help</title></story></items>