<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:49 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>BEIJING Two surveys released this week show 
that China's manufacturing sector posted modestly slower growth 
in December, although the key sector of the world's 
fourth-biggest economy was still expanding. Brokerage house CLSA's Purchasing Managers' Index (PMI) 
fell to 52.4 in December from 53.0 in November, while an index 
based on an official survey slipped to 54.8 from 55.3. The indexes are designed to give a timely snapshot of 
business conditions in the manufacturing sector. A reading 
above 50 indicates expansion, while one below 50 shows 
contraction. The official survey has been in positive territory above 50 
for two years running; CLSA's index remained above the 
boom-bust line of 50 for the 13th straight month. "Overall, the two separate PMI series seem to suggest that 
the near-term momentum in China's industrial activities would 
likely hold steady, but not necessarily decelerate further," 
Qian Wang, an economist with JPMorgan in Hong Kong, said in a 
note to clients. A slight slowdown in the output and new orders components 
of both indexes in December suggested that a recent moderation 
in investment demand would weigh on manufacturing going 
forward, she said. New export orders fell to 55 from 57.1 in the official 
survey, while they rose back above the 50 mark following a 
contraction in November, according to CLSA's reading. Jim Walker, chief economist at CLSA, said that although new 
export orders had rebounded in December, they were likely to 
fall as the U.S. economy suffered a sharp slowdown and act as a 
drag on overall orders growth. Although the easing in the CLSA index should help lower 
concerns about a re-acceleration in the economy, Beijing was 
leaning toward taking further tightening steps in 2007, Walker 
said. Last year, China twice hoisted interest rates and raised 
the amount of funds which lenders must hold in reserve three 
times as part of a long-running campaign to curb an 
investment-fuelled liquidity boom. A recent moderation in investment growth has offered some 
evidence that such measures have had some success, but many 
economists expect the government to raise interest rates 
further and to take other tightening measures this year. Walker said Beijing would also keep close tabs on inflation 
pressures after CLSA's sub-index on input prices hit 60.3 and 
the output price index climbed to 54.9, its highest reading 
since July. "Chinese inflation pressures are bubbling just below the 
surface. Difficult policy choices lie ahead for Beijing in the 
new year," he said. Annual consumer price inflation remained under two percent 
in 2006, but rose to 1.9 percent in November from 1.4 percent 
in October in part due to quickly rising grain prices.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/businesspro-china-economy-clsa-dc-idUSPEK13488120070102</link><sectors></sectors><title>chinese manufacturing growth slows in dec : surveys</title></story></items>