<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:24 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON The euro rose to a record peak against the Japanese yen and a near seven-year high versus the Swiss franc on Tuesday as hunger for rising yields looked to be setting the tone for early 2007.Growth in the euro zone manufacturing sector slowed marginally in December, data released earlier showed, but that failed to shake robust sentiment on the euro area currency, as investors started this year in the same vein as they ended 2006.Liquidity was significantly thinned on Tuesday by a market holiday in Japan, with forex trading also seen winding down early in the United States to commemorate the death of former President Gerald Ford."The Swiss franc and the yen are still fairly weak versus the euro, indicating that risk appetite in the market is high and carry trades are very much in vogue," said Michael Klawitter, currency strategist at Dresdner Kleinwort in Frankfurt.By 1202 GMT the euro had hit a lifetime peak against the yen at 157.85, according to Reuters data EURJPY=, extending an almost 13 percent advance made in 2006.It also rose to a near seven-year high of 1.6112 Swiss francs EURCHF= and climbed half a percent versus the dollar to stand at $1.3564 EUR=.The RBS/NTC Eurozone Purchasing Managers' Index, which measures activity in the manufacturing sector, slipped to 56.5 last month -- a nine-month low and below a consensus forecast for a rise to 56.8 -- from 56.6 in November. But it remained firmly above the 50 mark that divides growth from contraction."There is nothing in these surveys that suggests rates don't go up in the first quarter of this year, probably in March," said Mark Miller, economist at HBOS Treasury Services, noting that exports had held up well.The European Central Bank is widely expected to raise borrowing costs to 3.75 percent from the current 3.5. By contrast, the next move on U.S. interest rates is likely to be a cut from 5.25 percent after a steady policy in recent months.Japanese rates are seen rising at a very gradual pace from 0.25 percent -- maintaining the euro's yield advantage.HUNT FOR YIELDThe Yomiuri newspaper reported the Bank of Japan would consider raising rates at its January 17-18 policy meeting, but added a hike might be delayed depending on "adjustments" between the BOJ and the government and ruling parties.The Australian dollar hit nine-year highs above 94.50 yen AUDJPY=R as the market priced in more risk of a further increase in Australian interest rates.The dollar maintained an overall weaker bias, down 0.17 percent at 118.86 yen JPY=.Financial markets are still pricing in at least one rate cut for the United States in 2007, although surprising strength in some recent data has pushed out the timing of any move.The minutes of the Federal Reserve's December policy meeting may help refine the outlook for rates. The minutes were due to be released on Tuesday but have been put back to Wednesday due to the national holiday.The ISM reading on manufacturing is also due on Wednesday along with vehicle sales, while Friday has the December payrolls report.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/02/us-markets-forex-idUSN2941694320070102</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>forex - euro hits record peak vs yen as yields in focus</title></story></items>