<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:33 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>SEOUL South Korea expects exports to grow 10.4 percent in 2007, decelerating from a 14.6 percent gain in 2006, hit by a slowdown in the U.S. economy, the commerce ministry said on Wednesday.Exports will reach $360 billion in 2007, while imports will probably rise a faster 10.9 percent to $343 billion, resulting in a surplus of $17 billion, according to the commerce ministry."Global economic growth is seen slowing down, mainly on a downturn in the U.S. economy, despite stable economic growth in countries such as China and India," the ministry said in a statement.Goh You-sun, an economist at Daewoo Securities, said Daewoo had anticipated slower export growth this year due to a slowing U.S. economy, although the government's outlook looked more grim than her expectations."How fast the U.S. economy will get back on track, and the pace of the won's appreciation are keys. The won will continue to strengthen this year though the pace could be slower than last year," she added.The South Korean won climbed 8.4 percent against the dollar in all of 2006.Economists have said the slowdown in U.S. economic growth this year and an expected weakening of global expansion in 2007 will inevitably hit Asian exports.China is South Korea's largest export market and takes more than one-fifth of the smaller country's shipments abroad, although many of the goods sent to China end up in the U.S. market.Exports from Asia's third-largest economy grew faster in 2006 than a 12 percent rise in 2005, although still down from a 31 percent jump in 2004, playing a solid role in the economy amid weak domestic demand and helping to keep the economy on a recovery track.The commerce ministry said in a separate statement that foreign direct investment plans received by South Korea fell 2.9 percent in 2006 to $11.23 billion and are expected to show little change in 2007.In 2005, such plans had fallen around 10 percent to $11.56 billion, from a year earlier."Foreign direct investment has been gradually shrinking and the trend could continue, said Lim Ji-won, an economist at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co, citing competition with China and the won's strength as key reasons."There is talk about making South Korea Asia's hub but not much is really happening."The benchmark KOSPI share index erased early gains to be down 0.5 percent after the export forecast figures, with key exporters such as chip maker Samsung Electronics turning a modest gain into a 0.6 percent fall by noon.The foreign exchange market reacted little to the forecast, with the won down about 0.1 percent against the dollar at around 926.(Additional reporting by Kim Soyoung and Rhee Soeui)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-korea-economy-idUSSEO14308720070103</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>s . korea expects 10 . 4 pct growth in 2007 exports</title></story></items>