<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>06:37 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Shares in British Bluetooth chip specialist CSR (CSR.L) slid after it was named at the center of a patent infringement case brought against Nokia (NOK1V.HE), Samsung Electronics (005930.KS) and Matsushita-owned (6752.T) Panasonic.The Cambridge-based Bluetooth chip market leader fell as much as 6.6 percent before clawing back some of the early losses to stand down 3.3 percent at 638-1/2 pence by 1058 GMT.The Federal law suit has been brought by the Washington Research Foundation. The Foundation said in the document seen by Reuters that it is acting on behalf of the University of Washington, which owns the patents in question.The Foundation claims the three firms have sold handsets and devices in the United States using CSR's Bluetooth chips which use technology that infringe the University's radio frequency receiver patents.The patents have already been licensed to CSR's rival Broadcom (BRCM.O)."Defendants have manufactured, used, imported into the United States, sold and offered for sale devices which, or the use of which, infringes at least the '963' patent," the Foundation said in a complaint filed at the United States Western District Court of Washington State at Seattle.A spokesman for CSR, which was not sued by the research group as it does not sell the chips directly into the United States, said the firm was looking closely at the legal documents but declined to comment further.Nokia declined to comment. "We are currently studying the claims," said spokeswoman Eija-Riitta Huovinen.Samsung and Panasonic were not immediately available to comment.One analyst said that patent cases such as these were notoriously unpredictable in their outcome, while another said the worst case scenario would merely see CSR pay the university for the licenses."I think it's far too early to say but apparently innocuous patent cases can blow up into a bit of a mine," said Nomura analyst Sean Murphy."It could take years before it will be obvious whether it represents a serious threat," he added.Named after a 10th century Scandinavian King, Bluetooth technology uses radio frequency to enable mobile phones and other electronic gadgets to talk to each other and transfer data over short distances without the need for wires.Engineer Jaap Haartsen at Swedish mobile phone maker Ericsson (ERICb.ST) has been credited with the invention of Bluetooth during his research work in the second half of the 1990s.Ericsson has donated the technology, royalty-free, to create a large market for the wire replacement.Hundreds of millions of mobile phones, headsets and laptops are now equipped with Bluetooth chips every year, while a number of adaptations have been made to the technology to make it faster.(Additional reporting by Tarmo Virki in Helsinki, Lucas van Grinsven in Amsterdam)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-csr-bluetooth-patent-idUSL0313406120070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>csr shares hit by bluetooth infringement claims</title></story></items>