<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>05:32 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 3 ITV Plc (ITV.L) said it had
appointed the former Times and Telegraph new media director
Annelies van den Belt to lead the commercial broadcaster's
launch of a broadband portal in 2007. In a statement, ITV said the service would carry all of its
best content for viewers to access mostly for free.
 The Web site, which will have an entertainment feel and
carry user-generated content, will launch at the end of March
and show ITV's live broadcast channel and reruns of programmes
within a 30-day window via a media player. Van den Belt joins ITV as managing director of the broadband
team from the Telegraph Media Group where she was director of
new media. She had previously spent five years at News
International where she launched Times Online. In her new role, van den Belt will be responsible for all
aspects of commercial and operational delivery for the broadband
site, including advertising, content production and
commissioning, ITV said. "Plans for our broadband portal are ambitious and well
advanced," Jeff Henry, director of ITV Consumer said in a
statement on Wednesday. "Bringing on board an industry leader
like Annelies is a hugely significant step." ITV has previously said it will spend 20 million pounds
($39.44 million) on the launch of the service.  The broadcaster is looking to reduce its reliance on its
flagship ITV1 channel which has suffered in the last year from a
falling audience and lower advertising revenue. It hopes to draw 50 percent of revenues from outside ITV1
advertising by the end of 2010. The ITV proposition differs from Channel 4 which said in
November it would launch its own video-on-demand service to
allow viewers to catch up with programmes via their Web site for
a small fee. Most of ITV's programming will be available for free with
the exception of some premium events like sports. Britain's pay-TV company BSkyB BSY.L said on Tuesday it
would also launch an on-demand service later in 2007. The announcement from ITV follows months of uncertainty at
Britain's biggest commercial broadcaster. Cable operator NTL NTLI.O said in November it was
considering making a bid for ITV, before its rival BSkyB stepped
in and effectively blocked the move by buying a 17.9 percent
stake for almost 1 billion pounds. ITV then secured a huge boost when it poached Michael Grade
from the BBC to be its new executive chairman. The two new
appointments will start on Jan 8.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/itv-broadband-idUSL0311504220070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>itv signs up new media boss for broadband portal</title></story></items>