<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>06:53 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>DHAKA Bangladesh's Sheikh Hasina said on Wednesday that the mainstream political alliance she leads would boycott the January 22 elections because the interim government had failed to ensure the vote would be free and fair.The former prime minister's move adds to uncertainty ahead of the parliamentary elections, which have already brought weeks of political violence and crippling strikes."We have agreed not to participate in the election because the country's interim government in charge of holding a free and fair election has failed to create a congenial election atmosphere," said Hasina, whose Awami League leads a powerful 14-party alliance."Besides the election boycott, we will now launch a bigger movement to oust Iajuddin from the post of caretaker chief," she told a news conference.The country has been run by a caretaker government, headed by President Iajuddin Ahmed, since Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chief Begum Khaleda Zia ended her five-year term as prime minister in October.Hasina accused Iajuddin of favoring Khaleda and demanded he step aside because he had failed to prove his neutrality and acted under her rival's instructions.She called for a new interim chief to be appointed soon, demanded that the voters' list be updated and corrected, and that new election schedules be announced.Acting Chief Election Commissioner Mahfuzur Rahman said Hasina's alliance had formally conveyed its decision to boycott the election. "But we will continue our work for holding the polls on the due date," he told reporters.Nazmul Huda, a senior BNP leader and former minister, slammed Hasina's decision, saying "Awami League had smelt a massive defeat in the election. So they have made a face-saving retreat."Ali Ahsan Mohammad Mujahid, secretary-general of Jamaat-e-Islami, a BNP ally, urged the interim authority to deal with attempts to "foil the election and create lawlessness with heavy hands".BIAS CLAIMHasina denounced the Election Commission saying "biased and dishonest" officials could not be trusted to hold a free and impartial election."They must be removed while corrupt and partisan civil officials be kept off duty during the polls," she said.Bangladesh's constitution stipulates that the interim authority must hold new elections within three months, although this can be extended with permission from the Supreme Court.Hasina said people would take responsibility to protect the constitution and preserve democracy, "but they want to get rid of a corrupt and biased administration first," hinting that she could re-enter the election race should her demands be met.Bangladesh's giant neighbor India said the election machinery in Bangladesh should inspire confidence."It is our hope that the people of Bangladesh will be able to elect a government of their own choice in a free, fair credible and democratic election," an Indian foreign ministry spokesman said in response to questions about Hasina's decision.At least 45 people have been killed and hundreds injured in political violence since the interim government took over to steer the country to the polls.Hasina on Wednesday reaffirmed plans to stage a countrywide protest on January 5, followed by transport blockades on January 7 and 8.(Additional reporting by Serajul Islam Quadir, Azad Majumder, Ruma Paul and Y.P. Rajesh in New Delhi))(Editing by Jeremy Laurence; Reuters Messaging: anis.ahmed.reuters.com@reuters.net; +880-2-8614088))</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-bangladesh-election-idUSDHA15142020070103</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>hasina - led alliance to boycott bangladesh elections</title></story></items>