<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:09 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>BRUSSELS European countries met on Wednesday to push for a revival of the peace process in Somalia, as Ethiopian warplanes backing the Somali government pursued fleeing Islamists near the border with Kenya.The Islamists, who withdrew from their last stronghold on Monday after two weeks of war, rejected a government amnesty offer after disappearing into the hills and vowing to fight on.Swedish Foreign Minister Carl Bildt told Reuters before the meeting in Brussels: "We are keen to see an inclusive political process in Somalia ... without that it will be difficult to achieve security."Norwegian Foreign Minister Jonas Gahr Stoere said: "It would be a missed opportunity to say that every category of people calling themselves Islamists should be excluded."Both said they would call for Ethiopian troops to leave the country quickly but without creating a security vacuum, and would discuss a possible international peacekeeping force."It is certainly not something Europe can fix, dictate or arrange," Stoere said of a peacekeeping force. "But it is an issue where we should be able to contribute politically," he said, adding that "some kind of presence" would be needed.Germany, which took over the EU's rotating presidency on January 1, called the meeting of European members of the International Contact Group on Somalia to coordinate European efforts and take stock of the situation, it said in a statement.The European members of the Contact Group are the EU presidency, Sweden, Britain, Italy, the EU's executive Commission and non-EU member Norway."If you look at the past 15 years in Somalia it is difficult to be that optimistic, but ... we will look at that new situation and see if we can make anything good come out of it," Bildt said.The full International Contact Group on Somalia -- which also comprises the United States and Tanzania -- is to meet on Friday in Nairobi at working-group level, the Norwegian and Swedish ministers said.They also said they would discuss increasing humanitarian aid to Somalia.Ethiopian planes, tanks and troops helped the Somali government drive the Islamists from Mogadishu last week, after breaking out of its provincial outpost Baidoa to end six months of Islamist rule across much of southern Somalia.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-somalia-conflict-eu-idUSL0311755620070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>eu meets to push for peace process in somalia</title></story></items>