<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>06:38 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>  (Updates prices, adds fresh quotes, changes byline) By Carolyn CohnLONDON Jan 3 (Reuters) - The yen hit a record low against
the euro and a two-month low against the dollar on Wednesday as
the hunt for yield dominated sentiment ahead of U.S. data that
could give clues on the direction of U.S. interest rates. Carry plays, using low-yielding currencies such as the yen
to fund purchases of units with more attractive interest rates,
were the major factor behind the euro's pulse higher, analysts
said. The euro has hit successive record highs against the yen in
recent weeks, as investors look for a quicker pace of monetary
tightening in the euro zone than in Japan. "What we're seeing on euro/yen is pretty much a continuation
of the themes from the end of last year -- the theme of carry is
still very much in place," BNP Paribas senior currency
strategist Ian Stannard said. A holiday in Tokyo kept liquidity thin, analysts added. By 1053 GMT, the euro had hit a record peak of 158.02
EURJPY= according to Reuters data, its fourth record high in a
week, with technical analysts looking for the pair to break
160/161 yen in coming weeks. "The euro zone has stronger inflation so there is not as
compelling a case for the BOJ (Bank of Japan) to hike rates as
there is for the ECB (European Central Bank)," said Daragh
Maher, currency strategist at Calyon. The dollar rose half a percent to 119.45 yen JPY=, and
sterling and the Australian dollar also hit multi-year highs
against the Japanese currency. The high-yielding Australian dollar hit a one-year high
against the U.S. dollar AUD=, but the lower-yielding Canadian
dollar hit a nine-month low against the greenback CAD=.
 RATE MOVES The ECB is expected to raise borrowing costs to 3.75 percent
in coming months from the current 3.5. By contrast, the next
move on U.S. interest rates is likely to be a cut from 5.25
percent after a steady policy in recent months. Japanese rates are seen rising at a very gradual pace from
0.25 percent, maintaining the euro's yield advantage. Official figures for December showed the number of
unemployed people in Germany posted its sharpest monthly fall
since 1950, pushing the jobless rate below 10 percent for the
first time in over four years. The euro hit its highest level against the Swiss franc in
almost seven years, but fell 0.4 percent against the dollar to
$1.3223 EUR=, more than half a cent below three-week highs set
in the previous session.
 FOMC MINUTES, U.S. DATA DUE Minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's latest rate-setting
meeting at 1900 GMT were seen casting light on current thinking
for the U.S. rate outlook, with analysts widely expecting that
the next move in borrowing costs will be a cut. Fed officials have been talking tough on inflation even as
the market bet on rate cuts, and dollar bears will be looking
for any hint of a softer tone. The Institute for Supply Management's December reading on
the U.S. manufacturing sector is also due, while Friday brings
the non-farm payrolls report for December. A reading below 50 in the ISM index, which dipped below the
boom-or-bust level for the first time in three-and-a-half years
in November, would reinforce concerns about an economic
slowdown. The ISM is forecast to give a reading of 49.9. Other U.S. data due on Wednesday includes the ADP December
employment report at 1315 GMT, often seen as a precursor to
Friday's payrolls data.
  (Additional reporting by Simon Falush in London)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSL0312848920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - yen hits record low vs euro , 2 - mth low vs dollar</title></story></items>