<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:03 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 3 European stocks traded slightly
lower, but still close to near six-year highs on Wednesday, with
mining stocks weighing on the market as investors waited for
direction from Wall Street's first session of the year. Among major movers, CSR (CSR.L) shares tumbled after it was
named at the centre of a patent infringement case, while
Husqvarna (HUSQb.ST) gained after its biggest shareholder
rejected a bid approach. At 1140 GMT, the FTSEurofirst 300 index of top European
shares .FTEU3 was down 0.1 percent after earlier touching its
highest level since February 2001. "Many institutional clients are very cautious; they are very
sceptical on whether this can go on, they see the economy
slowing down, and they suspect the equity markets should
follow," said Andreas Gartner, fund manager at SEB. "We need some more weakness in the U.S. to avoid the Fed
increasing interest rates further. If we see some kind of soft
landing in the next six months, it will be very positive for the
markets." Among national indexes, Britain's FTSE 100 .FTSE and
Germany's DAX .GDAXI were down 0.1 percent, while France's CAC
40 .FCHI slipped 0.3 percent. Japanese markets were still closed for the New Year break,
 and U.S. stock markets were shut on Tuesday to mark the death
of former president Gerald Ford. "When Wall Street comes in, it will be interesting to see if
European shares can hold on to their gains," said Mike Lenhoff,
chief strategist at Brewin Dolphin. "We've had four really good years on the trot, and some sort
of consolidation could be due, though it may not come until
after the first quarter." U.S. manufacturing data was scheduled for release at 1500
GMT, with the minutes from the Federal Reserve's Open Markets
Committee December meeting due at 1900 GMT.
 MINERS DROP Mining stocks helped cap the market's gains, with
Antofagasta (ANTO.L) down 2.7 percent, Rio Tinto (RIO.L) 2.1
percent lower and BHP Billiton (BLT.L) down 1.8 percent as
copper tumbled below $6,000 a tonne on surplus worries. Steelmakers were also weaker after Credit Suisse cut its
recommendation on the sector to "underweight" from
"marketweight", on the grounds that problems may arise in the
next three to six months. ThyssenKrupp (TKAG.DE) fell 2.2 percent, Acerinox (ACX.MC)
dropped 3.1 percent, and Salzgitter (SZGG.DE) slid 1.8 percent. Also on the downside, shares in British bluetooth specialist
CSR (CSR.L) fell 3.8 percent after it was named at the centre of
a patent infringement case brought against Nokia (NOK1V.HE),
Samsung Electronics (000830.KS) and Matsushita (6752.T). Nokia shares fell 1 percent. Elsewhere, Husqvarna added 1.8 percent after Investor AB
(INVEb.ST) rejected a bid approach for the lawnmower and
chainsaw maker.





</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-europe-shares-idUSL0385508920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>european stocks tread water as miners cap gains</title></story></items>