<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:09 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> By Fatos Bytyci PRISTINA, Serbia, Jan 3 The winner of a 3.5
billion euro energy tender that has attracted big international
firms will be announced by the end of 2007, Kosovo's energy
minister said on Wednesday. The project involves the construction of a 2.47 billion euro
coal-fired power plant with a capacity of up to 2,100 MW, the
overhaul of the existing electricity plant and development of a
new lignite mine nearby. "We will have a decision in October, November or December on
which company or consortium has won the tender," Kosovo's Energy
and Mining Minister Ethem Ceku told Reuters. The government has narrowed the race down to four bids: - a joint bid by Czech power firm CEZ CEZPsp.PR, the
largest central European company, with AES (AES.N) of the United
States - a joint bid by Italian energy group ENEL (ENEI.MI) and
Sencap, a consortium of Greece's Public Power Corp. (PPC)
(DEHr.AT) and U.S. energy company ContourGlobal - a bid by Germany's RWE (RWEG.DE), one of Europe's biggest
electricity generators - a bid by a consortium of German utility EnBW (EBKG.DE),
part-owned by France's EDF (EDF.PA), and U.S.-based WGI. Ceku said the entire project would cost around 3.5 billion
euros ($4.65 billion). "In 2008 the company or consortium will start building the
power plant," he said. "The plant, Kosovo C, will start working
in 2012."   He added that the Kosovo government might hold as much as
49 percent of shares in Kosovo C. Lignite, one of the cheapest forms of fuel used by power
plants to produce power, is Kosovo's largest resource, with
around 10 billion tonnes. The province of 2 million people, which has been run by the
United Nations since NATO bombs drove out Serb forces in 1999,
is still plagued by power shortages. U.N. officials say it has
the natural resources to become a regional electricity exporter. A decision on the demand of the 90-percent Albanian majority
for independence from Serbia is expected in the spring. Local
officials hope that political clarity will encourage much-needed
foreign investment and lift the province out of poverty.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/kosovo-energy-idUSL0312375620070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>kosovo sees winner of power plant tender end - 2007</title></story></items>