<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:01 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (This is one of a series of stories previewing this year's
North American International Auto Show in Detroit) By Jui ChakravortyDETROIT Jan 3 (Reuters) - A year ago, General Motors Corp.
(GM.N) was facing the risk of bankruptcy and the ire of a
big-money shareholder, while an all-black cover of Fortune
magazine concluded the world's top automaker was "heading for a
wreck." But GM management silenced its critics in 2006 by cutting
more than 34,000 jobs, unveiling plans to close 12 plants and
reduce recurring costs by $9 billion. The cost-cutting flurry by GM Chief Executive Rick Wagoner
sent GM stock up more than 50 percent over the year,
outperforming the Dow Jones industrials by more than 3-to-1. Now, caution analysts, comes the hard part: convincing
still skeptical investors that GM can deliver sustained
profitability against increasingly successful competitors in a
weak market. Although GM still sells twice as many cars in the U.S.
market as Toyota Motor Corp. (7203.T), it is on track to be
overtaken by Toyota for the global top spot in terms of
production in 2007. And even after the share rally of last year, GM also has a
market capitalization, at $17 billion, that is just one-twelfth
that of Toyota's and one-fourth that of Honda Motor Co.
(7267.T) The disappearance of billionaire investor Kirk Kerkorian,
who had agitated for changes at GM before selling off his
stake, removes the uncertainty of a fight for board control but
also puts the spotlight back on GM management in 2007, analysts
said. "Wagoner's hotseat has cooled down a little bit," Argus
Research analyst Kevin Tynan said. "But at the same time, the
pressure has risen a bit because now there is no outside
activist, it's all about Wagoner and his strategy. So in a way
Kerkorian's departure intensifies long-term pressure." 'BIG BUT OUTDATED' GM executives say they understand the magnitude of the
problems. An internal planning memo, which became public in
December, describes the automaker as "big but outdated" and
warns that GM's "advantages of size and economies of scale are
eroding." The strategy document, first reported by the Detroit News
and confirmed by GM, also says that "lack of flexibility is
GM's chief disadvantage." That issue will loom large this year when GM kicks off
labor talks with the United Auto Workers union aimed it
clinching a new four-year contract. For GM, which has not faced a strike since 1998, the
negotiations are expected to test a collaborative relationship
with the UAW as the automaker seeks to unwind many of the
costly obligations written into past contracts. Those include health-care costs averaging $1,500 per
vehicle for GM and a "jobs bank" program that has morphed since
its creation in 1984 into a nearly open-ended commitment to pay
laid-off union workers. "What they have to get is major concessions to reduce cost,
create flexibility, cut wages, retiree benefits and health-care
costs," said Standard &amp; Poor's equity analyst Efraim Levy.
"They will also have to do away with the jobs bank." The UAW contract does not expire until Sept. 14 and
intensive talks are not expected until the summer, but in the
meantime the automaker will have to clinch a deal with bankrupt
former subsidiary Delphi Corp. DPHIQ.PK and the UAW. That deal, which is central to Delphi's plans to emerge
from bankruptcy, will determine the final tally for GM's
Delphi-related liability, estimated at between $6 billion and
$7.5 billion. CHANGING PLACES GM will likely be surpassed in global production by Toyota
in 2007, ending a run of over 80 years as the No. 1 automaker.
But some analysts say that those bragging rights should be the
least of GM's concerns. "It's a great headline grabber, but it is insignificant,"
Erich Merkle of IRN Inc. said. "All it means is that Toyota is
a dominant competitor, but we've known that for years. What GM
has to do, whether they are largest or second largest, is to
figure out how to make money selling cars." GM has several new car models hitting showrooms in 2007,
including the Chevrolet Malibu, the Cadillac CTS and the Saturn
Astra. It also has well-reviewed crossovers -- car-based
utility vehicles that are smaller than its traditional SUVs --
such as the GMC Acadia, Saturn Outlook and Buick Enclave. The
new Saturn Vue and Aura will also hit showrooms. "GM has accomplished a lot of the groundwork needed for a
turnaround in 2006," Tynan said. "But they still have a lot of work to do. Their products
need to sell, they need to reach out to markets they have
lagged in, such as the younger buyers and the West Coast, and
they need to start making a profit in North America," he said.
 (For other stories in the series, go to
here)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/autoshow-gm-idUSN2644440920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>auto show : gm faces new pressures after year of deep cuts</title></story></items>