<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:13 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 3 The FTSE 100 .FTSE index of
Britain's leading shares fell 0.1 percent by midday on
Wednesday, with miners hit by a tumbling copper price on surplus
concerns, led down by Kazakhmys (KAZ.L). A falling gold price put further pressure on the sector,
traders said. Kazakhmys (KAZ.L) fell 6 percent, while
Antofagasta (ANTO.L) fell 4.7 percent. Xstrata XTA.L fell 4.7
percent and Anglo American (AAL.L) fell 3.2 percent. "This is further evidence that mining is a see saw sector,
and that these are phenomenal stocks for arbitrageurs," a trader
said.  By 1150 GMT, the FTSE 100 index fell 8.2 points to 6,303.7.  Economic data from the U.S., including manufacturing,
construction spending and jobs data, will provide a steer on the
health of the country's economy, which may influence UK stocks,
traders said. The Federal Open Market Committee minutes due after the
close at 1900 GMT will come too late to have an impact on the UK
market on Wednesday, traders said. "This flat market is a pause for breath after Tuesday's big
market rise on thin volume," said Richard Hunter, head of
research at Hargreaves Lansdown.  "Everybody is waiting for Christmas trading statements from
retailers and for related consumer debt levels when banks issue
trading statements in February." The oil price fell towards $60 a barrel as mild weather in
the U.S. Northeast undermined demand for fuel in the world's
biggest heating oil market. Royal Dutch Shell (RDSa.L) fell 0.5
percent and BP (BP.L) fell 0.4 percent. Among other standout losers, Drax Group (DRX.L) fell 3.6
percent after a warm start to the winter and on weak power
prices, traders said. Among gainers, white goods retailer DSG DSGI.L rose 1.3
percent on Christmas trading optimism, traders said. Clothing retailer Next (NXT.L) rose 0.5 percent on hopes
that its Christmas trading statement on Friday could produce
higher margins than expected. Supermarket Wm Morrison Supermarkets (MRW.L) rose 1.1
percent a few days ahead of a Christmas trading statement, and
benefiting from positive like-for-like sales in the last nine
weeks of 2006 at wine warehouse store chain Majestic Wine
(MJW.L), up 0.4 percent, traders said. Insurer Prudential (PRU.L) added 2.4 percent on perennial
vague bid speculation, traders said. A UBS sector comment note boosted the banking sector. Key
picks were Barclays (BARC.L), which rose 0.9 percent, and RBS
(RBS.L), which rose 1.6 percent after UBS said it was the
cheapest large bank anywhere. HSBC Holdings (HSBA.L) gained 0.6 percent on news that the
banking group had appointed Simon Robertson, a City of London
adviser, to be its leading non-executive director.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-britain-stocks-idUSL0312201920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>ftse falls ; lower copper , gold hit miners</title></story></items>