<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:55 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 3 London robusta coffee futures are
poised to probe their highest levels since early 1999, driven by
the increased appetite of investment funds for coffee, rising
world consumption and falling stocks, traders said on Wednesday. The recent rise, which saw prices hit seven-week highs on
Tuesday, pointed to further gains by the futures market for
robustas, which are used mainly to produce soluble coffees. "There is anticipation that the market has potential to move
higher -- stocks have come down," a London futures trader said. He said the market would set its sights on $1,700 and $1,750
a tonne if the $1,653 level was broken. Prices rose to a 7-1/2-year high of $1,653, basis the second
position on the futures market, on November 9 as investment
funds bought heavily amid reports of crop problems in Brazil,
the world's leading producer of all coffees, and growing world
consumption. Robusta futures surged 34 percent in 2006, fuelled by strong
global demand for coffee, tightening supplies and growing
interest in the commodity from investment funds. Traders saw no reason for the bullish trend to lose momentum
yet, but said selling by Vietnam, the world's biggest robusta
exporter, at the peak of its harvest in the coming weeks would
limit gains. "Robust export demand helped to underpin the market
short-term," analyst Redtower Research said in a report. On Tuesday benchmark March LKDH7 robustas touched $1,634,
driven up by fund and speculative buying. March eased on
profit-taking to stand at $1,607 early on Wednesday morning. "If we don't get to $1,653 (in March futures) in the short
term, then I don't think we'll get to it until the second half
of 2007," said Andrea Thompson, analyst with CoffeeNetwork. The London futures trader said $1,653 might be reached later
on Wednesday depending on the New York arabica futures market,
which re-opens after a four-day break. London traders predicted a stronger opening by arabica
futures on the New York Board of Trade. Thompson estimated that total world coffee stocks at the
beginning of the 2006/07 season were 42 million bags, down from
48 million at the beginning of 2005/06. Coffee output in Vietnam and Brazil was expected to decline
in 2007/08 from 2006/07 for cyclical reasons, traders and
analysts said. In its first 2007/08 (July-June) coffee crop forecast on
December 15, Brazil's government saw output at 31.1-32.3 million
60-kg bags, sharply below the 42.5 million harvested this
season.
 Traders reported talk that investment funds might increase
their allocations to coffee in 2007 in the hope of reaping
further big returns after the strong gains seen in 2006. They noted buoyant export demand for coffee, noting strong
growth potential in eastern Europe and Asia, especially for
robustas, as incomes grew. Thompson said total world consumption would grow by 1.6-1.8
percent in 2007.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-coffee-idUSL0346397020070103</link><sectors><value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>london coffee prices seen ready to test new highs</title></story></items>