<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>20:19 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TOKYO Jan 4 The dollar dipped against the yen
on Thursday but stayed in sight of a 2-½   month peak scaled in
the previous session, buoyed by a survey showing that the U.S.
factory sector expanded in December. The dollar jumped on Wednesday after the Institute for
Supply Management said its manufacturing index climbed to 51.4
from 49.5 in November, above the 50 threshold that separates
expansion from contraction.
 The U.S. currency pared some of its gains after the minutes
of the Federal Reserve's December policy meeting indicated the
central bank sees increased downside risks to economic growth
even as inflation remained the predominant concern. Given such mixed signals, it was unclear whether the dollar
would muster enough energy during the Tokyo trading session to
rise convincingly beyond the previous day's high, said a trader
for a Japanese trust bank. "It doesn't seem like views (on the U.S. economy) are tilted
clearly in one direction," he said. In early Tokyo trade, the dollar was at 119.28 yen JPY=.
That was down slightly from around 119.40 yen in late U.S.
trading on Wednesday, when it rose to as high as 119.68 yen, its
highest level since mid-October. The euro was nearly flat at $1.3170 EUR=. The single currency slipped to 157.10 yen EURJPY=R from
around 157.25 yen in late New York trade and a record high of
158.06 yen hit on electronic trading platform EBS on Wednesday. Traders said the yen continued to look vulnerable after also
having fallen to fresh eight-year lows against sterling and
nine-year lows versus the Australian dollar this week, dragged
down by its low-yielding status. The yen was softer despite Japan's Yomiuri newspaper
reporting on Monday that the Bank of Japan will likely consider
raising interest rates as early as this month's policy meeting. The Yomiuri said, however, that the BOJ's decision on a rate
hike could be delayed until February or later, depending on
"adjustments" between the central bank and the government and
ruling parties. The BOJ held rates at 0.25 percent at its policy board
meeting in December, and traders are now focusing on whether the
central bank will raise rates in January.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/markets-forex-idUST13472220070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - dollar pulls back from 2 - ½ mth high vs yen</title></story></items>