<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:41 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TEL AVIV Jan 3 Israel's chemicals and
pharmaceuticals sector will post a 15 percent increase in
exports in 2007 to $10 billion, the Manufacturers Association
trade group said on Wednesday. In 2006 the sector's exports grew by 15.7 percent to $8.8
billion in what was the best year in a decade for the industry,
said Joseph Barnea, a member of the association's board and
outgoing chairman of its chemicals and drugs division. The gain came despite an 8 percent appreciation of the
shekel ILS= against the dollar during the year that hurt
companies with sales focused on the United States.  The fast growing sector's sales abroad account for 30
percent of Israel's industrial exports excluding diamonds,
Barnea told a news conference, making it the second largest
exporting industry after electronics. Domestic sales in 2006 rose 10 percent to $8.6 billion. Barnea forecast that the sector, which employs 28,700
workers, will record total sales in 2007 of $19.5 billion, up 12
percent from 2006. The sector includes several of Israel's largest companies,
such as Teva Pharmaceutical Industries TEVA.O (TEVA.TA), the
world's biggest generic drug maker; Israel Chemicals CHIM.TA;
and MA Industries MAIN.TA, the world's largest maker of
generic agrochemicals. Barnea said an ongoing trend in the sector of transferring
operations abroad was worrying. Currently, more than 25
Israeli-owned companies operate abroad, mainly in China, Brazil,
the Netherlands, Britain and the United States. He attributed this trend in part to the lack of investment
in infrastructure in Israel. In 2006, Israeli chemical and drug companies made
acquisitions abroad worth $1.5 billion, bringing the total in
the past 12 years to $12.5 billion. "This is money not being invested in Israel," he said.
He said to accelerate growth in the industry, the government
must spend more on infrastructure, increase aid for capital
investment, enact legislation for environmental regulation and
overcome delays in distributing natural gas to Israel's
industry.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/israel-chemicals-drugs-idUSL0366865220070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>israel chemical , drug exports to rise 15 pct in 2007</title></story></items>