<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:40 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LOS ANGELES Ben Stiller led the North American 
box office for a second weekend with "Night at the Museum," 
while Will Smith began 2007 on a good note as he logged his 
tenth $100 million movie. According to studio estimates issued on Monday, "Night at 
the Museum" earned $46.7 million during the four days beginning 
on December 29. After 11 days, the family comedy has earned 
$125.8 million. Stiller plays a security guard at a museum where the 
exhibits -- such as dinosaurs and Roman armies -- come to life 
at night. The family comedy, released by News Corp.'s 20th 
Century Fox, is based on a 32-page illustrated book by Milan 
Trenc. Smith's former chart-topper "The Pursuit of Happyness" 
followed at No. 2 for a second weekend with $24.7 million. 
After three weekends, its total stands at $103.7 million. The 
acclaimed rags-to-riches tale was released by Sony Corp.'s 
Columbia Pictures, which has handled five of Smith's $100 
million movies. "Dreamgirls," a musical loosely based on the story of 
Motown hitmakers the Supremes, jumped four places to No. 3 with 
a four-day sum of $18.7 million. The total for the Paramount 
Pictures film stands at $41.6 million after just eight days in 
national release. The movie widened to 852 theaters on Christmas day after a 
week of special engagements in New York, Los Angeles and San 
Francisco. It will expand to about 1,800 theaters on January 
12, three days before the Golden Globe Awards where it will 
compete for five trophies. (By contrast, "Museum" and 
"Happyness" are playing in 3,768 theaters and 2,870 theaters 
respectively.) Paramount's family movie "Charlotte's Web" rose one place 
to No. 4 with $15.1 million. The adaptation of the E.B. White 
barnyard tale has earned $55.9 million after three weekends. 
Paramount is a unit of Viacom Inc. "The Good Shepherd," a spy drama directed by Robert De 
Niro, slipped one place to No. 5 with $14.3 million. The film, 
which stars Matt Damon and Angelina Jolie, has earned $38.3 
million after two weeks. It was released by Universal Pictures, 
a unit of General Electric Co.'s NBC Universal. Rounding out the top-10 were Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer's "Rocky 
Balboa" with $13.7 million, Fox's "Eragon" with $10.6 million, 
the Warner Bros. Pictures pair of "We Are Marshall" with $10.2 
million and "Happy Feet" with $9.7 million, and Columbia's "The 
Holiday" with $8.5 million. Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer is closely 
held; Warner Bros. is a unit of Time Warner Inc.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/film-boxoffice-dc-idUSN3125640520070103</link><sectors><value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>Film</value></value></sectors><title>stiller , smith achieve box office milestones</title></story></items>