<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:12 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 U.S. government bond prices
edged up  on Wednesday as traders braced for a reading of
private-sector employment that could offer clues about Friday's
widely watched monthly payrolls report. The market will also consider a reading on the health of
manufacturing when the Institute for Supply Management releases
its December index. Economists expect the index to show a
contraction for the second straight month. But first investors will look at the December jobs report
from ADP Employer Services, a private employment service, due
at 8:15 a.m. (1315 GMT). Economists expect the report to show
the economy created 128,000 private-sector jobs last month,
according to a median forecast in a Reuters survey. The forecast for non-farm payrolls on Friday is for a rise
of 110,000 jobs in the overall economy. The ADP report "is seen as a useful guide to the
private-sector non-farm payroll change that will be contained
in this Friday's U.S. jobs data," wrote analysts with Brown
Brothers Harriman in a research note. In December, Treasury bonds experienced their sharpest
sell-off in nine months as stronger-than-expected economic data
prompted investors to rethink expectations for an early cut in
official interest rates. Even so, the market could rebound this
week if fresh data proved softer than expected, analysts said. "The Fed seems to be on firm hold for the next several
months, but that is already factored into prices," wrote David
Ader, head of government bond strategy with RBS Greenwich
Capital in Greenwich, Connecticut, in a daily research note. Early in New York, benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR were
up 2/32 in price for a yield of 4.68 percent, versus 4.68
percent late on Tuesday. Bond yields and prices move
inversely. Two-year notes US2YT=RR -- which respond closely to
expectations for Federal Reserve interest rate moves -- rose
2/32 in price for a yield of 4.78 percent, compared with 4.80
percent on Tuesday. At 10:00 a.m. (1500 GMT) the ISM releases its December
manufacturing index. The median forecast of economists in a
Reuters is for a reading of 49.9. A reading of less than 50
indicates contraction. On Tuesday, volumes slowed to a trickle as the United
States observed a day of mourning for former President Gerald
Ford. But most traders and the bulk of usual bond market volume
are likely to return on Wednesday. (Ana Nicolaci da Costa in London contributed to this
report)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-bonds-idUSN0337247820070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - prices edge up ahead of private jobs data</title></story></items>