<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>07:57 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>  (Updates prices, adds fresh quotes) By Carolyn CohnLONDON Jan 3 (Reuters) - The yen hit a record low against
the euro on Wednesday as investors flocked to higher-yielding
currencies, while the dollar strengthened across the board ahead
of minutes of the latest Federal Reserve meeting. The yen also hit two-month lows against the dollar and
multi-year lows against sterling and the Australian dollar due
to the impact of carry trades, using low-yielding currencies
like the yen to fund purchases of higher-yielding assets. The euro has hit successive record highs against the yen in
recent weeks, as investors look for a quicker pace of monetary
tightening in the euro zone than in Japan. "It's largely a carry trade story," said Antje Praefcke,
currency strategist at Commerzbank in Frankfurt. "People are also expecting slightly hawkish comments from
the Fed." A holiday in Tokyo kept liquidity thin, analysts added. By 1241 GMT, the euro had hit a record peak of 158.04
EURJPY= according to Reuters data, its fourth record high in a
week, with technical analysts looking for the pair to break
160/161 yen in coming weeks. The euro also hit its highest level against the Swiss franc
in almost seven years. "The euro zone has stronger inflation so there is not as
compelling a case for the BOJ (Bank of Japan) to hike rates as
there is for the ECB (European Central Bank)," said Daragh
Maher, currency strategist at Calyon. The ECB is expected to raise borrowing costs to 3.75 percent
in coming months from the current 3.5. Japanese rates are seen rising at a very gradual pace from
0.25 percent, maintaining the euro's yield advantage. The dollar rose half a percent to its highest level since
late October at 119.45 yen JPY=, and also hit nine-month highs
against the lower-yielding Canadian dollar CAD=. The dollar also rose against the euro, with the single
currency falling a third of a percent on the day to $1.3233
EUR=, more than half a cent below three-week highs set in the
previous session. But the high-yielding Australian dollar hit a one-year high
against the U.S. dollar AUD=.
 U.S. DATA Minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's latest rate-setting
meeting at 1900 GMT were seen casting light on current thinking
for the U.S. rate outlook, with analysts widely expecting that
the next move in borrowing costs will be a cut. Fed officials have been talking tough on inflation even as
the market bet on rate cuts, and dollar bears will be looking
for any hint of a softer tone, after the Fed left rates
unchanged at 5.25 percent last month. The Institute for Supply Management's December reading on
the U.S. manufacturing sector is also due, while Friday brings
the non-farm payrolls report for December. A reading below 50 in the ISM index, which dipped below the
boom-or-bust level for the first time in three-and-a-half years
in November, would reinforce concerns about an economic
slowdown. The ISM is forecast to give a reading of 49.9. Other U.S. data due on Wednesday includes the ADP December
employment report at 1315 GMT, often seen as a precursor to
Friday's payrolls data. The survey is forecast to show 128,000 jobs created in
December, from 158,000 in November.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSL0390843520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - euro / yen at record peak , dlr up before fed minutes</title></story></items>