<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:29 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TORONTO Jan 3 The Toronto Stock Exchange's
main index could give up ground on Wednesday as the market's
key energy and gold sectors face pressure from initial declines
in underlying commodity prices. With both oil and gold easing in early morning trade, the
S&amp;P/TSX composite index .GSPTSE could cut some of the modest
gains it booked on Tuesday. It ended the first session of 2007
with a modest gain of 15.27 points, or 0.1 percent, at
12,923.66. "Oil and gold coming off is probably good for the American
market and for general attitudes," said Douglas Davis,
president at investment counsel firm Davis-Rea Ltd. "It's not
so great for the Canadian market overall, so we may be off a
bit." Crude declined to below $60.50 a barrel in early trade on
Wednesday as mild weather in the U.S. Northeast reduced demand
for heating oil. Gold also inched lower, as investors took
profits and the U.S. dollar rose marginally against the euro. A higher U.S. dollar means gold is more expensive to buy
for holders of other currencies and can curb demand for the
precious metal. Weakness in oil and gold could mean that the share prices
of the companies that drill and mine the commodities could see
declines. Since the Toronto index is heavily weighted in those
sectors, the broader composite could ease as well. Davis, however, suggested the TSX will still push ahead
during at least the first three months of the year. "I think it probably will go up in the first quarter, but
then we'll be looking to consolidate somewhat," he said, adding
a pullback later in the year is possible. The main Toronto index returned 14.5 percent in 2006 and
investors are seen as confident both in the market and in the
broader economy. U.S. markets will resume trading on Wednesday after
exchanges stayed shut on Tuesday to mark a day of mourning for
the death of former U.S. President Gerald Ford. Since the last week of December, trading volumes both in
Canada and the United States have been thin as investors and
money managers extended holiday breaks. Volumes are expected to
begin growing this week before returning to fuller levels later
this month. ($1=$1.17 Canadian)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-canada-stocks-idUSN0337863720070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>oil , gold may put pressure on toronto stocks</title></story></items>