<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:42 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> TORONTO, Jan 3 The Canadian dollar fell hard
versus the U.S. dollar on Wednesday as commodity prices turned
lower while a slew of market players adjusted positions
according to recent economic data after the holiday break. Domestic bonds prices were higher ahead of U.S. data  that
could offer clues on the direction of U.S. interest rates. At 8:35 a.m. (1335 GMT), the Canadian unit was at C$1.1695
to the U.S. dollar, or 85.51 U.S. cents, down from C$1.1636 to
the U.S. dollar, or 85.94 U.S. cents, at Tuesday's close. The Canadian dollar fell as low as C$1.1700 to the U.S.
dollar earlier as investors focused on recent U.S. data that
suggested the U.S. Federal Reserve may hold rates steady for a
longer period than many expected. "The data coming out of the States over the last couple of
weeks has been quite good but the market's been in flow mode
because of all the holidays," said Steven Butler, director of
foreign exchange at Scotia Capital." "Today's the first day that the market's been back to full
strength so we'll have to see if we start to get a better feel
for what's actually going on in the world." The Canadian dollar was also hurt by a drop in commodity
prices as mild weather in the U.S. Northeast shook oil prices
and a bout of profit-taking hit gold prices after they came
close to a one-month higher. The Canadian dollar often shadows the moves in oil and gold
prices since Canada is a producer and net exporter of oil and
many base metals. January is expected to be a volatile month for currency
markets as it marks the start of a new financial year for most
people and many investors are putting off positions. "You don't want to bet the farm on a trend emerging in the
first week or two," said Butler. "I think by the end of January
we'll probably have a much better feel for how Q1 is going to
shape up." BONDS RISE Canadian bond prices were higher, but with no domestic data
on tap dealers were waiting to see reports out of the United
States as well as minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's
latest rate-setting meeting. The economic calendar in Canada picks up on Thursday with
November producer and raw materials prices, as well as jobs
figures for December and the December Ivey Purchasing Managers
index on Friday. The two-year bond climbed 4 Canadian cents to C$100.50 to
yield 3.976 percent, while the 10-year bond rose 18 Canadian
cents to C$99.72 to yield 4.036 percent. The yield spread between the two-year and 10-year bond
moved to 5.7 basis points from 6.4 at the previous close. The 30-year bond rose 35 Canadian cents to C$126.50 to
yield 4.098 percent. In the United States, the 30-year treasury
yielded 4.755 percent. The three-month when-issued T-bill yielded 4.15 percent,
unchanged the previous close.
































</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-canada-dollar-bonds-idUSN0338120320070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>canada dlr weighed down by commodities , bonds up</title></story></items>