<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>08:54 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds Wal-Mart rising before the bell, updates prices) By Caroline ValetkevitchNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. stocks were set to begin
2007 higher on Wednesday, with shares of Home Depot Inc. (HD.N)
jumping after the resignation of its chairman and chief
executive and lower oil prices helping the economic outlook. Shares of Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT.N) also rose before the
opening bell after the retailer estimated over the weekend that
December same-store sales rose more than expected in the
crucial holiday shopping period. For details, see
[ID:nN30286457] Home Depot shares rose after the home-improvement chain
said Chief Executive and Chairman Robert Nardelli will leave
the company. [nN03383942] Home Depot shares gained 6.2 percent
to $42.66 in electronic composite trading. Calling Nardelli's departure "bullish," Michael Metz, chief
investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co., New York, said, "I
think it's a response to very strong pressure by shareholders
who are dissatisfied. It also raises a question that maybe this
company is for sale." S&amp;P 500 futures SPc1 were up 7.6 points, above fair
value, a mathematical formula that evaluates pricing by taking
into account interest rates, dividends and time to expiration
on the contract. Dow Jones industrial average futures DJc1 rose 66 points,
and Nasdaq 100 NDc1 futures gained 15.75 points. S&amp;P futures briefly pared gains after the ADP National
Employment report showed a surprise decline in private sector
jobs in December. The market was closed on Monday for the New Year's holiday
and again on Tuesday to observe a national day of mourning for
former U.S. President Gerald Ford. Crude oil slipped toward $60 a barrel as mild weather in
the U.S. Northeast lessened demand for fuel there.
[ID:nSP161243]. Nardelli leaves as Home Depot faces a regulatory probe over
its options pricing practices and increased investor scrutiny
amid falling earnings. In other Wal-Mart news, The Wall Street Journal reported
the discount retailer would start moving many of its 1.3
million workers from predictable shifts to a system based on
how many customers are in stores at a given time. The changes could increase employees' productivity and
customer satisfaction, the report said. Wal-Mart shares rose 2
percent to $47.10 in electronic trade. Also on the economic agenda, the Institute for Supply
Management releases its December manufacturing index at 10 a.m.
(1500 GMT). Economists in a Reuters survey expect a median
reading of 49.9 versus 49.5 in November. At the same time, the Commerce Department releases November
construction spending. Economists in a Reuters survey forecast
a median decline of 0.5 percent compared with a 1.0 percent
drop in October. The Federal Open Market Committee issues
minutes from its Dec. 12 meeting at 2 p.m. (1900 GMT)
 (Additional reporting by Ellis Mnyandu)











</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-stocks-idUSN0337551220070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>us stocks - wall street set to start new year higher</title></story></items>