<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:48 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>  (Adds quotes, details) By Fang YanSHANGHAI Jan 4 (Reuters) - Hyundai Motor Co.'s (005380.KS)
Chinese joint venture missed its 2006 sales target on fierce
market competition and sees slower growth this year due largely
to capacity restraints, a company executive said on Thursday. Beijing Hyundai Automotive Corp., a 50-50 joint venture
between South Korea's biggest auto maker and Beijing Automotive,
sold roughly 290,000 cars last year, 10,000 units shy of its
earlier target of 300,000 units, the executive said. Sales are estimated to climb only 6.9 percent to 310,000
units in 2007, mainly due to limited capacity, said the
executive, who asked not to be identified. Such growth would be considerably slower than the venture's
24 percent sales increase seen in 2006, and the 15 percent growth
expected for the China car market in 2007. "We are adding capacity now but it won't be available this
year," the executive told Reuters. Beijing Hyundai, based in the Chinese capital, has a designed
annual capacity of 300,000 vehicles. It is building a second
plant in the city, to add 200,000 units of capacity by early
2008, increasing to 300,000 units by the end of that year. But until then, the venture would not aggressively roll out
new models -- an effective way to lure customers in the world's
second-largest and hotly-contested auto market, another company
executive said. Hyundai, which competes with Toyota Motor Corp. (7203.T) and
others in China, had made headway in Beijing and surrounding
areas, helped largely by its hot-selling mid-range Elantra sedan. However, it has seen weaker sales in Shanghai, the homebase
of the local ventures of Volkswagen AG (VOWG.DE) and General
Motors Corp. (GM.N), where many local buyers favour Santana and
Excelle over the Hyundai Accent. Globally, the South Korean automaker moved an estimated 2.5
million cars in 2006, lower than its target of 2.69 million
units, hit by unionised workers' strikes.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/hyundai-chinasales-idUSSHA17012320070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - hyundai motor china jv sees slow 2007 sales rise</title></story></items>