<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:04 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates prices, adds comment) By John ParryNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. government bond prices
rallied on Wednesday after a surprise contraction in a private
sector jobs release hinted the nonfarm payrolls report on
Friday could prove soft. Bond prices rose on what analysts said could be the start
of a rethink of the view that the U.S. economy remained
resilient. A string of recent firmer-than-expected data hit the
bond market in December, which suffered its sharpest selloff in
nine months. Bond investors were also turning their sights to a pivotal
national manufacturing report due at 10 a.m. (1500 GMT) and to
minutes from the Federal Reserve's December policy-setting
meeting, due at 2 p.m. (1900 GMT). "Clearly, going into the employment data this Friday,
people coming into the New Year with a clean book would
certainly feel that this (the ADP report) is something people
want to be buying bonds on", said Michael Cheah, vice president
and portfolio manager with AIG SunAmerica Asset Management in
Jersey City. U.S. private sector employment likely declined by 40,000 in
December, the first contraction since April 2003, according to
the ADP National Employment Report. Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR rose 8/32 in price for
a yield of 4.65 percent, compared with 4.68 percent just before
the ADP report and versus 4.68 percent late on Tuesday. Bond
yields and prices move inversely. Flat positioning and prices at the low end of recent ranges
helped set the stage for bonds to rally on the weak data, Cheah
added. Two-year notes US2YT=RR -- which respond closely to
expectations for Federal Reserve interest rate moves -- rose
3/32 in price for a yield of 4.75 percent, versus 4.78 percent
before the ADP report and compared with 4.80 percent on
Tuesday. ADP's employment report "is seen as a useful guide to the
private sector nonfarm payroll change that will be contained in
this Friday's U.S. jobs data," wrote analysts with Brown
Brothers Harriman in a daily research note. At 10:00 a.m. the Institute for Supply Management releases
its December manufacturing index. Economists in a Reuters
survey expect a median reading of 49.9 in December, which would
mark its second straight month of contraction, a reading under
50. The ADP report is a hint that employment could be taking a
turn for the worse in the broad economy, which may yet feel the
full effect of a downturn in the housing sector and some areas
of manufacturing, some said. "The report is another reminder that we still have the
housing thing hanging around our necks. We have yet to see the
shedding of construction and housing-related jobs," Cheah
said. The 30-year bond US30YT=RR rose 14/32 in price for a
yield of 4.76 percent, versus 4.79 percent late on Tuesday.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-bonds-idUSN0338750320070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - rally on shrinking private jobs ; ism awaited</title></story></items>