<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:08 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> Thursday, April 26 NEW YORK - Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco President
Janet Yellen speaks before the Money Marketeers of New York
University. Time, location, other details TBA. Information:
here Tuesday, May 22 NEW YORK - Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond President
Jeffrey Lacker speaks before the Money Marketeers of New York
University. Time, location, other details TBA. Information:
here
------------------------------------------------------------- FED MONTHLY REPORTS Monday, January 8
 ***WASHINGTON (Tentative) - Federal Reserve releases November
consumer credit figures, 1500 EST/2000 GMT Thursday, January 11
 ***PHILADELPHIA - Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia issues
historical revisions to its monthly business outlook survey. Tuesday, January 16
 ***NEW YORK - Federal Reserve Bank of New York issues monthly
Empire State Manufacturing Survey, 0830 EST/1330 GMT Wednesday, January 17
 ***WASHINGTON - Federal Reserve releases December industrial
production and capacity utilization data, 0915 EST/1415 GMT Thursday, January 18
 ***CLEVELAND - Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland releases its
monthly median Consumer Price Index, a weighted median of the
CPI issued by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, no set time.
 ***PHILADELPHIA - Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia
releases its monthly business outlook survey, 1200 EST/1700
GMT. Monday, January 22
 ***CHICAGO - Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago issues monthly
Chicago Fed National Activity Index on current state of U.S.
economic activity and inflationary pressures, 0730 CST/0830
EST/1330 GMT. NOTE: Time of release changed from 0900 CST/1000
EST/1500 GMT beginning with this report Tuesday, January 23
 ***RICHMOND, Va. - Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond releases
monthly manufacturing and services indices, 1000 EST/1500 GMT. Thursday, January 25
 ***KANSAS CITY, Mo. - Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City
releases its manufacturing index for the tenth Fed district for
January, 1000 CST/1100 EST/1600 GMT. Monday, January 29
 ***DALLAS - Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas issues Texas
Manufacturing Outlook Survey for January, 0930 CST/1030
EST/1530 GMT.
 ***CHICAGO - Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago releases the
Midwest Manufacturing Index, 1100 CST/1200 EST/1700 GMT.
----------------------------------------------------------- FED QUARTERLY REPORTS Tuesday, February 13 PHILADELPHIA - Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia
releases quarterly Survey of Professional Forecasters, 1000
EST/1500 GMT.
--------------------------------------------------------- OTHER FED REPORTS BEIGE BOOK (Wednesday dates, except where noted)
 ***2007 (For release at 1400 EST/1900 GMT): January 17; March 7 (For release at 1400 EDT/1800 GMT): April 25; June 13; July 25; September 5; October 17 (For release at 1400 EST/1900 GMT): November 28
--------------------------------------------------------- FED WEEKLY DATA Every Monday (except federal holidays) WASHINGTON - Federal Reserve releases weekly selected
interest rates, no set time. Every Thursday (except federal holidays) NEW YORK - Federal Reserve releases weekly money supply and
other weekly Fed banking statistics, 1630 EST/2130 GMT Every Friday (except federal holidays) WASHINGTON - Federal Reserve releases weekly assets and
liabilities of commercial banks figures, 1615 EST/2115 GMT.
------------------------------------------------------------- FOMC MINUTES FROM MEETINGS 2007 dates: (For release at 1400 EST/1900 GMT):
 ***Wednesday, January 3 (for December 12 meeting). NOTE:
Delayed from January 2 due to Gerald R. Ford national day of
mourning Wednesday, February 21 (for January 30-31 meeting) (For release at 1400 EDT/1800 GMT): Wednesday, April 11 (for March 20-21 meeting) Wednesday, May 30 (for May 9 meeting) Thursday, July 19 (for June 27-28 meeting) Tuesday, August 28 (for August 7 meeting) Tuesday, October 9 (for September 18 meeting) (For release at 1400 EST/1900 GMT): Wednesday, November 21 (for October 30-31 meeting) 2008 dates: Wednesday, January 2 (for December 11 meeting)
--------------------------------------------------------- NOTES: Eastern Standard Time through March 30, 2007 (five-hour
time difference EST/GMT) Eastern Daylight Time resumes April 1, 2007 (four-hour time
difference EDT/GMT) Eastern Standard Time resumes October 28, 2007 (five-hour
time difference EDT/GMT)
--------------------------------------------------------- VOTING MEMBERS: 2007 Federal Reserve Bank of New York President Timothy
Geithner Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago President Michael Moskow Federal Reserve Bank of Boston President Cathy Minehan Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis President William Poole Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City President Thomas
Hoenig 2008 Federal Reserve Bank of New York President Timothy
Geithner Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland President Sandra
Pianalto Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia President Charles
Plosser Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas President Richard Fisher Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis President Gary Stern 2009 Federal Reserve Bank of New York President Timothy
Geithner Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago President Michael Moskow Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond President Jeffrey Lacker Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta president TBA Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco President Janet
Yellen
---------------------------------------------------------



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/diary-fed-idUSN243477020070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>diary - federal reserve events</title></story></items>