<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>00:53 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Boat dealers at the New York National Boat Show are upbeat about 2007 sales after a record year for Wall Street bonuses and the blue-chip Dow Jones industrial average.More than 1,000 boats are on display at the show, including the MTI Mojo used in the film "Miami Vice." The 39-foot speedboat, still awaiting a buyer, was on sale for $699,000.Among the most gawked-at attractions was the Cruisers Yacht 520 Express, a $1.1 million yacht with a cherry wood interior, a cockpit bar and grill, and therapeutic foam mattresses in each stateroom.Unlike car shows, boat shows are designed to move inventory as well as display the industry's latest models.The show, which began on December 30 and runs through January 7, represents a chance for dealers to earn a large chunk of their profits for the year, with companies earning nearly 30 percent of their annual income from the New York show alone, show manager Michael Duffy said."We're encouraged by the economy," said Bob Moseley, a salesman manning the Cruisers Yachts booth."It's looking much stronger than last year with the record-breaking Dow and stable fuel prices," Moseley said.The Dow notched a 16 percent gain for 2006 and oil prices fell below $61 a barrel Tuesday, helped by unseasonably warm weather in the northeastern United States."The outlook is positive for a number of reasons, including the weather," said Allan Valunas, a brokerage consultant at boat retailer MarineMax Inc."Because of the weather, they'll put them in the water sooner," he said, adding that Wall Street's pay bonuses of nearly $24 billion should also be a boon to sales.With five days remaining for the show, Cruisers had sold one 44-foot yacht for $499,000, an exhibitor said.A buyer was also in negotiations to purchase the 57-foot Carver Marquis 55, whose price was listed at $1.25 million, show spokeswoman Raevan Naanen said. The yacht features master and VIP staterooms equipped with LCD TVs, bamboo floors and a spacious galley.Most of those in attendance during the show's first weekend were serious buyers, Naanen said."Last year demand was slow, but it built up," said Steve Schwartz, a salesman working the Silverton booth.Silverton sold five boats over the weekend, Schwartz said.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-boatshow-idUSN0235755920070103</link><sectors><value><value>U.S.</value></value></sectors><title>luxury yacht dealers see strong sales in 2007</title></story></items>