<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:32 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>An Indonesian plane with 102 people on board was still missing on Wednesday, while a search continued for more than 400 people missing after a ferry sank in stormy seas off the main island of Java late last week.Here is an overview of some of the worst disasters to hit Indonesia over the last two years.* TSUNAMI: December 26, 2004: Giant waves kill nearly 132,000 Indonesians and leave 37,000 missing after a massive earthquake in the Indian Ocean creates the world's most deadly tsunami. At least 231,127 lives are lost across coastal Indonesia, Sri Lanka and India, dwarfing the previous worst death toll of 36,380 killed in Sumatra and Java by an 1883 tsunami.* MUDFLOW: May 2006: Around 10,000 people are displaced after a torrent of unstoppable hot mud gushes from the ground in East Java, following a May 2006 drilling accident. The environmental disaster swamps entire villages in the Sidoarjo area, near Indonesia's second largest city, Surabaya.* EARTHQUAKE: May 27, 2006: Some 6,000 people are killed and 200,000 left homeless after a magnitude 6.3 quake strikes central Java, in Indonesia's worst disaster since the 2004 tsunami. On March 28, 2005, another earthquake kills some 900 people on Nias island off the western coast of Sumatra island.* PLANE CRASH: September 5, 2005: Some 102 passengers and 47 people on the ground are killed in the inferno when a Boeing 737-200 belonging to Indonesian carrier Mandala Airlines crashes in a residential area of Medan, the country's third-biggest city.* BIRD FLU: July 20, 2005: The country confirms its first bird flu death, a year and a half after the World Health Organization records the initial outbreaks in Vietnam in 2004. Indonesia subsequently becomes the worst hit by the virus, with 57 people dead, just under a third of the global tally.* TERROR ATTACK: October 1, 2005: Twenty-three people are killed when three bombs rip through popular tourist areas in south Bali. The attack is the deadliest since 202 people were killed in the country's worst-ever terror attack, also in Bali, in 2002.Sources: Reuters, WHO (www.who.int)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-indonesia-disasters-idUSSP13364820070103</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>factbox - indonesia ' s worst post - tsunami disasters</title></story></items>