<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:14 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>  (Updates prices, changes dateline, previous LONDON)NEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - The dollar pared earlier gains
on Wednesday after a survey showed that employment in the U.S.
private sector contracted unexpectedly in December. The greenback retreated after the ADP National Employment
Report showed that private-sector jobs likely declined 40,000
in the month, the first contraction since April 2003 and flying
in the face of consensus forecasts for a solid rise in jobs. The soft report led some traders to speculate that the more
closely watched nonfarm payrolls report -- due from the
government on Friday -- could also come in softer than
expectations. "It points to a pretty poor payroll number on Friday, so I
think we'll see some revisions to the expectations for that
number," said Shaun Osborne, senior currency strategist at TD
Securities in Toronto. A weak reading in that payrolls report would likely
strengthen the view that the Federal Reserve may start cutting
interest rates in coming months to shore up a slowing economy. The euro was trading down 0.2 percent on the day at $1.3248
EUR= in early New York, compared to around $1.3130 before the
release of the ADP report. The dollar was up 0.35 percent at
119.22 yen, short of a high of 119.46 hit earlier in the
session. The market's reaction the ADP report was somewhat muted,
however, with the Institute for Supply Management due to
release its closely watched reading on the manufacturing sector
at 10:00 am (1500 GMT). Economists in a Reuters survey expect a December reading of
49.9 on the median. That would mark the second straight month
the index has come in below 50, indicating a contraction. The
November report showed the first contraction in the
manufacturing sector in 3-1/2 years.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSN0332330720070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - dollar pares gains on weak adp jobs report</title></story></items>