<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>00:46 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>PERTH Mark Philippoussis has been ruled out of this month's Australian Open after a scan revealed he had torn knee cartilage in his Hopman Cup match in Perth on Tuesday.The 30-year-old Australian, who would have needed a wildcard to play at the Melbourne Park grand slam, had a scan on Wednesday and was diagnosed with a torn lateral meniscus cartilage in his right knee and will require surgery. "I knew something was terribly wrong," a forlorn, wheelchair-bound Philippoussis told reporters at a news conference."I went for a wide one and knew I had done something wrong straight away. I woke up this morning at 6 a.m. and I could not move my knee and I'm still in a lot of pain."The world number 114 confirmed he would be undergoing surgery in Sydney on Thursday and made no predictions about a possible return to the court."This is another setback and something I've got to deal with. It's difficult to get excited to talk about getting back and the rehabilitation, but one thing I know is I'm going to take care of it."The former Wimbledon and U.S. Open finalist, who had surgery three times on his left knee between 1999 and 2001, jarred his knee while reaching for a backhand in the fourth game of his match against France's Jerome Haehnel in Perth.OBVIOUS PAINIn obvious pain and restricted heavily by the injury, Philippoussis finally called it quits at 1-4 after losing his serve to love in front of a packed house at Burswood Dome.Haehnel was awarded the match and the mixed doubles ruled a walkover, giving France a 3-0 victory over the hosts.World number 162 Nathan Healey will take Philippoussis's place for Australia's final group match against the U.S. on Thursday.Philippoussis was hoping for a solid performance this week to earn a wildcard for the Australian Open starting on January 15, but will now miss the year's first grand slam in his home town.He had seen his world ranking slump to 205 in February 2005 after further surgery on his groin but recovered to end 2006 as the number 114 after taking the title at Newport, Rhode Island in July.It was the third time Philippoussis had withdrawn from the Hopman Cup, the groin problem curtailing his 2005 bid and shin splint soreness forcing him to retire in the 2000 competition, the year after he had won it with Jelena Dokic.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-tennis-philippoussis-idUSSP14719620070103</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>philippoussis out of australian open</title></story></items>