<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:43 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 3 The dollar pared gains on
Wednesday, while bonds rose after an unexpected drop in U.S.
private sector jobs hinted that a key employment report on
Friday might prove soft and fuel talk of an interest rate cut. The monthly ADP National Employment Report showed that a
40,000 decline in December was the first since early 2003,
according to a graph released with the report.  Private sector employers added 158,000 jobs in November and
the median forecast from 10 economists surveyed by Reuters had
pointed to a rise of 128,000 jobs in the December ADP report. The dollar pared earlier gains, leaving the euro EUR= down
0.25 percent on the day after the ADP report. Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR rose 9/32 in price for a
yield of 4.65 percent, versus 4.67 percent just before the data,
while European government bond futures also gained -- the March
Bund future FGBLH7 jumped to a day's high of 116.46 after the
report was released. The S&amp;P 500 .SPX opened up 0.49 points at 1.418.79, with
stock futures having pared gains on the jobs report before the
bell. "This is the first negative reading from ADP since early
2003," HSBC U.S. economist Ian Morris said in a note to clients.
But he left unchanged a forecast of a rise in Friday's non-farm
payroll count. "We'll stick to our call of 70,000 (consensus
120,000), which is already suggesting some softening of the
labor market," he said. Markets' reaction to the surprise fall in the ADP employment
report was limited, however, as investors were awaiting a key
measure of manufacturing activity which could shed further light
on the timing of a possible cut in U.S. borrowing costs. The Institute for Supply Management's December reading on
the U.S. manufacturing sector is due at 1500 GMT. A reading
below 50 on the ISM index, which dipped under the mark that
divides growth from contraction for the first time in 3-1/2
years in November, may reinforce concerns about an economic
slowdown. Mellon Bank's head of currency research Ian Gunner noted
that the picture of a softer U.S. manufacturing sector had
appeared in other data in recent weeks, with a negative
Philadelphia Fed balance and declines in business sales and core
durable goods orders.  "Key now is whether this is just a blip or the start of
something more serious and the market will be sensitive to any
news that offers strong support to either of these scenarios,"
Gunner said. Minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's latest interest
rate-setting meeting due at 1900 GMT were also seen casting
light on current thinking for the rate outlook. Fed officials have been talking tough on inflation even as
the market bet on rate cuts from the current 5.25 percent and
dollar bears will be looking for any hint of a softer tone. Global market liquidity remained thinner than normal as
Japanese markets were closed for the New Year break. U.S. stock
markets were shut on Tuesday to mark the death of former U.S.
President Gerald Ford. (Reporting by Veronica Brown; editing by David Stamp; email:
veronica.brown@reuters.com; Reuters Messaging:
veronica.brown.reuters.com@reuters.net; Tel + 44 20 7542 6745))</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-global-idUSL0353387320070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>global markets - dlr pares gains , bonds up , us data in focus</title></story></items>