<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>09:25 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK U.S. private sector employment 
contracted in December, the first time since April 2003, a 
private employment service report showed on Wednesday. The monthly ADP National Employment Report showed private 
sector employers shed 40,000 jobs after adding 158,000 jobs in 
November. The report is based on payroll data and measures the 
change in total private sector nonfarm employment each month. "These findings suggest an abrupt slowing of employment, 
following three months during which, according to the ADP 
National Employment Report, gains in private nonfarm employment 
averaged 121,000 per month," said Joel Prakken, chairman of 
Macroeconomic Advisers. The median forecast for the ADP report from 10 economists 
surveyed by Reuters pointed to a reading of gains of 128,000 
jobs for the December. Government bond prices rallied on the report, which hinted 
that the government's closely watched nonfarm payrolls report 
for December, due on Friday, might prove soft, although 
economist debate the extent of the correlation between the two 
reports. "This is a big surprise ... there is no evidence of 
systematic problems in the ADP survey," said Ian Shepherdson, 
chief U.S. economist at High Frequency economics in New York. 
He said his firm would cut its estimate for the Labor 
Department's report to 75,000 jobs created, from an original 
estimate of 100,000. "ADP is not perfect and is sometimes horribly wrong, but it 
is the best of a bad bunch of payroll indicators and cannot be 
completely ignored." According to the latest Reuters poll of economists, 
Friday's report is expected to show that 110,000 nonfarm 
payroll jobs were created in December, down from 132,000 in 
November. Investors will be looking to the nonfarm payrolls report 
for clues on the timing of the first interest rate cut after 
the Federal Reserve tightened monetary policy 17 times between 
June 2004 and June 2006.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/businesspro-usa-economy-employment-adp-d-idUSN0338518420070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>private sector shed 40 , 000 jobs in dec : report</title></story></items>