<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:17 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK The U.S. industrial sector expanded again in December, defying predictions for another modest contraction, according to data on Wednesday that calmed fears of a sharper slowdown in factory activity.  KEY POINTS: - The Institute for Supply Management index of national factory activity climbed to 51.4 from 49.5 in November, above the 50-threshold that separates growth from contraction. - Wall Street forecasts centered around 49.9. - The survey's employment measure was still below 50 at 49.7, but higher than November's 49.2. - The prices paid index, which measures inflation pressures at the industrial level, fell to 47.5 from 53.5, while the new orders index climbed to 52.1 from 48.7. COMMENTARY:BORIS SCHLOSSBERG, SENIOR CURRENCY STRATEGIST, FOREX CAPITAL MARKETS, NEW YORK:"The fact that ISM came back above 50 puts the whole soft-landing, dollar-positive scenario back in play. But that said, we still think a more severe slowdown is a likely possibility. The ADP number suggests we are only starting to feel the impact of a slower economy. But this ISM report buys the dollar some breathing room for the next couple of days before the big event risk of nonfarm payrolls on Friday."JOHN SPINELLO, TREASURY BOND STRATEGIST, JEFFERIES &amp; CO., NEW YORK:"Treasuries sold off from the highs. Production was higher and new orders were higher. The market for now is focusing on the headline (ISM reading), with 10-year notes selling off about 6/32 (from price highs). It is probably enough to take a little bit of the edge off the upside, which we got on the ADP number."ROBERT MACINTOSH, CHIEF ECONOMIST, EATON VANCE MANAGEMENT, BOSTON:"The manufacturing index itself was up above October so that confirms the little bit of firming we thought we had -- it's not huge but economy seems like it has firmed. The fact the price index is down is good news, offsetting negativeness of overall number. For the Fed it's a small piece of data but everything else being equal, this would make them hold off from a cut. The service (index) is 5/6 of economy and will get more attention."PIERRE ELLIS, SENIOR ECONOMIST, DECISION ECONOMICS, NEW YORK:"The rebound in the ISM is broad-based, spanning the important subcomponents and that's significant because it begins to reverse several months' decline in those indexes. Since the ISM is a turning point indicator, we're seeing the downswing reversed. So the apparent slowdown in manufacturing seems more moderate than might have been feared and the breadth of the increase is probably a bit greater than generally looked for. That makes the general economy look steadier and even firmer than it was thought to be."Much the same message is given by the construction spending numbers where you see an ongoing and unsurprising decline in residential spending, but what had appeared to be a deterioration in private non-residential spending is now decisively reversed, reducing a drag on fourth-quarter growth."The Fed has no new reason to be concerned about the downside to economic growth and the situation appears to be the best of all possible worlds with inflation evidently slowing and growth stabilizing at a satisfactory rate." MARKET REACTION: - Bonds: U.S. Treasuries retrace session gains after ISM reading comes in stronger than expected. - Dollar: Rises to session high against the euro and yen. - Stocks: S&amp;P 500 adds about 2 points from pre-ISM level, pushing the index back to near its session high. LINKS: - U.S. December ISM manufacturing index poll story  - For U.S. ISM data, the Web site is: www.ism.ws/</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-usa-economy-ism-mfg-idUSN0339840020070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>instant view 2 - us dec ism mfg index rises , topping expectations</title></story></items>