<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:24 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>AMSTERDAM Jan 3 Philips Electronics (PHG.AS)
(PHG.N) said on Wednesday it had sold the majority of its
"electronic paper" or rollable displays business to Luxembourg
venture capital group, Technology Capital. Technology Capital has invested 21 million euros ($28
million) in Philips' Polymer Vision business, and in return now
holds around 60 percent of the shares in the company. Philips retains 20 percent of the company which has around
30 staff. Employees and management hold the remainder. The company is the first spinout from Philips' Technology
Incubator which was set up four years ago to speed its
technology to the market. Philips no longer sees display
technology as a core activity, having sold its cathode ray tube
and liquid crystal display businesses in recent years. Philips
now focuses on healthcare and lifestyle businesses. Not all companies within the research incubator are sold to
outside companies: one micro laser business was snapped up by
Philips Lighting recently. Polymer Vision produces a paper-like display which can be
rolled out to a greater size than the actual device itself. The
display is easy to read, even in bright sunlight, and has
significantly lower power requirements than a liquid crystal
display with a backlight which is used in today's devices. "Once the user has finished reading, the display can simply
be rolled back into the device. This makes the rollable display
ideal for mobile applications such as mobile phones, document
readers and personal navigation systems," Philips said. Volume production of a 5-inch monochrome rollable display
will start this year in cooperation with existing partners. The
company will continue to operate from its location at the High
Tech Campus Eindhoven, the Netherlands.
 Philips has recently set up two more incubators to market
its technology: one for healthcare and one for lifestyle. Philips is the world's biggest lighting maker, a top three 
hospital equipment maker and Europe's biggest consumer
electronics producer.







</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/philips-rollable-displays-idUSL0377209920070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A</value></value></sectors><title>philips exits its nascent electronic paper business</title></story></items>