<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:18 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 U.S. copper futures started the
new year off down over 6 percent on Wednesday as visible
warehouse supplies rose to a near two-year high, fueling
speculation of a supply glut in the market this year, traders
said. "Stocks were up again today, and we are in sight of the
significant 200,000 a tonne mark on the London Metal Exchange,
with this, no doubt, being the prime catalyst behind the change
in psychology," said Edward Meir, metals analyst with Man
Financial. Copper for March delivery HGH7 sank 19.05 cents, or 6.6
percent, at $2.6805 a lb by 10:11 a.m. EST (1511 GMT) on the
New York Mercantile Exchange's COMEX division, near the bottom
of its early $2.65-$2.7980 trading band. The $2.65 low was the
cheapest price March copper has seen since April of last year. Spot January HGF7 slipped 18.15 cents to trade at its
morning trough at $2.6725. COMEX copper futures volume was estimated at 4,000 lots by
10:00 a.m. The price of copper in New York has erased nearly 16.5
percent of its value since the start of December as steady
builds in stock levels, coupled with softer demand in the U.S.
and China and receding threats of supply disruptions out of
Chile have all contributed to the market's bearish tone,
analysts said. "The stocks keep building. It seems like the supply
problems have been pretty much resolved, leading to greater
availability, and I think people are intent upon liquidating
any excess inventory and moving to more of a hand-to-mouth
fashion that is helping to contribute to the pressure on
copper values," said Steve Platt, an analyst with Archer
Financials in Chicago. Inventory data on Tuesday showed copper stocks at London
Metal Exchange warehouses surge 7,775 tonnes, with an
additional 1,975 tonnes added on Wednesday, bringing total
stocks to 192,550 tonnes -- their highest since March 2004. The almost persistent increases in copper warehouse stocks
were seen as a direct reflection of the market's falling demand
growth. Chinese consumption of refined copper is expected to fall 7
percent this year as higher copper prices were seen dampening
demand. China is forecast to consume 3.4 million tonnes of refined
copper in 2006, compared with a total consumption of 3.67
million tonnes in 2005, the National Development and Reform
Commission said on its Web site. (www.ndrc.gov.cn)[nSHA204175] Meanwhile, Codelco, the world's largest copper producer,
said on Tuesday it had sold 80 percent of its 2007 refined
copper production on the international market.[nN02331044] On the LME, three-months copper MCU3 last traded at
$5,895 a tonne, down $215 from Tuesday's kerb close.




















</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-copper-comex-idUSN0336791520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>comex copper futures begin new year on defensive</title></story></items>