<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:33 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>A state funeral was held in Washington on Tuesday for former U.S. President Gerald Ford, who died a week ago at age 93. Ford took office on August 9, 1974, following Richard Nixon's resignation in the worst U.S. political scandal.Here are some facts about Ford's life and presidency.* Ford pardoned Nixon on September 8, 1974, for any crime he may have committed in office, an act that stunned the nation and stirred enduring controversy. He denied making any deal with Nixon.* He escaped two assassination attempts in a 17-day span in 1975, and served on the Warren Commission which investigated the 1963 assassination of President John Kennedy.* At the Helsinki summit of 1975, Ford and Soviet leader Leonid Brezhnev signed agreements in effect swapping Western acknowledgment of post-war Soviet domination in central Europe for Moscow's vows to liberalize human rights and ease border restrictions.* Ford declared the Vietnam War "finished as far as America is concerned" on April 23, 1975, and the U.S.-backed Saigon government fell one week later. Congress had rejected Ford's last-ditch efforts to boost military aid to Saigon.* Ford represented Michigan in the U.S. House of Representatives from 1949 and rose through Republican ranks to become House minority leader in the 1960s. Nixon named him vice president in 1973 after Spiro Agnew resigned the post in a corruption scandal.* He was the only U.S. president to have assumed office without winning a national election as either president or vice president. He lost to Democrat Jimmy Carter in his 1976 bid for a full term, in one of the closest U.S. elections in U.S. history.* Ford played on the University of Michigan's national championship football teams in 1932 and 1933 and turned down offers to play with the Detroit Lions and Green Bay Packers in the National Football League. Instead he went to Yale University, where he went to law school and served as boxing coach.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-ford-facts-idUSN0234020120070103</link><sectors><value><value>U.S., </value><value>Politics</value></value></sectors><title>factbox - facts about ex - u . s . president gerald ford</title></story></items>