<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:33 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>Quotes from former U.S. President Gerald Ford, who died a week ago and whose state funeral was held in Washington on Tuesday:* "I am a Ford, not a Lincoln."--December 6, 1973, after being sworn in as vice president.* "I have not sought this enormous responsibility but I will not shirk it ... My fellow Americans, our long national nightmare is over. Our Constitution works; our great republic is a government of laws and not of men. Here the people rule."--Aug, 9, 1974, upon being sworn in as president following the resignation of Richard Nixon.* "A government big enough to give you everything you want is a government big enough to take from you everything you have."--August 12, 1974, address to a Congress.* "Theirs is an American tragedy in which we all have played a part. It could go on and on and on, or someone must write the end to it. I have concluded that only I can do that, and if I can, I must."--September 8, 1974, upon granting a pardon to Richard Nixon.* "The establishment of justice and peace abroad will in large measure depend upon the peace and justice we create here in our own country, for we still show the way."--July 4, 1976, on the U.S. bicentennial at Independence Hall in Philadelphia.* "There is no Soviet domination of Eastern Europe and there never will be under a Ford administration."--October 6, 1976, in a presidential campaign debate against Jimmy Carter.* "I can report that the state of the union is good. There is room for improvement, as always, but today we have a more perfect Union than when my stewardship began."--January 12, 1977, in his final State of the Union to Congress.* "I am a loyal Wolverine. When they lose in football, basketball, or anything I still get darn disappointed."--October 8, 1994, newspaper interview before the University of Michigan retired his football number.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-ford-quotes-idUSN0233926220070103</link><sectors><value><value>U.S., </value><value>Politics</value></value></sectors><title>factbox - quotes from former u . s . president gerald ford</title></story></items>