<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:34 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts with reaction to ISM manufacturing data, updates
prices, adds comment) By John Parry NEW YORK, Jan 3 (Reuters) -U.S. government bond prices were
little changed  on Wednesday after a report showed the U.S.
industrial sector bounced back in December, calming earlier
fears raised by an unexpectedly weak private-sector jobs
report. Earlier, Treasuries rallied after a surprise contraction in
a private jobs report hinted the nonfarm payrolls report on
Friday could prove soft and set economists at some Wall Street
banks to cutting their jobs forecasts for Friday's nonfarm
payrolls report. Bond prices rose on what analysts said could be the start
of a reconsideration of the view that the U.S. economy remained
resilient. A string of recent firmer-than-expected data hit the
bond market in December, which suffered its sharpest selloff in
nine months. "The market for now is focusing on the headline (ISM
reading)," said John Spinello, Treasury bond strategist, with
Jefferies &amp; Co. in New York. "Treasuries sold off from the
highs," he said. "It is probably enough to take a little bit of
the edge off the upside, which we got on the ADP (jobs)
number." Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR traded up 4/32 in price
for a yield of 4.67 percent, versus 4.64 percent before the ISM
report and versus 4.68 percent late on Tuesday. Bond yields and
prices move inversely. The Institute for Supply Management's December
manufacturing report reading was 51.4, above the 50 mark that
divides expansion from contraction, and above economists'
forecasts for 49.9, and up from November's 49.5 reading. Earlier data showed that U.S. private sector employment
likely declined by 40,000 in December, the first contraction
since April 2003, according to the ADP National Employment
Report. "Clearly, going into the employment data this Friday,
people coming into the New Year with a clean book would
certainly feel that this (the ADP report) is something people
want to be buying bonds on," said Michael Cheah, vice president
and portfolio manager with AIG SunAmerica Asset Management in
Jersey City. Two-year notes US2YT=RR , which respond closely to
expectations for Federal Reserve interest rate moves, traded up
1/32 in price for a yield of 4.78 percent, versus 4.75 percent
before the ISM report and compared with 4.80 percent on
Tuesday. Bond investors were also turning their sights to minutes
from the Federal Reserve's December policy-setting meeting, due
at 2 p.m. (1900 GMT) for clues to how the Fed views trends in
the economy back in early December.






</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-bonds-idUSN0343909620070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - pare gains on resilient manufacturing data</title></story></items>