<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:37 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds background, analyst comment, byline) By Pedro Nicolaci da Costa NEW YORK, Jan 3 The U.S. industrial sector
bounced back in December, according to data published on
Wednesday, calming fears of a sharper slowdown in factory
activity. The Institute for Supply Management said its index of
national factory activity climbed to 51.4 from 49.5 in November
-- above the 50-threshold that separates growth from
contraction. Wall Street forecasts had centered around 49.9. The figures suggested the economy would kick off the year
on a stronger footing than some had believed. "The apparent slowdown in manufacturing seems more moderate
than might have been feared," said Pierre Ellis, senior
economist at Decision Economics. "That makes the general
economy look steadier and even firmer than it was thought to
be." All news was not positive, however, with the survey's
employment measure still below 50 at 49.7, albeit slightly
higher than November's 49.2. However, the trend was encouraging. The prices paid index,
for instance, which measures industrial inflation pressures,
fell to 47.5 from 53.5, while a measure of new orders climbed
to 52.1 from 48.7. In terms of the outlook for interest rates, the ISM data
bolstered the case for no change in policy from the Federal
Reserve. The central bank has left benchmark rates at 5.25 percent
since June, on the hope that slower economic growth could take
some heat off inflation -- a gamble that seems to have paid off
thus far. The next major insight into the state of the U.S. economy
will come on Friday, when the government releases its
employment report for December. The jobs component of the ISM survey indicates
manufacturing continued to be a drag on the overall health of
the labor market, although Friday's report may show that
last-minute retail hiring to support the holiday shopping
season made up the difference.  
 (additional reporting by Ellen Freilich)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/usa-economy-manufacturing-idUSN0339921420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - u . s . manufacturing growth rebounds in december</title></story></items>