<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:29 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds CSR comment, Broadcom shares) By Lucas van Grinsven, European Technology CorrespondentAMSTERDAM Jan 3 (Reuters) - A U.S. research institute has
sued Nokia (NOK1V.HE), Samsung Electronics (005930.KS) and
Matsushita-owned (6752.T) Panasonic for violating a patent for
Bluetooth technology, potentially putting the free wireless
standard at risk. The Washington Research Foundation, which markets technology
from the University of Washington, is seeking damages from the
three mobile-phone makers for using a radio frequency receiver
technology without paying royalties, according to court papers
obtained by Reuters on Wednesday. A University of Washington scientist Edwin Suominen was
awarded a patent in 1999 for "simplified high-frequency
broadband tuner and tuning method". Bluetooth was invented as a wire replacement by Ericsson
(ERICb.ST) engineer Jaap Haartsen in the mid 1990s and developed
by engineers at Ericsson and four other companies that made it
available at no cost through the Bluetooth Special Interest
Group (SIG). Haartsen told Reuters that others had previously tried
unsuccessfully to claim part of the Bluetooth technology. "We'll have to see how this one pans out," he said before
looking at the claim in detail. Nokia declined to comment. "We are currently studying the
claims," said spokeswoman Eija-Riitta Huovinen. Samsung and
Panasonic were not immediately available to comment. Bluetooth was given away by Ericsson and others to create a
global wireless standard to connect mobile phones, laptops,
headsets and other electronic gadgets wirelessly. Since the
first standard was set in 1998 it has become hugely popular, and
hundreds of millions of devices a year are produced with
Bluetooth capability. "As they say, 'Where there is a hit, there is a writ'," said
analyst Neil Mawston at market research group Strategy
Analytics.
 U.S. IMPACT The claim appears to restrict itself to Bluetooth devices
sold or used in the United States, which means any ruling will
affect around 15 to 20 percent of total global Bluetooth mobile
phone and headset sales in the near-term, Mawston said. "The mobile Bluetooth market in the U.S. is relatively
immature and it is not yet as important to vendors as, say,
Western Europe with 30 to 40 percent of total," he said. But Ben Wood, a mobile telecoms consultant at CCS Insight,
said the implications for the standard could be more serious if
the foundation's claim is successful. "A standard which everyone assumes to be royalty free is now
at risk of becoming a chargeable element inside mobile phones
and other devices," he said. Although the complaint, filed in the United States Western
District Court of Washington State at Seattle, was filed against
the three companies, it targets products containing Bluetooth
chips from British chip maker CSR (CSR.L), which has a world
market share of more than 50 percent. Cambridge-based CSR, which was not sued by the research
group as it does not sell the chips directly in the U.S., said:
"CSR has taken advice from its attorneys. The suit is without
merit in relation to CSR's Bluetooth chips, and CSR will defend
its products vigorously." Its shares lost as much as 6.6 percent but recovered most of
the early losses after its reaction. They were down 2.9 percent
at 640 pence by 1407 GMT, but still underperforming a 0.2
percent higher European technology index .SX8P. Nokia shares were down 0.7 percent at 1322 GMT. The suit set apart CSR rival U.S.-based Broadcom (BRCM.O),
which has acquired a licence to use the radio technology, the
Washington Research Foundation said. The foundation said it had informed the three mobile phone
makers about Broadcom's licence, and that they could have bought
their chips from Broadcom and avoided a legal battle. "The document is positive news for Broadcom, but negative
for CSR. These two are the main global players in the Bluetooth
chip market," Mawston said. Broadcom shares were up 2.75 percent at $33.20. Bluetooth SIG Marketing Director Anders Edlund said he could
not yet comment on the validity of the court case.
 (Additional reporting by Marc Jones in London and Tarmo Virki
in Helsinki)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/bluetooth-patent-infringement-idUSL0313940620070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 2 - u . s . group sues nokia , samsung over bluetooth</title></story></items>