<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:26 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Refiles to additional codes, adds attribution in 7th
paragraph)TORONTO Jan 3 (Reuters) - Canada is preparing to spend
about C$3 billion ($2.6 billion) on a search-and-rescue
aircraft contract, and the selection process has been narrowed
down to just one bid, the Globe and Mail newspaper said on
Wednesday. The Spartan C27J aircraft is the only aircraft ready for
purchase to replace the Buffalo and Hercules aircraft currently
in use, the Globe quoted unnamed sources as saying. The Spartan is made by Global Military Aircraft Systems,
which is a joint venture between subsidiaries of Finmeccanica
(SIFI.MI) and L-3 Communications Holdings Inc. (LLL.N) Boeing
(BA.N) is also in the group of companies behind the aircraft. Canada's previous Liberal government announced funding in
2004 for new fixed-wing aircraft and the Department of National
Defence is to launch the formal process to acquire the
aircraft, which were due to be in service by last year, the
Globe reported. A DND document obtained by the newspaper confirmed only one
aircraft is considered a "viable bidder" for the
search-and-rescue contract. The project includes the
maintenance of the aircraft over 20 years, the newspaper
reported. If the Spartan is bought, it will be the latest instance of
the government signing multibillion-dollar deals without
accepting competing bids, the Globe said. The paper said that last year, Canada bought 16 Chinook
helicopters for C$2.7-billion, four C17 cargo airplanes for
C$3.4-billion and 17 C130J Hercules transport planes for
C$5-billion. In each case, only the winning bid was
considered. In the upcoming search-and-rescue competition, EADS
EAD.PA, the builders of the rival C295 aircraft, are lobbying
Ottawa to change certain requirements in the hope of qualifying
for the competition, the Globe reported. ($1=$1.17 Canadian)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/canada-planes-contract-idUSN0338605220070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>refile - canada to spend c $ 3 bln on rescue plane deal - paper</title></story></items>