<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:46 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates to midmorning)NEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. stocks started 2007 with
sharp gains on Wednesday after a drop in oil prices and a
stronger-than-expected reading in a gauge of U.S. manufacturing
underscored optimism about the economy. The Dow Jones industrial average hit an intraday record
high, with shares of Wal-Mart Stores Inc.(WMT.N) and Home Depot
Inc. (HD.N) leading gains. The Nasdaq jumped more than 1 percent. Shares of Wal-Mart rose after the retailer estimated over
the weekend that December same-store sales rose more than
expected in the crucial holiday shopping period. For details,
see [ID:nN30286457] Stock in Home Depot advanced after the
resignation of its chairman and chief executive revived
takeover talk. Oil prices fell below $60 a barrel as mild weather in the
U.S. Northeast cut demand for fuel in the world's biggest
heating oil market. The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI was up 110.15
points, or 0.88 percent, at 12,573.30. The Standard &amp; Poor's
500 Index .SPX was up 10.83 points, or 0.76 percent, at
1,429.13. The Nasdaq Composite Index .IXIC was up 34.70
points, or 1.44 percent, at 2,449.99. The Institute for Supply Management said its manufacturing
index for December rose to 51.4 from a November reading of
49.5. A reading above 50 indicates growth in the sector. "The manufacturing index itself was up above October, so
that confirms the little bit of firming we thought we had. It's
not huge but the economy seems like it has firmed," said Robert
Macintosh, chief economist at Eaton Vance Management in
Boston. Shares of Wal-Mart rose 3.7 percent to $47.90, while shares
of Home Depot gained 3.9 percent to $41.71. U.S. crude CLc1 fell $1.94 to $59.11 a barrel.
 (Additional reporting by Chris Sanders)











</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-stocks-idUSN0340172620070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>us stocks - shares surge on oil drop , factory data</title></story></items>