<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>10:32 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates figures, adds details, comments)TORONTO Jan 3 (Reuters) - The Toronto Stock Exchange's
main index fell shortly after market open on Wednesday as
weaker resource and energy issues dragged the broader benchmark
into the red. The S&amp;P/TSX composite index was down 48.52 points, or 0.4
percent, at 12,875.14 shortly after the year's second session
kicked off, reversing the 15-point gain made on Tuesday. "Obviously, it is a reflection of the 45 percent of the
index that's in oil and materials," said Gavin Graham, chief
investment officer at the Guardian Group of Funds in Toronto. Eight of the composite's 10 main groups advanced. But the
heavyweight materials sector, which includes gold miners, and
the energy sector lost 1.42 percent and 1.75 percent,
respectively. The key groups' declines reflected softness in their
underlying commodity prices. Oil fell below $60 a barrel as
warm weather in the United States ate into heating oil demand. Base metals also fell, dragged down by copper prices which
touched their lowest levels since early April. Oil and base metals are "the two areas where you have
liquid, traded contracts that can be easily speculated in,"
Graham said. Speculation can add to market volatility. Zinc giant Teck Cominco Ltd. (TCKb.TO) was among the
biggest losers, dropping C$2.95, or 3.4 percent, to C$82.98.
Energy giant EnCana Corp. (ECA.TO) eased 90 Canadian cents to
C$53.45. Inmet Mining IMN.TO dove C$4.29, or 7 percent, to
C$56.49. Trading volumes are only beginning to return to normal
levels following the Christmas and New Year holiday break. As well, U.S. traders are back at their desks for the first
time this week following a day of mourning for former U.S.
President Gerald Ford which kept stock exchanges south of the
border closed on Tuesday. ($1=$1.17 Canadian)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-canada-stocks-idUSN0339730520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>softer resources , energy drag down toronto stocks</title></story></items>