<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:05 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds quotes, details, background)WASHINGTON Jan 3 (Reuters) - President George W. Bush said
on Wednesday the budget he presents to Congress next month will
aim to balance the budget by 2012 and make lower tax rates
permanent. "Next month I will submit a five-year budget proposal that
will balance the federal budget by 2012," Bush said after a
meeting at the White House with top administration officials. Bush said the budget would address "priorities" like "the
need to keep this economy growing by making tax relief
permanent." Balancing the budget in the given timeframe would require
substantial spending discipline, given that recent projections
by the White House showed it expected a budget gap of $127
billion by 2011. Bush also said entitlement programs for retired Americans
and for medical care need reform. "We need to reform Social
Security and Medicare and Medicaid so future generations of
Americans can benefit from these vital programs without
bankrupting our economy," Bush said. The Bush administration tried unsuccessfully in the past to
reform Social Security, proposing to make private savings
accounts a part of the retirement program in an effort that was
rejected by the public and by Democrats. Bush faces a Democrat-controlled Congress after elections
last November that cost his Republican party its majorities in
the Senate and U.S. House of Representatives, and he suggested
both parties could work together to curb wasteful spending. "One important message we all should take from the
elections is that people want to end the secretive process by
which Washington insiders are able to get billions of dollars
directed to projects, many of them pork-barrel projects that
have never been reviewed or voted on by the Congress," Bush
said.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/bush-budget-idUSN0340267220070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - bush says aims to balance u . s . budget by 2012</title></story></items>