<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:07 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds detail about source in para 6)LONDON/KUALA LUMPUR Jan 3 (Reuters) - British airlines
easyJet (EZJ.L) and Virgin Atlantic [VA.UL] on Wednesday denied
media reports that they might take part in a global low-cost
alliance with Malaysian carrier AirAsia Bhd (AIRA.KL) or its
owners. Malaysian newspapers have reported that AirAsia, easyJet and
the Virgin Group were in talks to form a global no-frills
alliance that would offer cheap flights within Asia as well as
between Europe and Australia via Kuala Lumpur.
"We are not joining any alliance," easyJet spokesman Toby
Nicol said. "The whole low-cost airline business model is based on
simplicity," he added, noting alliances with other airlines
involve costs and complications. Virgin Atlantic spokesman Paul Charles said: "It's nothing
to do with us. AirAsia clearly have their own plans and it is up
to them to announce them." A source familiar with the plan told Reuters on Wednesday
that the major owners of AirAsia might pursue a tie-up with the
two airlines via FlyasianXpress (FAX), a domestic Malaysian
carrier they control. AirAsia Chief Executive Tony Fernandes, one of those
stakeholders, was not immediately available for comment. AirAsia has said it will make an announcement on Friday in
Kuala Lumpur with the Malaysian transport minister set to
attend. Speculation over the tie-up drove shares of AirAsia up as
much as 9.3 percent earlier on Wednesday. EasyJet was down 1.2 percent at 629 1/2 pence in late trade
on Wednesday, lagging London's FTSE 100 index .FTSE which was
little changed. Fernandes told Malaysia's New Straits Times on Saturday that
there was potential for a budget long-haul air service model. "It's a matter of time before someone comes up with a good
model for a low-cost carrier and I hope the innovation would
come from Malaysia," he told the newspaper.
The source familiar with AirAsia's plan said a new service
would be announced aimed at a July launch and include cargo
operations. "It's expected to be part and parcel of the business," said
the source, who did not want to be identified. The alliance is expected to initially need two aircraft -- a
toss up between Airbus's EAD.PA A330 or Boeing Co's (BA.N) 777
-- and will probably stay a one-make outfit, the source added.
 (Additional reporting by Hsu Chuang Khoo in Kuala Lumpur)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/airasia-alliance-idUSKLR15619220070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A</value></value></sectors><title>update 3 - easyjet , virgin deny airasia tie - up talks</title></story></items>