<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:30 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK U.S. mortgage applications rose last week, led by increased demand for home purchase loans even as interest rates climbed for a fourth consecutive week, an industry trade group said on Wednesday.The Mortgage Bankers Association said its seasonally adjusted index of mortgage application activity, which includes both refinance and purchase loans, for the week ended December 29 increased 3.6 percent to 575.6. The index stood at 555.8 in the previous week, which was its lowest level since early August.Applications were 5.4 percent above their year-ago level.The indexes tend to be volatile on a weekly basis, analysts say. However, the monthly average shows a decline in the volume of applications for home loans, with the four-week moving average of mortgage applications down 2.8 percent.Jim Svinth, chief economist at LendingTree.com, an online company that matches consumers with lenders, said the slim difference between the borrowing costs for some fixed- and floating-rate loan types has been luring consumers."While we expect interest rates to stay relatively flat for the next couple of quarters, it's interesting to note that the spread between fixed and adjustable rate mortgages is the tightest it's been since December 2000," he said."This represents a real opportunity for borrowers to shift from adjustable to fixed rate loans," said Svinth, who is based in Irvine, California.Borrowing costs on 30-year fixed-rate mortgages, excluding fees, averaged 6.22 percent, up 0.10 percentage point from the previous week. Four weeks earlier, 30-year mortgage rates were at 5.98 percent, the lowest level since October 2005.Interest rates were also above year-ago levels of 6.15 percent.The MBA's seasonally adjusted purchase index, widely considered a timely gauge of U.S. home sales, rose 4.3 percent to 406.9. However, the purchase index was below its year-ago level of 418.3, a drop of 2.7 percent.Demand for home refinancing loans also strengthened as the MBA's seasonally adjusted index of refinancing applications increased 2.2 percent to 1,640.4, up 20.3 percent from a year ago. This followed two consecutive weeks of sharp declines.The refinance share of applications decreased to 48.1 percent from 48.8 percent the previous week.FAREWELL TO ARMSIn the past adjustable-rate mortgages, known as ARMs, have been a refuge for cash-strapped consumers seeking to buy a home with low initial mortgage payments.But the ARM share of activity decreased to 20.4 percent from 23.1 percent the previous week, its lowest since July 2003.Fixed 15-year mortgage rates averaged 5.93 percent, up from 5.84 percent. Rates on one-year adjustable-rate mortgages (ARMs) decreased to 5.84 percent from 5.87 percent.The MBA's report precedes separate data this week gauging the state of the U.S. housing market.The National Association of Realtors will release data on pending sales of existing U.S. homes in November on Thursday.U.S. housing industry indexes, in general, tend to be volatile and in recent months they have painted a mixed picture, with some pointing to weakening and others to stabilization.The MBA's survey covers about 50 percent of all U.S. retail residential loans. Respondents include mortgage banks, commercial banks and thrifts.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-usa-mortgages-mba-idUSN0335443320070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>home loan demand rises despite higher rates</title></story></items>