<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:01 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 U.S. gold futures climbed almost
1 percent early Wednesday, extending their gains from the end of
2006, as funds poured money into the market on a weaker dollar
and lingering geopolitical tensions around the world. At 10:28 a.m. EST (1528 GMT), gold for February delivery
GCG7 on the COMEX metals trading division of the New York
Mercantile Exchange was up $6.10 at $644.0 an ounce, near its
four-week high of $648.80. It traded in a range between $635.10
and $647.30. James Quinn, commodity commentator at A.G. Edwards, said
that a lower dollar, technical buying and geopolitical issues
underpinned the gold market's gain. "We left off the end of the calendar year in a more
positive way, and technically, the market seems to find some
support back around the $630 area," Quinn said. "We think there's been some good fund participation in the
market," he said. Quinn added that Iran's nuclear saber-rattling and Nigeria's
oil-supply disturbance could continue to extend support to gold
prices for weeks, or even longer. Militant attacks at Nigeria's Agip Tebidaba oil field, a key
export facility, have disrupted output for the last two months.
Kidnappings and attacks on oil facilities have become an almost
weekly occurrence in the world's eighth-largest exporter. "In the gold, it looks like there's some renewed buying
interest as the new year starts. People are looking for higher
numbers," said one precious metals trader on the floor, adding
that fund buying has lifted the markets. Gold and silver rose despite a plunge of more than 7 percent
in COMEX copper futures HGH7 prices. The trader said that
lower copper prices often pulled the precious metals markets
down. Investors now await the release of the most recent Federal
Reserve Open Market Committee (FOMC) minutes, due at 2 p.m. EST
(1900 GMT), which often offers direction to the U.S. dollar. Spot gold XAU= was quoted at $641.40/2.15, up from
$640.20/1.20 in late trade on Tuesday. London's gold fix was
$642.60. In other precious metals, COMEX March silver SIH7 rose
21.5 cents, or 1.7 percent, at $13.150 an ounce, trading
between $12.905 and $13.280. Spot silver XAG= was up at $13.040/3.110, against
$13.080/3.140 late on Tuesday. Silver was fixed in London at
$12.910 an ounce. NYMEX January platinum PLF7 edged up 90 cents at $1,140.20
an ounce. Spot platinum XPT= fetched $1,136.00/1,142.00. NYMEX March palladium PAH7 was up $4.55, or 1.3 percent,
at $343.50 an ounce. Spot palladium XPD= was quoted at
$338/344.00.






















</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-precious-comex-idUSN0338868120070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>u . s . gold climbs 1 pct on fund buying , weak dollar</title></story></items>