<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:41 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds stock activity, other details)NEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - Amgen Inc. (AMGN.O) and
Cytokinetics Inc. (CYTK.O) said on Wednesday they will
collaborate to develop drugs to treat heart failure in a deal
that could yield smaller Cytokinetics more than $600 million if
the products eventually succeed in clinical trials. Shares of Cytokinetics rose 12 percent on news of its deal
with Amgen, one of the world's largest biotechnology companies
that is best known for its drugs to treat anemia and to boost
immune systems of chemotherapy patients. During the initial two-year term of the partnership,
Cytokinetics will be obliged to conduct and pay for research of
its compounds that have not yet reached clinical trials, as
well as to finance its own continued development of a product
called CK-1827452 that has completed two early-stage trials. Cytokinetics is receiving an up-front fee of $42 million,
the two California-based companies said in a joint release. In
addition, Amgen has purchased nearly 3.5 million Cytokinetics
shares for $33 million. That translates into a price of $9.47
per share, or about 27 percent higher than its Friday closing
share price. Heart failure is a hard-to-treat condition in which the
heart -- damaged by clogged arteries or other causes -- is
unable to adequately pump blood to the rest of the body. Few
drugs are now able to treat the life-threatening condition,
which is a major cause of disability and hospitalizations among
the elderly. Cytokinetics is attempting to develop synthetic drugs,
including CK-1827452, that prompt weakened heart muscle to
contract, by activating a family of proteins called myosins. "Joint research activities will focus on identifying and
characterizing activators of cardiac myosin as back-up and
follow-on potential drug candidates to CK-1827452," the
companies said in the release. Amgen has an option to help develop and sell CK-1827452,
assuming the synthetic compound meets goals of planned
mid-stage trials. Cytokinetics also may receive milestone payments of up to
$600 million on CK-1827452 and other products arising from the
research as well as royalties, the companies said. Cytokinetics, which lost about $15 million in the third
quarter, had about $94 million in cash and marketable
securities on hand at the end of the period. Amgen on Wednesday also reaffirmed it expects earnings per
share of $3.85 to $3.95 for 2006, excluding special items. Shares of Cytokinetics were up 88 cents to $8.36 in morning
trading. Amgen rose 90 cents, or 1.3 percent, to $69.21, also
on the Nasdaq.
 (Additional reporting by Lewis Krauskopf)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/cytokinetics-amgen-idUSN0339492220070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Bonds, </value><value>Markets</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - amgen , cytokinetics to team on heart - failure drugs</title></story></items>