<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:45 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Nabors Industries Ltd. (NBR.N) warned on Wednesday its fourth-quarter earnings would fall short of Wall Street estimates as weakening gas prices cooled demand for its drilling rigs in the United States and Canada.The news caused shares of the company based in Hamilton, Bermuda, to post their largest one-day decline in nearly a year. The stock was off more than 6 percent to $27.99 on the New York Stock Exchange.The world's largest land-based oil and gas driller now sees earnings at 95 cents to $1 a share. Analysts, on average, were expecting earnings of $1.11 before one-time items, according to Reuters Estimates.Nabors expects 2006 earnings to be between $3.53 and $3.58 a share. Analysts, on average, look for $3.70.Nabors Chief Executive Gene Isenberg said in a statement that a lower level of activity in the company's North American gas markets was the primary factor behind the company's lowered forecast.He said a portion of the shortfall is also due to equipment problems in the lower 48 states and weather-related start-up delays in Canada.In October, Nabors forecast potential softening in the U.S. gas markets as it announced a slightly better-than-expected third-quarter profit.Nabors also said its Alaskan and U.S. land well servicing operations are growing in line with previous expectations as is its U.S. offshore business, although modestly slower.High gas inventory levels pushed prices to four-year lows in October, prompting some producers to curtail drilling operations in Western Canada and parts of the United States.Unseasonably mild winter weather in key consumption areas has curbed demand for natural gas and so far this week, short-term forecasts in key consumption cities like New York and Chicago do not show any relief.(Additional reporting by Madhubanti Routh in Bangalore and Michael Erman in New York)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-nabors-outlook-idUSBNG13318520070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>nabors warns on earnings , stock tumbles</title></story></items>