<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:46 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds analyst comments, details; updates share movement)Jan 3 (Reuters) - Poniard Pharmaceuticals Inc. PARD.O
said it plans to begin a key late-stage trial of its
experimental lung cancer treatment picoplatin after receiving
regulatory approval, and its shares rose 7 percent. The company said it received a special protocol assessment
(SPA) from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration for the phase
III trial of picoplatin for the treatment of small cell lung
cancer (SCLC). The pharmaceutical company said it plans to start the
late-stage study of picoplatin efficacy after relapse in the
first half of 2007, based on positive interim mid-stage data
for the platinum therapy announced earlier. "In our view, this SPA underscores the unmet clinical need
that is SCLC and provides added assurance that the FDA will
approve picoplatin for this indication if (the phase III
trial's) primary endpoints are met," analyst George Zavoico of
Cantor Fitzgerald said in a research note. Zavoico, who has a "buy" rating and a $9 price target on
the stock, however, cautioned that mid-stage trial results
might not be repeated in later stages. A special protocol assessment provides for the FDA to
evaluate within 45 days some late-stage trial protocols to see
if they meet scientific and regulatory requirements. "This SPA agreement with the FDA solidifies our plan to
conduct a single pivotal Phase 3 trial that evaluates overall
survival as the primary endpoint..." Jerry McMahon, Poniard's
chief executive, said in a statement. Picoplatin, the company's lead product candidate, is
designed to overcome and prevent platinum resistance associated
with chemotherapy in solid tumors. The company said it plans to enroll about 400 patients in
the trial. The company expects to file a new drug application
for the therapy in 2009. Poniard said it had received orphan drug designation from
the FDA for picoplatin for the treatment of SCLC in November
2005. An orphan drug designation encourages development of
treatments of rare diseases by giving the parent company seven
years of exclusivity to market the product for a particular
disease. Picoplatin was licensed to Poniard by Canadian
biotechnology firm AnorMED Inc. in 2004. AnorMED was acquired
by Genzyme Corp. GENZ.O last year. Shares of Poniard rose 35 cents to $5.35 in morning trade
on the Nasdaq.
 (Reporting by Dilipp S. Nag, Varsha Tickoo in Bangalore)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/poniard-fda-idUSBNG17046520070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets, </value><value>Regulatory News</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - poniard says to begin late - stage trial for lung cancer</title></story></items>