<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:50 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON Conservative Christian broadcaster Pat Robertson says God told him a terrorist attack will result in "mass killing" in the United States in the second half of 2007."I'm not saying necessarily nuclear, the Lord didn't say nuclear," Robertson said on Tuesday on his television show "The 700 Club." "It'll be mass killing, possibly millions of people, major cities."The evil people will come after this country and there's a possibility, not a possibility, a definite certainty, that chaos is going to rule," he added.Robertson told viewers they should not be afraid because "if you get blown up or something, you go to heaven, that's the worst thing that will happen to you."Robertson said God conveyed this message to him during an annual prayer retreat. He said he has received other spiritual messages during past retreats.The broadcaster's 2006 forecast of heavy storm damage in coastal areas was followed by the second-lightest hurricane season since 1995. He said his prediction was borne out by storms in New England, Denver, the Pacific Northwest and the Philippines.God did not warn him of any natural disasters this year, he said.Robertson, 76, reaches about 1 million U.S. viewers daily on the Christian Broadcasting Network, which he founded. He is credited for helping shape political views of evangelical Christians, a vibrant force in the Republican Party, and campaigned for the presidency as a Republican in 1988.Robertson has not shied away from controversial statements in the past.In January 2006, he suggested that former Israeli Prime Minister Ariel Sharon suffered a stroke because God was punishing him for dividing Israel. He also called for the assassination of leftist Venezuelan President Hugo Chavez, a vocal critic of President George W. Bush.He also claims on his Web site (here) that he can leg-press 2,000 pounds (907 kg), well above the world record, thanks to an energy shake he promotes.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-usa-robertson-terrorism-idUSN0338478620070103</link><sectors><value><value>U.S.</value></value></sectors><title>christian broadcaster predicts terrorist attack</title></story></items>