<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:16 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>DETROIT The Detroit Red Wings paid Steve Yzerman the ultimate tribute on Tuesday, retiring his number 19 jersey and raising it to the rafters of Joe Louis Arena in a stirring pre-game ceremony.Then in the unselfish fashion that defined his career, Yzerman offered his encouragement to a troubled city that had inspired him for 22 NHL seasons.With Detroit's battered auto industry casting a dark shadow of layoffs and unemployment over the city, Yzerman used the ceremonies to deliver the type of pep talk that helped establish him as one of the NHL's all-time great leaders.The Red Wings also produced an inspired effort, capping off the celebrations with a 2-1 win over the NHL leading Anaheim Ducks."I came to Detroit as an 18-year-old boy and was immediately drawn to the lore of the Detroit Red Wings," said Yzerman, who spent his entire career in a Detroit jersey before retiring at the end of last season."There has not been a time since I came to Detroit that I have regretted or been disappointed about playing here."I think of the Red Wings and how our organization was rebuilt and became a champion, I think is very similar to what is going on in the city."It's a very difficult time but I think we can look back on what has transpired for the Detroit Red Wings over the last 20 years."Our organization has had strong leadership and dedicated players and everyone with a common goal, which was to bring a championship back to the city."I think that single-mindedness, that willingness to work together are exactly the kind of things that it will take to rebuild our city."THREE CUPSSelected by Detroit with the fourth overall pick in the 1983 draft, Yzerman became the cornerstone around which the dilapidated franchise that had become known as the 'Dead Things' would rebuild.In just his third season, the 20-year-old Yzerman became the Red Wings captain and wore the 'C' for 20-years, the longest tenure in NHL history, leading Detroit to three Stanley Cups in 1997, 1998 and 2002.While Yzerman was celebrated for his leadership skills he was also one of the NHL's most complete players, finishing his career among the league's all-time scoring leaders with 692 goals and 1,755 points.His trophy case is also packed with individual honors, including the Conn Smythe Trophy as the Stanley Cup playoffs MVP.One of the NHL's original six franchises, Yzerman becomes only the sixth Detroit player in the team's 81-year history to have his number officially retired, joining Gordie Howe, Terry Sawchuk, Ted Lindsay, Alex Delvecchio and Sid Abel in the Joe Louis rafters.Earlier in the day, Yzerman was handed a key to the city to go along with a key to a new car and a street named in his honor.The current Red Wings also presented Yzerman with a trip to Vienna and tickets for the final of the 2008 Euro championships."I feel like my image as a great leader is greatly overblown because I played with some great hockey players," offered a humble Yzerman, watched by his family, former-team mates and a sellout crowd of 20,066 during the 80 minute ceremony."Any personal success I had was because of the great players I played with."</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-nhl-yzerman-idUSSP15625120070103</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>yzerman inspires detroit to victory after number retired</title></story></items>