<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:55 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>OTTAWA Jan 3 Canada's robust labor market will
likely show signs of weakness in December, reflecting a
sharper-than-expected slowdown in economic growth, analysts
said on Wednesday. The economy added more jobs than expected in both November
and October despite the slowdown. But the average forecast in a
Reuters poll is that a modest 10,000 jobs were created in
December with the unemployment rate unchanged at 6.3 percent. The strong headline jobs numbers have masked underlying
weaknesses. Jobs have been plentiful in resource-rich western
Canada while lay-offs have been the norm in the powerful
central provinces of Ontario and Quebec where the U.S. slowdown
has taken a toll on exporters. Also, all the job growth in November came from part-time
jobs while full-time positions were lost. "I think the risk is certainly toward a pretty weak
number," said Marc Levesque, chief fixed-income strategist at
TD Securities. "The data on GDP growth for the past two months has been
surprisingly weak and suggests the Canadian economy in the
fourth quarter will probably have difficulty even eking out
positive growth," he said. "I'd be surprised to see Canada's
job market continue to pump out jobs at that pace." In the United States, private sector employment likely
declined by 40,000 in December, suggesting an abrupt slowing of
employment there, the monthly ADP National Employment Report
showed on Wednesday. Max Clarke, economist at IDEAglobal, sees downside risks to
the research firm's estimate of 20,000 new jobs in December,
because the data are so volatile. "You could even see a number that's single digit," Clarke
said. "The one thing that is difficult to measure is the change
in part-time jobs or even as we saw recently the changes in
full-time jobs. The headline number itself is difficult to
gauge when those two numbers are weighted equally." Whatever the jobs report reveals, the Bank of Canada is
unlikely to be rattled. Bank Governor David Dodge has already
acknowledged that fourth-quarter 2006 growth appears to be
weaker than the bank had anticipated. The central bank has kept its key overnight rate steady at
4.25 percent since May 2006 following seven straight hikes. Markets rule out any interest rate moves on Jan. 16, the
bank's next policy announcement date, but are keen to see if
policymakers will change their neutral tone to reveal a bias
toward rate cuts later this year, as is widely expected. "Whether or not (the jobs report) will cause them to revise
their risks is going to depend on whatever data we get for the
U.S. and Canada from this point on," said Levesque. For the past several months, the bank has said the risks to
its economic outlook are balanced.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/canada-economy-jobs-idUSN0340155920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>canada ' s slowing economy set to crimp jobs growth</title></story></items>