<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:55 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Total help-wanted postings on major U.S.-based Internet job boards fell 10 percent in December, a private research group said on Wednesday.The Conference Board said its measure of the total number of unduplicated online jobs dropped to 3.34 million in December from about 3.71 million in November."The period between Thanksgiving and the end of the year is typically slow in terms of hiring, so it's not surprising that we saw a decline in the number of job ads last month," said Gad Levanon, economist at The Conference Board.Online advertised job vacancies actually rose 17 percent in 2006 compared to the previous year, the group said."While the economy slowed down in 2006, all in all weaknesses in the labor market have not been widespread. Advertised vacancies actually grew during the year and unemployment edged lower," Levanon said.California had the most advertised vacancies, with 590,200, more than twice the vacancies posted in Texas, New York and Florida, which followed with an average of 244,600 each.Adjusting job ads for the size of the state labor force, Massachusetts led with 4.0 online job ads per 100 people, followed by Rhode Island with 3.9.The online job demand is strongest in management, business and finance, and computer and mathematical operations."Not only are these jobs in demand, but many of them are high-paying jobs," said Levanon.The average hourly wage for the management posts was $42.52, the report said.The new Help-Wanted Online Data Series measures the total number of online job ads posted on more than 1,200 major Internet job boards and smaller job boards that serve niche markets and smaller geographic areas. In previous releases, the Conference Board tracked mainly the new online job ad postings.Online jobs-posting data reflects both changes in labor demand and the shift of other sources of advertising to online media, which could result in an upward bias in the data.The Conference Board's gauge measuring help-wanted ad volume in 51 newspapers across the country is released the last Thursday of each month.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-economy-helpwanted-online-idUSN0342410820070103</link><sectors><value><value>Tech</value></value></sectors><title>online help - wanted ads fall in december : report</title></story></items>