<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:01 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Releads with VW figures, adds details, background)FRANKFURT Jan 3 (Reuters) - Sales of Volkswagen (VOWG.DE)
brand cars in the United States fell 23.2 percent year-on-year
to 19,942 vehicles in December, Volkswagen said in a statement
on Wednesday. The company gave no reason for the year-on-year fall, but
full-year 2006 VW brand sales in the United States rose 4.9
percent to 235,140 units, the company said. VW's premium brand Audi (NSUG.DE), the profit driver of the
VW group, saw its U.S. sales rise 34.6 percent in December,
helped by strong demand for its A3 compact, A4 mid-size and Q7
sport utility models. Audi said in a statement it sold 11,897 vehicles in the
United States in December, taking its 2006 U.S. sales to a
record 90,116 cars. Over the whole of 2006 its U.S. vehicle
sales rose 8.5 percent. "2007 looks to be just as exciting," said Johan de Nysschen,
Audi of America's executive vice president. Audi plans to invest about 8.4 billion euros ($11.2 billion)
by 2011 on developing new products as it seeks to almost double
its range to 40 models by 2015. VW shares pared earlier gains, and were up 0.9 percent at
85.68 euros by 1601 GMT, still outperforming the German top-30
DAX index .GDAXI, which was up 0.2 percent. Volkswagen, Europe's biggest carmaker, said its most popular
model of 2006 in the United States was the new compact saloon
Jetta, for the second year running. The company sold 103,331
Jettas in the United States. The new Passat sedan, with sales of 54,208 cars, and the new
Beetle, including the cabriolet version, were next most popular. The VW brand has embarked on a revamp under brand chief
Wolfgang Bernhard, a protege of ex-Chief Executive Bernd
Pischetsrieder, who was ousted in a boardroom coup in November. Some investors are concerned that Bernhard may resign next
week, after new VW group Chief Executive Martin Winterkorn, the
former Audi chief, outlines his plans for a management shake-up. Winterkorn has been replaced at Audi, at least in the
interim, by the division's former Chief Financial Officer Rupert
Stadler.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/volkswagen-us-idUSL031931220070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - vw brand sales fall 23 . 2 pct in u . s . in december</title></story></items>