<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:29 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LOS ANGELES Shoppers bumped up their spending the last week of December, giving retailers some optimism for the start of 2007 after lackluster holiday sales, according to a retail report released on Wednesday.The rise in spending from December 26 to December 30 was led by footwear and men's apparel, capping a December of tepid sales that fell from a year ago, according to SpendingPulse, a retail data service of MasterCard Advisors. The survey that captures sales figures did not say how big the increase was for the final week of the month.SpendingPulse also said a 3.7 percent year-over-year rise in spending on gasoline in December showed consumers were increasingly taking to the road to do their shopping as the impact of lower fuel prices seemed to be taking hold after three months of slightly negative sales."It's good to see consumers hitting the road more, buying more gasoline," said Michael McNamara, vice president of research for MasterCard Advisors. "It increases the velocity of the retail economy when you see people out there hitting the stores."A burst of cooler weather across the country following unseasonably warm temperatures, together with higher foot traffic from shoppers redeeming gift cards and searching for post-holiday discounts, also spurred shoppers during the last week of December, SpendingPulse said.The survey comes ahead of a report measuring total retail sales excluding automobiles for the month of December and after SpendingPulse data last week showed a 3 percent rise in holiday retail sales that compared to a year-ago 5.2 percent gain.Retailers from Federated Department Stores FD.N to Best Buy Co. Inc. (BBY.N) and Gap Inc. (GPS.N) release their key December sales figures later this week.The week after Christmas, which can account for between 14 percent and 16 percent of December sales, saw a 9.5 percent rise in footwear -- with boots especially popular -- and an 8 percent jump in men's apparel, according to SpendingPulse.But demand for electronics -- stars of the holiday season as consumers snatched up flat-screen televisions and video game consoles -- slowed the last week of December, perhaps as more shoppers gravitated to apparel, McNamara said.Looking ahead to 2007, McNamara said that retailers will face difficult comparisons with January 2006, when strong sales growth was fueled by record good weather."There are signs of optimism but there are definitely some warning signs we have to watch out for regarding energy and housing," he said.SpendingPulse reports are based on aggregated sales activity in the MasterCard U.S. payments network, coupled with estimates on all other payments forms, including cash and check. SpendingPulse is a retail data service of MasterCard Advisors, an arm of MasterCard Worldwide.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-spendingpulse-idUSN0219790320070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>end of december sees retail sales rise : report</title></story></items>