<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:15 01 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> NEW YORK (Hollywood Reporter) - Major news outlets faced an 
ultimate ethical dilemma -- whether to televise an execution -- 
when what appeared to be cell phone video emerged Saturday from 
the scene of Saddam Hussein's execution. Some U.S. networks ran 
portions of the video, which predictably spread like wildfire 
through the Internet. Fox News Channel was the first to run some of the footage 
shortly after 4 p.m. EST Saturday. The grainy, shaky video 
includes an angle of the hanging and audio of sometimes testy 
exchanges between Saddam, his executioners and witnesses as the 
former dictator is led to the gallows. It wasn't clear who shot the video, which appeared on a Web 
site and then on a pan-Arab news channel, or how it made its 
way to the public. The video was later uploaded to APTN, the 
Associated Press' video news service, which made it available 
to every network. "The real journalistic value of the footage, if it is 
authentic, is that it gives you much more of the context 
surrounding his execution," said CNN president Jon Klein. "You 
learn so much more about what really was said, and how fraught 
with sectarian fervor the whole issue was. That could not be 
conveyed better than listening to the sound of the moment, even 
more so than the video." "It was a different angle of what we had already seen," 
said David Rhodes, vp news at Fox News Channel. "It was useful 
because there's some audio on it that you didn't necessarily 
hear in the previous version, and it's a fuller picture as to 
what was happening. You can hear all the principals speaking." Fox News Channel wasn't willing to carry anything further 
than where it had stopped with the government-provided 
videotape, when the noose was being fitted around Saddam's 
neck. The cell phone video continues with Saddam's body falling 
through the trap door but no U.S. network ran that portion on 
the air. CNN too showed the video up to the noose, not 
necessarily because of any camera angle but, like others, 
because of the audio. CNN's Web site showed the tape only up to the point just 
before Saddam fell; Fox News' site 
(one.revver.com/watch/130549) showed what appeared to be 
the entire video, including Saddam's body on the ground with 
his neck broken. Both sites warned viewers about the graphic 
nature. MSNBC.com, on the other hand, adhered to the standards of 
NBC News and didn't show the graphic parts of the video. NBC 
News showed some of the Iraqi government's video and reporting 
by Richard Engel of what eyewitnesses said, along with a shot 
of Saddam's body wrapped in a shroud with his head poking out 
-- the same shot, NBC News president Steve Capus noted, that 
was on the front page of the New York Times. But in consultation with his deputies including standards 
vp David McCormack and senior vp Alex Wallace, Capus ruled most 
of the cell phone video off-limits. "I really don't believe that it's appropriate to show much 
of that," Capus said Sunday afternoon. "It shows the execution, 
and we're not going to show that. I don't believe it's 
appropriate to show that to the audience, I don't think it's 
our responsibility to show an actual execution on video tape." Even though Saddam has been dead since Friday night U.S. 
time, the specter of even more video could lead to another 
round of soul-searching by the U.S. networks. Fox News' Rhodes 
didn't rule out running other video if it surfaces. "There's definitely an argument to run it and arguments not 
to," Rhodes said Sunday. Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/television-saddam-network-dc-idUSN2821679420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>Television</value></value></sectors><title>networks air more saddam execution video</title></story></items>