<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:07 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Shares in Freeport McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold Inc. (FCX.N) tumbled more than 8 percent on Wednesday as copper prices fell and visible warehouse supplies rose to a near two-year high.The combination of a price slump and higher inventories fueled speculation of a supply glut in the market this year, traders said.Copper for March delivery HGH7 sank 19.05 cents, or 6.6 percent, at $2.6805 per pound on the New York Mercantile Exchange's COMEX division. The $2.65 trading band low was the cheapest price March copper has seen since April of last year.Spot January HGF7 slipped 18.15 cents to trade at its morning trough at $2.6725.The price of copper in New York has erased nearly 16.5 percent of its value since the start of December as steady builds in stock levels, coupled with softer demand in the United States and China, and receding threats of supply disruptions out of Chile, have all contributed to the market's bearish tone, analysts said.The lower copper price, coupled with higher inventories, predictably sent copper mining company stocks down when the markets opened again after four days.In morning trading on the New York Stock Exchange, Freeport stock was down $4.92, or 8.83 percent, at $50.81. Phelps Dodge Corp. PD.N, another U.S. copper producer, which Freeport is in the process of acquiring in a $25.8 billion deal, saw its stock fall 2.9 percent to $116.25.New Orleans-based Freeport operates the vast Grasberg gold and copper mine in Indonesia.Earlier, in Jakarta, Simon Sembiring, Indonesia's director general of mining, told reporters the government hoped parliament would pass a new law in March that would force foreign mining companies to smelt ore within Indonesia.There is only one copper smelter in Indonesia, the Gresik smelter, operated by Mitsubishi Materials Corp. (5711.T) in a joint venture with the Indonesian unit of Freeport-McMoRan and Mitsubishi Corp (8058.T).(Additional reporting by Chris Kelly)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-freeport-shares-idUSN0340216820070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>freeport - mcmoran shares tumble as copper price slumps</title></story></items>