<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:17 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates to midday, changes byline) By Emily ChasanNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. stocks jumped on the first
trading day of 2007 on Wednesday as a drop in oil prices and a
stronger-than-expected reading of U.S. manufacturing spurred
optimism among investors who returned from a four-day break. Shares of Home Depot Inc. (HD.N) and Wal-Mart Stores
Inc.(WMT.N) led gains, pushing the Dow Jones industrial average
to an intraday record high. The Nasdaq jumped more than 1.5
percent.  Stock in Home Depot advanced 3.3 percent to $41.50 after
the resignation of its chairman and chief executive. For
details, see [ID:nN03383942] "The indications early on were that we would get a nice
rally and it was supported by some of the economic data this
morning," said Paul Nolte, director of investments at Hinsdale
Investments in Hinsdale, Illinois. "It's a combination of the
oil off and the Home Depot news. I think the Home Depot news
definitely lifted a cloud from around that stock." The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI was up 108.63
points, or 0.87 percent, at 12,571.78. The Standard &amp; Poor's
500 Index .SPX was up 9.44 points, or 0.67 percent, at
1,427.74. The Nasdaq Composite Index .IXIC was up 35.32
points, or 1.46 percent, at 2,450.61. The Dow earlier hit an all-time high of 12,580.35. U.S.
stock markets were closed on Monday for the New Year holiday
and on Tuesday for a day of mourning for former U.S. President
Gerald Ford. Shares of Wal-Mart rose after the retailer estimated over
the weekend that December same-store sales rose more than
expected in the crucial holiday shopping period.
[ID:nN30286457] Shares of Wal-Mart rose 2.9 percent to $47.52 Oil prices fell 3.6 percent as mild weather in the U.S.
Northeast cut demand for fuel in the world's biggest heating
oil market. U.S. crude CLc1 fell $2.20 to $58.85 a barrel,
sparking a decline in shares of oil companies such as Exxon
Mobil Corp. (XOM.N), which was off 2.6 percent at $74.62. The lower oil prices also sparked a rally in transportation
stocks with the Dow Jones Transportation average .DJT up 2.7
percent. The index was on track to record its best one-day gain
in nearly 4 months. The Institute for Supply Management said its manufacturing
index for December rose to 51.4 from a November reading of
49.5. A reading above 50 indicates growth in the sector. On the Nasdaq, shares of Google Inc. (GOOG.O) rose 3
percent to $474.50. Stifel Nicolaus said Google has replaced
eBay Inc. (EBAY.O) on its select list. [ID:nBNG172155]









</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-stocks-idUSN0340508520070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>us stocks - shares climb on home depot , oil ' s fall</title></story></items>