<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:53 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates with Chevron, Exxon comments, background) By Nidhi VermaNEW DELHI Jan 3 (Reuters) - India expects soon to ink a
deal to buy 2.5 million tonnes a year of liquefied natural gas
(LNG) from Australia to secure energy supplies as Asian demand
grows, government and company officials said on Wednesday. The LNG will come from Australia's Gorgon development, said
A. Sengupta, finance director at Indian gas firm Petronet LNG
Ltd. (PLNG.BO). The company expects a deal by end-June after negotiations
with the project's joint venture partners Exxon Mobil Corp.
(XOM.N), Chevron Corp. (CVX.N) and Royal Dutch Shell (RDSa.L). However, spokesman Michael Barrett said Chevron, who has
already pre-sold almost all its Gorgon gas, was not the seller.
Barrett said each partner was handling negotiations for sales of
its share of Gorgon gas separately. Exxon Mobil and Shell declined comment on potential Gorgon
gas sales discussions. Exxon Mobil has previously been linked with sales to India,
while Shell has said it planned to sell all or part of its share
of LNG from Gorgon to the North American market, via a terminal
in Baja California, Mexico. Sengupta's comments clarified earlier remarks by Petroleum
Secretary M.S. Srinivasan, who told reporters at a conference
that the gas was from Australia's North West Shelf, which may
have been a reference to the region that includes Gorgon, rather
than the North West Shelf (NWS) venture LNG project. "Some delays due to environment concerns were there, but
that has been sorted out. We expect to sign a deal in the next
60 days," Srinivasan said. "It is a 25-year contract and supplies are expected to begin
in 2011."
 SECURING ENERGY SUPPLIES India, which imports more than 70 percent of the fuel it
consumes, wants to ensure adequate supplies to sustain an
economy growing at more than 8 percent a year. It is also
negotiating LNG purchases with Iran. Srinivasan said India's domestic gas production was seen at
200 million cubic metres a day in the next five years. Petronet
says India's regasification capacity for LNG -- gas super cooled
and shipped by tanker -- stands at 10 million tonnes a year. India imposes price controls on domestic gas sales, keeping
prices below world market levels. However, the LNG is destined
for industrial users such as fertiliser manufacturers and power
stations, which will have to pay market rates. Gorgon's operator Chevron won a government green light last
month for the project, which has been beset by worries over its
environmental impact that have pushed back first deliveries
until after the originally planned date of 2010. Chevron holds a 50 percent stake, while Exxon Mobil and
Royal Dutch Shell Plc each have 25 percent. Chevron has made
preliminary agreements to sell LNG to Japanese customers,
including Osaka Gas Co. Ltd. (9532.T) and Tokyo Gas Co.
(9531.T). Gorgon is expected to have a total liquefaction capacity of
10 million tonnes a year. The greater Gorgon area has estimated
gas reserves of about 40 trillion cubic feet (tcf), a quarter of
Australia's known gas reserves. Western Australia, rich in natural gas, is home to many
major LNG developments, including the North West Shelf gas field
operated by Woodside Petroleum Ltd. (WPL.AX). NWS currently has a production capacity of 11.6 million
tonnes of LNG per year and will increase to 16.3 million from
late 2008. Woodside has been working to renew long-term supply
agreements with Japanese customers that underpin the project. The six equal partners in the NWS joint venture are
Woodside, BHP Billiton (BHP.AX)(BLT.L), Chevron, BP Plc (BP.L),
Japan Australia LNG (MiMi) Pty. Ltd., a joint venture of
Mitsubishi Corp. (8058.T) and Mitsui and Co. (8031.T) and
Woodside's 34 percent shareholder, Royal Dutch Shell.
 (Additional reporting by Tom Bergin in London)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/india-lng-idUSSP16442720070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 3 - india to sign 25 - year deal for australian lng</title></story></items>