<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>11:54 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates prices) By David McMahonNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - The dollar rallied broadly on
Wednesday, hitting two-month highs against the yen, after a
survey showed the U.S. factory sector expanded in December,
defying predictions for another modest contraction. The dollar jumped after the Institute for Supply Management
said its manufacturing index climbed to 51.4, above the 50
threshold that separates expansion and contraction. The
greenback erased losses spurred by an earlier report showing
the first contraction in the U.S. private sector job market
since April 2003. "The fact that ISM came back above 50 puts the whole
soft-landing, dollar-positive scenario back in play," said
Boris Schlossberg, senior currency strategist at Forex Capital
Markets in New York. Led by strong gains against European currencies including
sterling, the euro and the Swiss franc, the dollar was set for
its biggest rise in around six months against a basket of six
major currencies =USD. The euro EUR= was trading down 0.8 percent on the day at
$1.3175, while sterling tumbled more than one percent to
$1.9485 GBP= in its biggest daily decline since July 2005.
The dollar was up 0.7 percent at 119.63 yen JPY= after
reaching as high as 119.65 on electronic trading platform EBS. Earlier in the session, the dollar had given up some ground
after a survey showed employment in the U.S. private sector
contracted unexpectedly in December. The ADP National Employment Report showed private-sector
jobs likely declined 40,000 in the month, flying in the face of
consensus forecasts for a solid rise. The soft report led some traders to speculate that the more
closely watched nonfarm payrolls report -- due from the
government on Friday -- could also come in softer than
expectations. "It points to a pretty poor payroll number on Friday, so I
think we'll see some revisions to the expectations for that
number," said Shaun Osborne, senior currency strategist at TD
Securities in Toronto. A weak reading in that payrolls report would likely
strengthen the view that the Federal Reserve may start cutting
interest rates in coming months to shore up a slowing economy. However, in the wake of the higher-than-expected ISM
reading, the futures market is pricing in only a 12 percent
chance of a rate cut by March, down from 18 percent in early
trading. For more click on [ID:nN03398946]. Later on Wednesday traders will also be taking a look at
minutes from the Federal Reserve's Dec. 12 meeting -- the
fourth straight occasion the central bank kept rates on hold
since its last rate rise to 5.25 percent in June. (Additional reporting by Steven C. Johnson)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSN0341802720070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - dollar surges after ism beats forecasts</title></story></items>