<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:30 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON Parents, pick up your pencils. It's time to fill out the financial aid forms that may get you some help with those arrhythmia-inducing tuition bills.It's a great time to ask for financial aid. Federal and local governments and colleges have been giving out some $135 billion a year, according to the College Board. And Congressional Democrats say they are going to make aid more plentiful and college loans more affordable when they take control of Capitol Hill this week.So, get the paperwork in for your fledgling fall freshman. Here's how.-- First, position yourself.Savings in your children's name penalizes their aid award far more than savings in 529 plans do. A loophole in the law allows you to clean out your kid's account and put the money in a 529 plan. Do that now, before you fill out and sign the aid forms. Some states will give you a tax break for that 529 deposit, even if you pull the money out next year to pay for that first semester.Financial aid formulas similarly put your retirement savings off limits but not your regular savings. So make your 2006 IRA contribution before you finish the forms.-- Then file fast.Though they may claim they don't, some schools give more money to early birds. Their financial aid offices start out generously and then, if they perceive themselves running low of funds, get a bit more tight-fisted later in the application cycle.You can, and should, file your Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) before the end of January, even if you don't have exact figures for your 2006 income and tax situation. You can always amend your form. Don't wait for the July 31 federal deadline, because states and individual schools have their own deadlines that may be earlier.-- Check with all the schools your child applied to and find out whether they require any other forms.Many private schools also require the College Board's PROFILE form (profileonline.collegeboard.com), and some might have their own forms, as well.-- Apply online, as do 90 percent of financial aid applicants.Do that at fafsa.ed.gov. The online version of the form is slightly different than the printed version, and allows you to forward the form to more schools. It also collects information about students who might qualify for a new federal grant program for low-income high achievers. The paper form doesn't.-- Make sure all the schools get your forms.This year's online FAFSA allows you to list six schools to receive the forms. But you can add additional schools and should, so that every college that got an application from your child also gets financial aid forms.-- Try to DIY.There are many professionals who are willing to fill out the forms for you for a fee, but it's not that hard, says Tom Joyce of student lending firm Sallie Mae.His firm offers an informational Web site with instructions and checklists to make it easier at collegeanswer.com. It's free to file the FAFSA, so you shouldn't fill out the form at a Web site that charges you for filing, he says.-- Don't limit your child until you see all of the financial aid offers.You may think that you make too much to qualify for aid, but you may be wrong. Some private schools with large endowments hand out big money even to well-heeled kids. Fill out the forms, even if you don't expect much, and maybe you'll be pleasantly surprised come April, when aid awards are announced."The stakes are high and getting higher every year," says Joyce. "Parents and students need to make sure they get the form filled out early and take advantage of all the free money."</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-column-finance-idUSN15253920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>the facts on filing those fall freshman aid forms</title></story></items>