<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:29 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 Overseas shares traded in the
United States rallied on Wednesday in their first trading day
of 2007, catching up with gains in markets around the world. European, Asian and Latin stock indexes rose on Tuesday
while the Nasdaq and the New York Stock Exchange were both
closed on Tuesday in observance of the death of former
President Gerald Ford. The Bank of New York's index of leading ADRs .BKADR was
up 1.1 percent while the 30-share Dow Jones industrial average
.DJI was up 0.9 percent at 12,574.26. The Bank of New York's index of leading European ADRs
.BKEUR was up 1.1 percent. In Europe, shares were flat. U.S.-listed shares of recently merged Alcatel-Lucent
(ALU.N) surged a day after the French-American
telecommunications gear maker said it had completed its
acquisition of the high-speed UMTS mobile access business from
Canada's Nortel NT.TO NT.N. U.S.-listed shares of French insurer AXA AXA.N were up
3.6 percent to $41.79 on the NYSE after the company's chief
executive said on Tuesday it is targeting cost savings of about
10 percent in its German operations [ID:nL02920141]. Other heavily weighted gainers were U.K bank Barclays
(BCS.N), up 2.6 percent to $59.67 and Finnish mobile phone
maker Nokia Oyj (NOK.N), up 2.1 percent to $20.75, both on the
NYSE. The Bank of New York's index of leading Asian ADRs .BKAS
was up 1.1 percent. In Asia, shares ended mostly flat. Markets
were closed in Tokyo. Toyota's ADRs (TM.N) were up sharply after analysts said
the Japanese auto maker will likely surpass Ford Motor Co
 (F.N) to the No. 2 spot in the U.S. auto market in December
[ID:nN02339758]. Toyota's U.S.-listed shares were up 1.6 percent to $136.48
on the NYSE. U.S.-listed shares of China Mobile (CHL.N) shot up amid
speculation that the company, whose local shares are listed in
Hong Kong, is eyeing a listing on the Chinese mainland. Receipts with the Bank of New York's index of leading Latin
American ADRs .BKLA up 0.5 percent. In Latin America, major
benchmarks were mostly trading lower, except in Chile. One of the few declining sectors were global miners and
energy companies as prices of the underlying commodities
tumbled amid concern about oversupply. Share of Peruvian gold miner Buenaventura (BVN.N) were down
2.3 percent to $27.42, while Brazil's state operated oil
company Petrobras (PBR.N) was down 0.8 percent to $101.27.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-stocks-adrs-idUSN0340538120070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>adr report - adrs rally as shares play catch - up</title></story></items>