<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>12:53 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Amounts in U.S. dollars)VANCOUVER, British Columbia Jan 3 (Reuters) - The value of
Canadian mergers and acquisitions nearly doubled in 2006
boosted by two blockbuster mining deals, KPMG Corporate Finance
said on Wednesday, predicting another strong year for deals
globally. The audit, tax and advisory firm said $173.6 billion worth
of M&amp;A deals were done in Canada last year, up from $89 billion
in 2005. The number of deals increased by 26 percent, with
1,720 closing in 2006, the analysis, based on data supplied by
Thomson Financial Securities Data, showed. "It's frothy with capital out there," said Peter Hatges, a
corporate finance partner in KPMG's Canadian Advisory Services
practice. "The increase in Canadian M&amp;A activity is partly due to
significant activity in Canada's mining and resource sector and
the high prices for commodities due to buoyant global demand.
But that's not the whole story, particularly in the middle
market," he said in a statement. Private equity firms continue to be very active, increasing
competition for deals and driving up transaction prices, KPMG
said. "We continue to see the M&amp;A market globally exhibiting
strength given the abundance of available capital and the need
for companies to achieve economies of scale in the global
marketplace," Hatges said. Among Canadian companies, the purchase of Toronto-based
Falconbridge, the world's third largest nickel producer, by
Xstrata Plc. XTA.L for $18.2 billion was last year's largest
deal. A close second was world No. 2 nickel producer Inco Ltd.'s
N.TO takeover by Brazil's Cia Vale do Rio Doce (VALE5.SA)
(RIO.N) for $18 billion. The third and fourth largest deals also involved mining
companies. Barrick Gold Corp. (ABX.TO) bought smaller rival
Placer Dome Inc. for $10.2 billion and Goldcorp Inc. (G.TO)
acquired Glamis Gold Ltd. for $8.7 billion. ($1=$1.17 Canadian)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/canada-mergers-idUSN0340463220070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A</value></value></sectors><title>value of canadian m &amp; a deals doubles in 2006 - study</title></story></items>