<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:04 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates to early afternoon)NEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. stocks rallied on
Wednesday -- the first trading day of 2007 -- as falling oil
prices and news that Home Depot's (HD.N) embattled chief
executive resigned spurred optimism among investors returning
from a four-day break. Shares of Home Depot Inc. (HD.N) led gains, rising 3.1
percent to $41.40 and pushing the Dow Jones industrial average
to a record high. The Nasdaq jumped more than 1 percent. "The indications early on were that we would get a nice
rally and it was supported by some of the economic data this
morning," said Paul Nolte, director of investments at Hinsdale
Investments in Hinsdale, Illinois. "It's a combination of the
oil off and the Home Depot news. I think the Home Depot news
definitely lifted a cloud from around that stock." The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI was up 105.74
points, or 0.85 percent, at 12,568.89. The Standard &amp; Poor's
500 Index .SPX was up 8.76 points, or 0.62 percent, at
1,427.06. The Nasdaq Composite Index .IXIC was up 33.80
points, or 1.40 percent, at 2,449.09. Home Depot Chief Executive Robert Nardelli, who came under
fire last year for a pay package, left the retailer in a
mutual decision with its board of directors.For details, see
[ID:nN03383942] Oil prices fell 4.2 percent as mild weather in the U.S.
Northeast cut demand for fuel in the world's biggest heating
oil market. U.S. crude oil CLc1 fell $2.62 to $58.43 a
barrel, sparking optimism that lower energy costs could help
corporate profits. Adding support to the market, the Institute for Supply
Management said its manufacturing index for December rose more
than expected. The Dow earlier hit an all-time high of 12,580.35. U.S. stock markets were closed on Monday for the New
Year's Day holiday and on Tuesday for a day of mourning for
former U.S. President Gerald Ford.










</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-stocks-idUSN0340839720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>us stocks - shares rise as oil falls , home depot jumps</title></story></items>