<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:09 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 U.S. stocks inaugurated 2007
with strong gains on Wednesday after a drop in oil prices and a
stronger-than-expected reading in a U.S. manufacturing gauge
sparked optimism about the economy and corporate profits. The view that moderate economic growth would give the
Federal Reserve little impetus to cut interest rates sent bond
prices lower, erasing early gains. The dollar, meanwhile,
rallied to two-month highs. The Institute for Supply Management (ISM) said its
manufacturing index climbed to 51.4, above the 50 threshold
that separates expansion in the sector from contraction. Oil prices fell as mild weather in the U.S. Northeast cut
demand for fuel in the world's biggest heating oil market.  
U.S. crude CLc1 fell $2.41 to $58.65 a barrel. The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI was up 104.38
points, or 0.84 percent, at 12,567.53. The Standard &amp; Poor's
500 Index .SPX was up 8.82 points, or 0.62 percent, at
1,427.15. The Nasdaq Composite Index .IXIC was up 34.78
points, or 1.44 percent, at 2,450.07. Shares of retailers Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT.N) and Home
Depot Inc. (HD.N) led gains. Shares of Wal-Mart rose after the
world's largest retailer estimated over the weekend that its
December same-store sales rose more than it had expected in the
crucial holiday shopping period. Stock in home improvement retailer Home Depot advanced
after the resignation of its chairman and chief executive
revived takeover talk. ISM said its manufacturing index for December rose to 51.4
from a November reading of 49.5. "It's not huge, but the economy seems like it has firmed,"
said Robert Macintosh, chief economist at Eaton Vance
Management in Boston. Shares of Wal-Mart rose 3.1 percent to $47.63, while shares
of Home Depot gained 3.2 percent to $41.43. Before slipping at mid-morning, bond prices rose when the
ADP National Employment Report showed private sector employers
shed 40,000 jobs last month, the first contraction in private
sector employment in nearly four years. The report flew in the
face of consensus forecasts for a solid rise. Key data on U.S. employment are due on Friday from the U.S.
Labor Department. Economists, according to a median estimate
culled from a Reuters poll, expect that 110,000 new jobs were
added to U.S. payrolls in December. In early afternoon, benchmark 10-year notes were flat on
the day, yielding 4.68 percent, having erased earlier gains. Led by strong gains against European currencies including
sterling, the euro and the Swiss franc, the dollar was set for
its biggest rise in around six months against a basket of six
major currencies =USD. The euro EUR= was trading down 0.8 percent on the day at
$1.3175, while sterling tumbled more than 1 percent to $1.9485
GBP= in its biggest daily decline since July 2005. The dollar
was up 0.7 percent at 119.63 yen JPY= after reaching as high
as 119.65 on electronic trading platform EBS. Minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's most recent policy
meeting due at 2 p.m. (1900 GMT) were expected to shed some
more light on the likely outlook for interest rates.
 (Additional reporting by Caroline Valetkevitch, David McMahon,
John Parry)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-global-idUSN0346546520070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>global markets - stocks , dlr up on factory index , oil price fall</title></story></items>