<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:12 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON These are tough times for bond investors, with equities showing no sign of cooling and the U.S. and global economies still too robust to persuade central bankers to cut interest rates.A stronger-than-expected U.S. manufacturing report on Wednesday will have done little to cheer those hoping for the Federal Reserve to ease soon.It adds to the hawkish sentiment in the euro zone, Britain and Japan.New figures from Citigroup, meanwhile, confirm what many already suspected -- that most substantial gains on government bonds last year came from foreign exchange plays, not the underlying debt itself.The investment bank's benchmark index of mainly developed government bonds showed returns of just 0.71 percent in 2006 in local currency terms. Compare that with an 18.78 percent rise on the MSCI all-country world stock index .MSCI.At a more detailed level, U.S. Treasuries returned 3.12 percent in dollar terms, British gilts just 0.50 percent in sterling, and Japanese government bonds 0.30 percent in yen. Euro zone bonds lost 0.42 percent for euro holders.The Citigroup indexes suggest, however, that unhedged dollar investors had a better time of it. For them, Britain returned 14.57 percent, and the euro zone 11.32 percent.The spreads, of course, came courtesy of the weakening dollar, which declined around 8.5 percent against a basket of currencies =USD during the year and more than that against the likes of the euro EUR= and pound GBP=.But similar benefits will have accrued to unhedged dollar investors making equity plays overseas, meaning that even those who got the more robust gains from bonds could have done far better on many of the world's bourses.BAD NEWS, GOOD NEWSSo what about this year? Investors have entered 2007 clearly expecting more of the same for now.Reuters asset allocation polls  showed bond holdings at the end of December were higher than 12 months previously, but below highs of the past two years.U.S., continental European and British investors were all underweight in bonds and expecting to stay that way for at least three months. A Merrill Lynch poll showed 65 percent of fund managers were underweight bonds.The key for bonds this year likely will be how much the U.S. economy slows and whether this translates into central banks lowering interest rates globally.The European Central Bank and central banks of England and Japan are showing no such proclivity whatsoever and are instead leaning toward hikes.Prospects for U.S. rates under the Federal Reserve have been different following its pause after a long tightening cycle. But any hopes for near-term easing probably went out the window with Wednesday's manufacturing data.Futures markets are pricing in roughly 50 basis points of Fed easing this year, which would take the fed funds rate down to 4.75 percent. Only a month ago, however, futures were discounting 75 basis points of rate cuts.The Institute for Supply Management's manufacturing index for December bounced back to 51.4 from 49.5 in November. Readings above 50 denote expansion in the sector and readings below denote contraction.Research by investment bank HSBC economists Ian Morris and Ryan Wang earlier in the week noted that an ISM below 50 usually stays that way for eight or nine months and presages a Fed easing phase.HSBC is projecting a sharper-than-expected U.S. slowdown and five Fed rate cuts by the end of the year.The rub for bond investors is that even in this rate-cutting scenario, the bank researcher saw already relatively low long-end U.S. bond yields dropping less than half a point from current levels -- hardly a bonanza.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-markets-bonds-performance-idUSL0310814120070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>woes look set to stay for bond investors</title></story></items>