<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:20 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>CHICAGO Shares of Goodyear Tire &amp; Rubber Co. GT.N rose 9.5 percent on Wednesday after the No. 1 U.S. tire maker projected savings from a new labor contract well above what analysts had expected.The shares reached their highest price since May 2002 after the company obtained relief from long-term union retiree health-care obligations and forecast hefty savings from improved productivity.The labor pact ended a nearly three-month strike by the United Steelworkers union. With the strike resolved, analysts expect Goodyear to turn toward announced plans to sell assets, such as its engineered products business, and a possible equity offering.A Goodyear spokesman declined to comment.Union members went on strike at 16 Goodyear facilities in the United States and Canada on October 5. They began returning to work Tuesday after ratifying new contracts last week.The projected savings imply increased attrition rates for union workers that may come in part from future buyouts, J.P. Morgan analyst Himanshu Patel said in a note to clients.Patel, who has an "overweight" rating on Goodyear, also said the company likely would look to close a non-union plant in North America to meet its goal for capacity cuts, and also may trim non-union health-care and pension benefits.Deutsche Bank upgraded Goodyear to "buy" from "hold" on Tuesday, mainly due to much-larger-than-expected projected cost savings from the new labor contract. It said this addressed some of its long-term concerns about the tire maker's competitiveness.Goodyear expects up to $610 million in savings under the three-year contract, and $300 million of annual savings thereafter. The agreement allows Goodyear to hire new workers at lower wage and benefit levels.The company agreed to investments in its North American plants but will trim capacity with the closing of a Texas tire plant, putting it closer to its goal for reducing high-cost tire production capacity in North America.Shares of Goodyear were up $2 at $22.99 in midday trade on the New York Stock Exchange.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-goodyear-shares-idUSN0339855220070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>goodyear shares jump on savings from labor pact</title></story></items>