<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:00 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>FRANKFURT Jan 3 European stocks eked out minor
gains on Wednesday as rising technology, health care and
financial shares offset losses for miners such as Anglo American
(AAL.L) and Rio Tinto (RIO.L) as well as energy stocks. Shares in Europe moved back into positive territory late in
the session in the wake of a Wall Street rally on the back of
stronger than expected U.S. manufacturing data. The FTSEurofirst 300 index of top European shares .FTEU3
closed 0.07 percent up at 1,502.84 points, having touched
1,504.18 points in intraday trading, its highest level since
February 2001. The narrower DJ EuroSTOXX 50 index .STOXX50E rose 0.15
percent to 4,188.24 points. "The market is in very good shape," said a trader in
Germany, where the top-30 DAX index .GDAXI rose 0.15 percent. But some other market watchers were more cautious. "We've had four really good years on the trot, and some sort
of consolidation could be due, though it may not come until
after the first quarter," said Mike Lenhoff, chief strategist at
Brewin Dolphin. Royal Bank of Scotland (RBS.L) rose 1.9 percent after the
stock was tipped by several analysts for a strong year. Dresdner
Kleinwort named RBS its top UK bank pick for 2007 and UBS said:
"RBS remains the cheapest large bank anywhere." Bank shares firmed 0.6 percent on the DJ EuroStoxx sector
index .SX7P. Roche (ROG.VX) rose 2.3 percent and GlaxoSmithKline (GSK.L)
added 1.8 percent. Healthcare information company IMS Health
said on Wednesday that global pharmaceutical sales grew 5
percent in the 12 months to October in leading markets. Mining stocks slumped, with Anglo American and Rio Tinto
shedding 3.7 percent each as copper tumbled below $6,000 a tonne
-- its lowest since April -- on worries about rising
inventories.
 STEEL WORRIES Steelmakers took a beating after Credit Suisse cut its
recommendation on the sector to "underweight" from
"marketweight", foreseeing risks in the next three to six
months. "We expect earnings to fall through the quarters ahead ...
We believe the risk premium in steel equities is currently too
low and has to rise," Credit Suisse said in a note. Acerinox (ACX.MC) dropped 2.6 percent, Salzgitter (SZGG.DE)
fell 2.3 percent and ThyssenKrupp (TKAG.DE) lost 2 percent. CSR (CSR.L) fell 2.9 percent after the British maker of
Bluetooth semiconductor chips was named at the centre of a
patent infringement case brought against Nokia (NOK1V.HE),
Samsung Electronics (000830.KS) and Matsushita (6752.T). "I think it's far too early to say but apparently innocuous
patent cases can blow up into a bit of a mine," said Nomura
analyst Sean Murphy. "It could take years before it will be obvious whether it
represents a serious threat," he added.Nokia shares rose 0.6 percent. Shares in Total (TOTF.PA) fell 1.1 percent and Royal Dutch
Shell (RDSa.L) eased 0.3 percent in London as oil prices dived
more than $2 a barrel to less than $59. Mild weather in the U.S.
Northeast cut demand for fuel in the world's biggest heating oil
market. On the economic data front, the U.S. Institute for Supply
Management said its index of national factory activity climbed
to 51.4 from 49.5 in November, above the 50-point threshold that
separates growth from contraction. Wall Street forecasts had
centered around 49.9. The figures suggested the U.S. economy would kick off the
year on a stronger footing than some had believed and bolstered
the case for no change in monetary policy from the Federal
Reserve. "The apparent slowdown in manufacturing seems more moderate
than might have been feared," said Pierre Ellis, senior
economist at Decision Economics. "That makes the general
economy look steadier and even firmer than it was thought to
be." At 1720 GMT, the Dow Jones industrial average DJI was up
0.8 percent, the S&amp;P 500 .SPX was 0.6 percent higher and the
Nasdaq .IXIC was 1.4 percent higher.
 (Additional reporting by Sophie Hares in London)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-europe-shares-idUSL0318843220070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>europe stocks edge up after u . s . gains , miners weak</title></story></items>