<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:34 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds analyst's comments, details and background) QUITO Jan 3 (Reuters) - Ecuador's incoming government is considering forcing bondholders to accept a buyback of the country's global bonds due in 2012 by threatening not to pay interest, Economy Minister designate Ricardo Patino said on Wednesday.     Patino, who was named by President-elect Rafael Correa as his economy minister, was asked if he had considered announcing that the government would not pay interest to force creditors to accept a buyback to be managed through a Dutch auction.     "This is an alternative and we are studying several alternatives," answered Patino in a television program, without giving more details.     A Dutch auction starts with an asking price that moves downward until it is accepted by a bidder.     In a later news conference, Patino distanced himself from his earlier comments, saying Ecuador has "a thousand options" to manage the country's debt.     "We have to see if there are resources to pay debt interests," he told reporters. "If we have it, we will pay it, and if not, we will call creditors."     Patino said he was earlier answering a question about restructuring options and reiterated the suspension of payments was only one of many alternatives.     Correa, who will be sworn in as president on Jan. 15, has caused jitters on Wall street with threats to interrupt bond payments as he seeks to lower the country's debt burden.     "These kind of comments just add to the ambiguity surrounding the outlook of Ecuador and its debt," said Gianfranco Bertozzi, an analyst with Lehman Brothers in New York.     "Markets in the last several weeks have began to price in a suspension of payments ... The risk of a default event seems at 50 percent or greater as priced in by the market at the moment," he added.     Some Wall Street analysts say Correa will strike a more market-friendly stance once in office.     "The market has seen these comments as a possibility that they will not call a default," said Marjorie Hernandez, a Latin America analyst at HSBC Securities.     Patino's comments show that the incoming government is looking for other ways to manage the debt instead of calling a default, she said.     The yield spread between Ecuador's global bonds and comparable U.S. Treasuries tightened on Wednesday by 22 basis points to 900 basis points, according to J.P. Morgan's Emerging Markets Bond Index Plus 11EMJ .JPMEMBIPLUS.     On Tuesday, Correa said his government may adjust its debt service payments if the $900 million left in arrears by the current government generates budgetary problems this year.     Correa has vowed to restructure all of the Andean country's commercial, bilateral and multilateral debt. Ecuador's public foreign debt totaled $10.3 billion in November, according to the Economy Ministry.  (Additional reporting by Alexandra Valencia)  ((Reporting by Alonso Soto, Quito newsroom; editing by Gary Crosse; e-mail: alonso.soto@reuters.com; +593-2252-3560 ext. 102)) Keywords: ECUADOR ECONOMY/DEBT  (C) Reuters 2007.  All rights reserved.  Republication or redistribution ofReuters content, including by caching, framing or similar means, is expresslyprohibited without the prior written consent of Reuters. Reuters and the Reuterssphere logo are registered trademarks and trademarks of the Reuters group ofcompanies around the world.nN03406083</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/idUSN0340608320070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - ecuador mulls bond buyback , debt payment suspension</title></story></items>