<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:40 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK The departure of Home Depot Inc.'s (HD.N) top executive reignited takeover talk about the home improvement retailer, but analysts dismissed the idea again, saying the $100 billion company was probably too large to be bought out any time soon.Home Depot said on Wednesday that in a mutual decision, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Robert Nardelli had resigned. The retailer was the subject last year of media and market speculation that it is ripe for a leveraged buyout.After media outlets named Kohlberg, Kravis &amp; Roberts and Texas Pacific Group as being interested, Home Depot said in early December that it had not had any discussions about a potential buyout by private equity firms or a recapitalization.A few weeks later the company disclosed that a large activist investor firm, Relational Investors, was planning to launch a proxy fight that included the creation of a board committee that would consider strategic alternatives -- such as the sale of the company -- and management performance.But analysts, bankers and private equity investors agree there is a major obstacle to a deal: the equity and the debt that a leveraged buyout exceeding $100 billion would require.IT'S JUST TOO BIGAnd analysts said on Wednesday that while Nardelli's departure might be sparking yet another round of speculation on a possible sale -- as is often the case when a top executive leaves with little notice -- Home Depot is probably just too big."There have been a lot of rumors that Home Depot is a private equity play. We would not read that much into that. We just think that it's way too large of a fish to swallow," said Richard Steinberg, president of Steinberg Global Asset Management in Boca Raton, Florida. His firms owns shares in both Home Depot and rival Lowe's Cos. Inc. (LOW.N).A $100 billion deal would be far larger than anything yet attempted, and surpass the largest takeout ever -- KKR's $25.1 billion buyout of RJR Nabisco Inc. in 1988.Arun Daniel, a consumer analyst with ING Investments, said that LBO speculation is helping the stock, but is unrealistic."The LBO scenario, while the math works, from a practical perspective, it's difficult because simply the size of the financing. And based on my discussion with major bankers, it's very difficult to pull off," Daniel said.While real estate sales and co-investments by multiple private equity firms could help a Home Depot leveraged buyout, most bankers and private equity investors say that a $40 billion to $50 billion LBO is about all the market can handle right now.Indeed, several bankers and private equity investors told Reuters that the market is capable of handling roughly $30 billion of high yield debt and another $10 billion or so of bank debt.Since private equity firms rarely, if ever, use more than 10 percent of their funds for a single deal, and there are only a handful of funds with more than $15 billion, it would severely limit the number firms capable of doing the deal.Indeed, Goldman Sachs analyst Matthew Fassler said in a research note that while its numbers show that a leveraged buyout of Home Depot makes sense in terms of returns up until the $46 level, the size of the deal is a barrier because of the limits of the financing markets."We therefore think an LBO is relatively unlikely," Fassler wrote.In the U.S. options market, many investors greeted the surprise resignation by accumulating bullish calls as they bet on more upside potential in the shares of the home improvement retailer, according to Jon Najarian, co-founder of optionmonster.com, a Web information site in Chicago."They are also optimistic about Home Depot's board being receptive to merger combinations and/or a leveraged buyout," he added.Home Depot shares rose 3.3 percent to $41.49 in New York Stock Exchange trading.During the first half of the session, roughly 39,500 calls and 9,300 puts traded in Home Depot, above its average daily volume of 39,930 contracts, according to market research firm Track Data.(Additional reporting by Michael Flaherty and Nicole Maestri in New York and Doris Frankel and Ben Klayman in Chicago)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-homedepot-nardelli-takeover-idUSN0339472320070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>home depot ceo ' s departure reignites takeover talk</title></story></items>