<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:03 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds comments, sales details, stock activity, byline) By Jessica WohlCHICAGO Jan 3 (Reuters) - Walgreen Co. WAG.N, the
largest U.S. drugstore chain, said on Wednesday that sales at
its stores open at least a year rose 7.9 percent in December,
driven by stronger sales of prescription medications despite
the $4 generic plan in place at Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT.N)
and other low-priced chains. Total sales rose 14.4 percent to $5.13 billion. Pharmacy same-store sales rose 9.6 percent, while
same-store sales of general, or front-end, merchandise rose 5.8
percent. Total December pharmacy sales rose 15.6 percent, and the
number of prescriptions filled at comparable stores increased
4.8 percent. "Walgreen's December sales showed, once again, no impact
from Wal-Mart's $4 generics program," Goldman Sachs analyst
John Heinbockel wrote in a note to clients. He has a "neutral"
rating on the shares. Wal-Mart started selling certain generic drugs for $4 per
monthly prescription in Florida in September. By late November,
the program was in place at all of its 3,810 pharmacies and was
matched by rivals such as Target Corp. (TGT.N). But major drugstore chains such as Walgreen said consumers
would continue to fill prescriptions at their stores, despite
some higher prices, due to their convenient locations and
customer service. Walgreen and its rivals have not matched
Wal-Mart's $4 strategy. Walgreen said that having an extra weekend day and one
fewer weekday in December compared with a year earlier hurt
comparable pharmacy sales by 2.7 percentage points. Customers
tend to fill more prescriptions on weekdays than weekends, and
December 2006 had an additional Sunday and one fewer Thursday
compared with December 2005. Pharmacy sales accounted for 56.8 percent of sales in the
month, Deerfield, Illinois-based Walgreen said. Walgreen has higher annual sales than rival CVS Corp.
(CVS.N) but fewer stores. CVS operated 6,197 stores as of Nov.
25, while Walgreen had 5,584 stores as of Dec. 31. Shares of Walgreen were up 35 cents, or 0.76 percent, at
$46.24 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange
after rising as high as $46.69 earlier in the day. The shares
fell 7.3 percent on Sept. 21, the day that Wal-Mart unveiled
its $4 generics strategy. Since then, the shares are relatively
unchanged.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/walgreen-sales-idUSN0338467420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - walgreen dec . sales rise , driven by prescriptions</title></story></items>