<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>13:52 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Corrects figures provided by Apache Energy Corp. on amount of
production shut in)  NEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - Offshore contractors working
for Plains All American Pipeline L.P. (PAA.N) were analyzing
the extent of damage to the High Island Pipeline System (HIPS)
in the Gulf of Mexico after successfully plugging the leaking
line over the weekend, a Plains spokesman said on Wednesday. The HIPS system was severed on Dec. 24 by a tanker's
anchor, according to the U.S. Transportation Department. The
line was immediately shut down, but the rupture caused a 1,000
barrel oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico. "Since the line was plugged early Sunday all efforts have
been aimed at exposing the line and assessing the damage to the
line to determine what it is going to take to repair it," said
Plains spokesman Jordan Janak. Plains will not have an estimate of how long repairs will
take until a survey of the line has been completed, since the
company does not yet know how much of the line needs to be
replaced, Janak said. Since the line was shut down, 28,000 barrels per day of oil
production and 140 million cubic feet per day of natural gas
output from the High Islands and East Breaks sections of the
Gulf of Mexico has been closed off. Apache Energy Corp. (APA.N), Newfield Exploration Co.
(NFX.N) and Anadarko Petroleum Corp. (APC.N) all operate oil
and gas fields that are served by the HIPS pipeline. Apache said Wednesday it had shut in over 1,950 bpd of net
oil production and 4.9 million cfd of gas output due to the
pipeline disruption. The plugging of the line has helped to minimize the
environmental impact of the spill, which occurred about 30
miles southeast of Galveston, Texas, according to the U.S.
Coast Guard. None of the spilled oil has washed ashore and the
Coast Guard expects it to continue to drift away from land and
to quickly disperse.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/pipeline-operations-hips-idUSN0339467320070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>corrected - official - repair work set for us gulf hips oil pipe</title></story></items>