<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:16 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>CHICAGO Robert Nardelli renovated Home Depot Inc.'s corporate structure when he joined the retailer back in 2000, but the repair bill was too high for investors and its share price lagged the broader market."I think the focus clearly was on how much he was paid given how much he delivered for shareholders. The stock has languished here for some period of time," said Bill Schultz, chief investment officer at McQueen, Ball &amp; Associates, a Home Depot shareholder.Home Depot, the No. 2 U.S. retailer, on Wednesday said that it was a mutual decision between the board of directors and Chairman and Chief Executive Nardelli, 58, that he leave the company. He was replaced by 57-year-old Vice Chairman Frank Blake.Nardelli, who was one of three executives in the running to succeed Jack Welch as head of General Electric Co. years ago, came to Home Depot with much fanfare in December 2000, and was credited with overhauling purchasing and technology systems, saving the company money."At the time, when he came in, he certainly brought the skills that the company needed, and he brought the company -- I would say -- almost to the 21st century," Arun Daniel, an analyst at ING Investments, said."He changed all the systems, created more of a centralized structure within the company (and) communications systems improved."But Nardelli also quickly drew mixed reviews from workers used to the more free-wheeling management style of founders Bernie Marcus and Arthur Blank.Meanwhile, Home Depot came under increasing competition from rival Lowe's Cos. Inc., which developed a reputation for better customer service and Home Depot's stock stagnated.BIG MONEYIn 2006, discontent with Nardelli swelled as investors questioned his pay package, which exceeded that of most retail executives.Through the end of fiscal 2006, Nardelli received $119.2 million in salary and bonus, before stock options. The company said on Wednesday that Nardelli would receive a severance package valued at $210 million, including a $20 million cash payment, the acceleration of unvested deferred stock awards, unvested options, vested deferred shares and other compensation.Nardelli further inflamed critics by refusing to take questions or review the company's performance at its 2006 annual meeting.Meanwhile, Home Depot stock lost 8 percent between December 5, 2000, when Nardelli's appointment was announced, and the close of trading last Friday on the New York Stock Exchange.The company also faces a probe for its options dating practices and said last month that it found almost 20 years of options backdating, resulting in $200 million in unrecorded expenses. It also said there was no intentional wrongdoing by any person who was a member of the management team or board at that time.Finally, investment firm Relational Investors LLC said on December 18 that it planned to propose that a special panel of independent directors review the company's strategy. As of a filing made last month, Relational owns about 0.6 percent of Home Depot shares."Investors didn't like him, employees didn't like him, the stock market didn't like him," Jon Fisher, a portfolio manager at Fifth Third Asset Management, said."The increasing tide of negativity around there was just obviously too much and they just felt like they had to stem that tide, they had to make a change," Fisher added.In the end, analysts said Nardelli made some needed changes at Home Depot, but more needs to be done."He had a vision but he lacked on implementing it," Janna Sampson, fund manager at OakBrook Investments, said. "I have to give him mixed reviews; obviously the stock has not done particularly well."A Home Depot spokesman said Nardelli was not available for comment.(Additional reporting by Karen Jacobs, Nicole Maestri and Martha Graybow)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-homedepot-nardelli-newsmaker-idUSN0340011620070103</link><sectors><value><value>U.S., </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>pay , stock price doomed hd ' s nardelli : analysts</title></story></items>