<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:18 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK U.S. Federal Reserve officials agreed at their December meeting inflation was the predominant concern, but some felt the "subdued tone" of economic data meant risks to growth had increased, minutes released on Wednesday from the December 12 meeting show.The U.S. central bank at that meeting held benchmark interest rates steady at 5.25 percent, renewing a warning on inflation but also nodding to "mixed" economic signals and a "substantial" housing slowdown.  COMMENTARY: CARY LEAHEY, MANAGING DIRECTOR, DECISION ECONOMICS, NEW YORK:"I see more headlines that are bearish for bonds than are bullish, but the market could be higher because it already lost so much ground in December and there weren't any surprises in the headlines of the FOMC minutes at all."One bullish item for Treasuries was that several members of the Fed monetary policy committee saw a 'subdued tone' to the economic data and thought the downside risk to growth had increased. But this Fed meeting was held before the spate of reports, starting with retail sales in the middle of December, that showed the economy looking more resilient. So the one headline that could be viewed as bullish for bonds is probably, correctly, considered by the market to be out of date."Another item that could be seen as bullish for bonds is the fact that one FOMC member said the policymakers should open up the possibility of rates going in either direction, implying a chance of an ease." SAM RAHMAN, PORTFOLIO MANAGER, BARING ASSET MANAGEMENT INC., BOSTON:"The biggest change is the they are showing a little more anxiety about the economy. Inflation was a key focus, while they seemed to think the economy was chugging along just fine. Now, while inflation remains a key focus, the FOMC is showing clearer signs that the weakening economic environment has raised concerns. MICHAEL WOOLFOLK, SENIOR CURRENCY STRATEGIST, BANK OF NEW YORK, NEW YORK:"I don't find anything in the minutes that changes my view for either the economy or the dollar. Generally speaking, the minutes helped refine our understanding of where the Fed is in terms of policy. The Fed right now still believes there's upside risk to inflation, so there's a greater risk of a rate hike in the first quarter of the year than a rate cut. That should be supportive for the dollar at the margin. They indicate the data was on balance a bit weaker than expected, but wasn't weak enough to change the assessment of the economy and policy." LARA RHAME, SENIOR FX STRATEGIST, CREDIT SUISSE, NEW YORK:"I don't think there's anything really surprising here. I think people are taking tentative profits on their dollar gains so far today because the minutes are very much "permanent hold" kind of minutes and I think they reflect an FOMC that was discussing a somewhat more downbeat economy on December 12, that's what we're looking at today. So I think for that reason, certainly I would not have thought that they would have been dollar-positive." MARKET REACTION: - U.S. Treasury debt prices edge up after December Fed meeting minutes say downside risk to growth had increased.  - Dollar slips vs euro after Dec FOMC minutes say downside risk to growth has increased. The euro was now at $1.3164 EUR=, from about $1.3155 just before the release of the minutes. - U.S. stocks pare gains after Fed minutes.  - U.S. rate futures inch up on FOMC minutes, boost chances of Fed cut in first half 2007.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-usa-economy-fomc-instant-idUSN0351064320070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>instant view 2 - u . s . fed ' s fomc minutes from december 12</title></story></items>