<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:20 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>Jan 3 The following are the Federal Reserve's
staff forecasts as contained in the minutes released this year
of Federal Open Market Committee meetings: DEC. 12 FOMC: Minutes released on Jan. 3, 2007 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting indicated
that growth in economic activity had slowed to a pace below
that of the economy's long-run potential in the second half of
2006, partly as a result of the ongoing adjustment of the
housing sector. The rate of increase in real GDP was expected
to pick up gradually as the drag from the contraction in
residential construction diminished, returning towards the end
of 2007 to a rate close to the staff's estimate of potential
output growth. Core inflation was anticipated to edge down in
2007 and 2008 in response to a waning of the effects of higher
energy and import prices, a step-down in rent increases, and
the emergence of a small amount of slack in the economy." OCT. 24-25 FOMC: Minutes released on Nov. 15 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting indicated
that growth of real GDP had slowed further in the third
quarter, reflecting both a significant drag from the continuing
contraction in residential construction and a steep decline in
motor vehicle assemblies. Looking ahead, a gradual reduction in
the restraining effects of the contraction in residential
investment and further solid gains in consumer and business
spending were expected to lead to a pickup in GDP growth
through 2007 and into 2008. These gains in spending were likely
to be supported by past declines in energy prices and continued
gains in payroll employment and labor income. Real GDP was
expected to rise at a somewhat slower rate over the next two
years than in 2006 in part as a result of less impetus from
household wealth, interest rates, and fiscal policy. The
projected increase in real output over the next year or so was
a little below the staff's estimate of potential output growth,
leading to a lessening in pressures on resource utilization.
Core inflation was anticipated to edge down in 2007 and 2008
relative to the second half of this year because of the
diminishing impetus from the prices of energy and other
commodities and because of the modest easing in resource
utilization." SEPT. 20 FOMC: Minutes released on Oct. 11 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting indicated
that real GDP growth would continue to slow into the second
half of 2006 before strengthening gradually thereafter. By
2008, output was projected to be expanding at a pace about
equal to the staff's forecast of potential output growth. The
staff, however, had again reduced its projection for potential
GDP growth, and the projected slow pace of growth over the next
several quarters was thus consistent with an opening of only a
small gap in resource utilization. In the near term, the
cooling of the housing market and lower motor vehicle
production were expected to hold growth back. At the same time,
though, significantly lower energy prices, sustained increases
in labor income, and favorable labor market conditions were
anticipated to support expansion through the end of the year.
Further ahead, the lagged effects of the previous tightening of
monetary policy and waning stimulus from household wealth and
fiscal policy were anticipated to restrain growth, but the drag
from the downturn in residential construction was expected to
abate. Core consumer price inflation was projected to drop back
somewhat later this year and next, reflecting the emergence of
slack in the economy and lower energy costs." AUG. 8 FOMC; Minutes released on Aug. 29 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting indicated
that real GDP growth would slow in the second half of 2006 and
2007, and to a lower rate than had been anticipated in the
prior forecast. The marking down of the outlook was largely
attributable to the annual revision of the national income and
product accounts, which involved downward revisions to actual
GDP growth in prior years and prompted reductions in the
staff's estimate of potential output. The slowdown in the
housing market, the effects of higher energy prices on
household purchasing power, the waning impetus of household
wealth effects on consumer spending, and the effects of past
policy tightening were expected to hold economic growth below
potential over the next six quarters. Core consumer price
inflation was projected to drop back somewhat later this year
and next, mainly as the effects of higher energy and import
prices abated." JUNE 28-29 FOMC; Minutes released on July 20 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting indicated
that, after the significant deceleration of real GDP in the
current quarter from the first quarter of 2006, growth would
proceed through the end of 2007 at a pace a bit below the rate
of growth of the economy's potential. The outlook for modest
growth of real GDP reflected a slowdown in the housing market,
the effects of past policy tightening, and a diminished boost
to consumer spending from increases in household wealth. Core
consumer price inflation was projected to have stepped up in
the second quarter from its average pace over the preceding
several quarters but to then drop back somewhat, albeit to a
level higher than previously forecasted, as energy and import
prices flatten out and some slack emerges in labor and product
markets." MAY 10 FOMC; Minutes released on May 31 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting showed real
GDP growth moderating somewhat from the average pace of the
previous several quarters. The projected deceleration of real
GDP reflected the lagged effects of the tightening of monetary
policy, the waning impetus from increases in household wealth,
and reduced stimulus from fiscal policy. While higher energy
prices were expected to boost inflation in the near term,
structural productivity was strong, and the influence of higher
energy and material costs was thought likely to moderate. Thus,
consumer prices, after increasing at a faster rate in the first
half of the year, were expected to decelerate later this year
and next year." MARCH 27-28 FOMC; Minutes released on April 18 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting showed real
GDP expanding briskly in the current quarter. Economic growth
was expected to moderate later this year. The level of output
in the current quarter was estimated to be close to the
economy's potential and was anticipated to remain so over the
projection period. Core PCE inflation was expected to move
slightly higher in 2006 because of cost pressures induced by
high energy and import prices and to step back down in 2007 as
these cost pressures were anticipated to abate." JAN. 31 FOMC; Minutes released on Feb. 21 "The staff forecast prepared for this meeting suggested
that, after slow growth in the fourth quarter of 2005, real GDP
would expand at a fairly robust pace over the first half of
this year, boosted in part by spending on recovery activities
associated with the hurricanes. Thereafter, real GDP growth was
expected to moderate, importantly reflecting a reduced impetus
to consumption from house price appreciation and some slowing
in residential housing expenditures. Core PCE inflation was
expected to be a touch higher this year than in 2005, largely
because of the pass-through of higher energy and nonfuel import
prices, but, with energy prices leveling out, core inflation
was projected to drop back modestly in 2007."

</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/economy-fed-forecasts-idUSFED20070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>factbox - fed staff forecasts from fomc minutes</title></story></items>