<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:45 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>FRANKFURT Jan 3 German drugs and chemicals
group Merck KGaA (MRCG.DE) is mulling a sale of its generic
drugs business, which could be worth about 4 billion euros
($5.3 billion), business daily Handelsblatt reported on
Wednesday. Citing company and industry sources, the German newspaper
said Merck's supervisory board had already given the go-ahead
for the company to look for a buyer. Merck was not immediately available for comment. Merck's key business area is liquid crystals, which are
used in flat-screen televisions and mobile-phone displays. Its
generics business made sales of 1.796 billion euros in 2005,
about 20 percent of the company's total sales. Merck is also buying Swiss biotech company Serono SEO.VX
for $13.3 billion, which it is financing mainly through a
syndicated loan. Handelsblatt said in an advance copy of an article due to
be published on Thursday that financial investors were the most
likely buyers of Merck's business in generic drugs. Generic drugs are biologically equivalent to but usually
cheaper than brand-name drugs. They can be legally produced as
imitations of brand-name drugs for which patents have expired,
or where no legal patent exists. Europe's fast-growing generic pharmaceuticals industry is
widely expected to consolidate further over the next few years,
as companies seek to position themselves better in the
high-risk business amid tough competition. Swiss drugmaker Novartis (NOVN.VX) bought generics company
Hexal for $8 billion in 2005. More recently, Barr
Pharmaceuticals Inc. BRL.N said it would buy Croatian
drugmaker Pliva PLV.ZA for $2.5 billion last October. Merck KGaA is now the world's fourth-biggest generics
drugmaker, behind Israel's Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd.
TEVA.O, Novartis's Sandoz unit and Barr.
 ($1=.7532 Euro)




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/merck-generics-idUSL0323685020070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A</value></value></sectors><title>german merck mulls generics sale - newspaper</title></story></items>