<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:29 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 The price of copper tumbled to
a near 9-month low in futures trade on Wednesday after a hefty
influx of visible London warehouse supplies fueled speculation
of a supply glut hitting the market this year, analysts said. At the New York Mercantile Exchange's COMEX division,
copper for March delivery HGH7 ended down 22.20 cents, or 7.7
percent, at $2.6490 a lb, after dealing between $2.6450 and
$2.7980. The $2.6450 low was the cheapest March copper has been
since April 12, 2006. Spot January HGF7 fell 22.15 cents at $2.6325, a shade
above its session trough at $2.6320. Final estimated copper volumes reached 14,000 lots. Since topping out at $4.16 a lb in early May of last year,
COMEX copper prices have erased more than 36 percent of their
value. But, traders were quick to point out that prices were
still up a respectable 33 percent year over year. "I think the market had already made a pretty substantial
move to the upside, that was overdone, and now we are
correcting it to an extent," said one COMEX floor dealer. Inventory data on Tuesday showed copper stocks at LME
warehouses surged 7,775 tonnes. An additional 1,975 tonnes were
reported overnight on Wednesday, bringing total stocks to
192,550 tonnes -- their highest since March 2004. "Stocks were up again today, and we are in sight of the
significant 200,000 a tonne mark on the London Metal Exchange,
with this, no doubt, being the prime catalyst behind the change
in psychology," said Edward Meir, metals analyst with Man
Financial. The almost daily increases in copper warehouse stocks were
seen as a direct reflection of the market's falling demand
growth, analysts said. "The stocks keep building. It seems like the supply
problems have been pretty much resolved, leading to greater
availability, and I think people are intent upon liquidating
any excess inventory and moving to more of a hand-to-mouth
fashion ... that is helping to contribute to the pressure on
copper values," said Steve Platt, an analyst with Archer
Financials in Chicago. Higher inventory levels, softer demand in the U.S. and
China and receding threats of supply disruptions from Chile
were all seen contributing to the market's bearish tone. Chinese consumption of refined copper is expected to fall 7
percent this year as higher copper prices were seen dampening
demand. Meanwhile, Codelco, the world's largest copper producer,
said on Tuesday it had sold 80 percent of its allocated 1.5
million tonnes of refined copper in 2007, and will sell the
remaining 20 percent on the spot market.[nN02331044] On the economic front, a survey showing the U.S. factory
sector expanded in December did little to sway the broad-based
selling Wednesday. The Institute for Supply Management said its index of
national factory activity climbed to 51.4 from 49.5 in November
-- above the 50 threshold that separates growth from
contraction. On the LME, three-months copper MCU3 sank to a session
low at $5,822 a tonne, a level last seen on April 7, before
settling at $5,855, down $255 or 4.2 percent from Tuesday's
kerb close.




















</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-copper-comex-idUSN0351875420070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>us copper futures sink 7 pct on inventory builds</title></story></items>