<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:48 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds Fed minutes and economist comment, updates prices) By Chris ReeseNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. government bond prices
rose slightly on Wednesday after minutes from the Federal
Reserve's last policy meeting revealed central bank members saw
increased downside risks to economic growth. That concern over potentially slower growth helped to
marginally boost investor expectations that the Fed may be
considering the possibility of an official interest rate cut
later this year. "One bullish item for Treasuries was that several members
of the Fed monetary policy committee saw a 'subdued tone' to
the economic data and thought the downside risk to growth had
increased," said Cary Leahey, managing director at Decision
Economics in New York. Leahy cautioned however that a good portion of the
indicators released since the Dec. 12 Fed policy meeting have
shown an economy that is looking relatively resilient, and the
central bank's concern over slowing growth was based on
relatively old data. "The one headline that could be viewed as bullish for bonds
is probably, correctly, considered by the market to be out of
date," Leahy said. Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR were trading 1/32
higher in price for a yield of 4.68 percent. Early in the day, Treasuries rallied after a surprise
contraction in a private jobs report hinted the nonfarm
payrolls report on Friday could prove soft. After the data,
economists at some Wall Street banks cut their forecasts for
the government's nonfarm payrolls report. Data showed that U.S. private sector employment likely
declined by 40,000 in December, the first contraction since
April 2003, according to the ADP National Employment Report. "Clearly, going into the employment data this Friday,
people coming into the New Year with a clean book would
certainly feel that this (the ADP report) is something people
want to be buying bonds on," said Michael Cheah, vice president
and portfolio manager with AIG SunAmerica Asset Management in
Jersey City, New Jersey. However, those early bond gains were later tempered by a
stronger-than-expected U.S. factory index. The Institute for
Supply Management's December manufacturing report reading was
51.4, above the 50 mark that divides expansion from
contraction. Economists had forecast the index would rise to
49.9 from November's 49.5 reading. Two-year notes US2YT=RR were trading 1/32 higher in price
to yield 4.78 percent from 4.81 percent late on Tuesday, while
five-year notes US5YT=RR were trading 1/32 higher in price
for a yield of 4.67 percent from 4.68 percent. Thirty-year notes US30YT=RR were trading 6/32 higher in
price for a yield of 4.78 percent.
  (Additional reporting by Ellen Freilich)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-bonds-idUSN0352520420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - slightly higher as fed sees growth risk</title></story></items>