<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:55 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>DOHA Top seed Nikolay Davydenko and number two Ivan Ljubicic marched into the quarter-finals of the $1 million Qatar Open on Wednesday.Russian Davydenko defeated Swedish doubles specialist Jonas Bjorkman 6-4 6-3 while Croatian Ljubicic put out 2002 champion Younes El Aynaoui of Morocco 6-3 6-4.Davydenko meets Belgium's Olivier Rochus in the last eight on Thursday while Ljubicic faces Russian Mikhail Youzhny.The other quarter-finals pit third seed Marcos Baghdatis against Swede Robin Soderling, and fourth seed Andy Murray with Max Mirnyi of Belarus.Cypriot Baghdatis outplayed Ruben Ramirez Hidalgo 6-2 6-0 while Briton Murray cruised past Christophe Rochus of Belgium 6-1 6-3.Mirnyi went through with a 6-3 6-3 victory over Swiss qualifier Marco Chiudinelli and Soderling eliminated Spain's Guillermo Garcia-Lopez 4-6 6-0 6-3.DOHA DEBUTANTOlivier Rochus crushed Italian Federico Luzzi 6-1 6-0 while Youzhny eased past French youngster Gael Monfils 6-4 6-2.Doha débutante Murray needed only 84 minutes to reach the last eight.The young Scot's fluid movement, excellent shot-making skills and effective baseline game helped him pull off several winners.Murray said he had been fighting a cold since landing in Doha."I am less than 100 percent fit, maybe I am 80-85 percent. I still have a persistent cough," he told reporters."The last four days I have not been feeling that well. But it was good to have a fast match today, I am very happy with that."Baghdatis toyed with Ramirez Hidalgo in a one-sided match with the Spaniard."It feels great to be in the quarter-finals of the first tournament of the new season," Baghdatis said."I'm moving very well and my serving is good. I'm really looking forward to the Australian Open later this month," added last year's Melbourne runner-up.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-tennis-men-qatar-idUSL0308194720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>top seed davydenko powers into qatar quarters</title></story></items>