<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:53 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Corrects to delete references to Dow holding onto minor
gains in paragraphs 3 and 9) By Emily ChasanNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. stocks declined slightly
on Wednesday -- the first trading day of 2007 -- as minutes
from the Federal Reserve's most recent meeting renewed
concerns about the economic slowdown.Fed officials agreed at their December meeting that
inflation was their predominant concern, but some felt risks
to economic growth had grown according to minutes released on
Wednesday. For details, see [ID:nN03408654] The Fed's minutes offset earlier optimism about lower oil
prices and the resignation of Home Depot's (HD.N) embattled
chief executive. "Traders questioned both growth in the U.S. economy and
whether the Fed is indeed done raising interest rates," said
Tim Biggam, options strategist at Man Securities, an options
brokerage firm in Chicago. The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI was down 13.70
points, or 0.11 percent, at 12,449.45. The Standard &amp; Poor's
500 Index .SPX was down 6.27 points, or 0.44 percent, at
1,412.03. The Nasdaq Composite Index .IXIC was down 16.55
points, or 0.69 percent, at 2,398.74. Earlier, the Dow hit an all-time high of 12,580.35. Shares of Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM.N) were the heaviest
weight on both the Dow and the S&amp;P 500 as crude oil prices
dropped. Exxon Mobil's stock lost 3.3 percent to $74.10 on the
New York Stock Exchange.  Oil prices fell 4 percent as mild weather in the U.S.
Northeast cut demand for fuel in the world's biggest heating
oil market. U.S. crude for February delivery CLc1 fell $2.73
to settle ato $58.32 a barrel, sparking optimism that high
energy costs would not weigh down corporate profits. A rise in shares of Home Depot Inc. and Wal-Mart Stores
Inc.(WMT.N) helped limit the Dow's decline. Home Depot Chief Executive Robert Nardelli, who came under
fire last year for a pay package, abruptly left the retailer
in a mutual decision with its board of directors.For details,
see [ID:nN03383942] Its shares shot up 2.8 percent to $41.29. Shares of Wal-Mart climbed 2.9 percent to $47.50 after the
retailer estimated over the weekend that December same-store
sales rose more than expected in the crucial holiday shopping
period. [ID:nN30286457] On the Nasdaq, shares of Apple Computer Inc. (AAPL.O)
ranked as the biggest decliner. Apple's stock was down 2.5
percent at $82.70.
 (Additional reporting by Doris Frankel in Chicago)










</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-stocks-idUSN0342279420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>corrected - us stocks - u . s . stocks dip after fed minutes</title></story></items>