<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:58 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts with AMF statement, closing share prices) By William Emmanuel and Marie MaitrePARIS Jan 3 (Reuters) - The French financial markets
watchdog AMF said on Wednesday it would decide on Jan. 9 on a
target date by which French billionaire Francois Pinault must
make a bid for Suez LYOE.PA or else abstain for six months. A bid could derail a government-orchestrated plan for an
80-billion-euro ($106.2 billion) merger between Suez, a water
and energy group, and state-controlled Gaz de France GAZ.PA.
The shot-gun marriage was arranged last February in the face of
unwelcome advances toward Suez by Italy's Enel (ENEI.MI), but
legal rulings have delayed the consummation until next July. After a meeting on Wednesday, the AMF decided that due to a
statement by the Pinault family holding company Artemis on
Tuesday that it was keeping all its options open regarding a
possible bid for Suez, Artemis had to make its intentions
clear. Unless Artemis makes a statement before next Tuesday that
it has no plans for a bid, the AMF's ruling council will
consult with all parties involved and fix "a date at which the
company Artemis, alone or in concert, needs to register a
planned public offer for the shares of Suez or issue a
statement that contains the characteristics of a public offer,"
AMF said in a statement. Artemis and Suez were not immediately available for
comment. Earlier on Wednesday, the government reiterated its backing
for a merger between Suez and Gaz de France. "The position of the state as a shareholder is as follows:
The state supports clearly and strongly the Suez-GDF merger
plan," government spokesman Jean-Francois Cope told reporters
after the weekly meeting of the French government. The Suez-GDF merger already hangs in the balance after a
recent court decision that it cannot go ahead until the full
liberalisation of European Union energy markets on July 1 --
potentially tying its fate to the outcome of April/May
presidential elections. Suez shares closed down 0.33 percent at 39.77 euros. The
stock surged nearly 6 percent in the past two sessions to hit a
lifetime high of 40.50 euros. Suez is the world's
second-largest water group and a major energy company. ALBERT FRERE SEEN KEY French media reports said Pinault plans to break up Suez if
his bid succeeds, selling its energy assets to GDF and its
environmental unit to Veolia Environnement (VIE.PA). Wendel Investissement (MWDP.PA) and concessions group Vinci
(SGEF.PA) could also be interested in buying parts of Suez,
according to the reports. But doubts remained on Pinault's ability to wrap up the
financing for a costly acquisition, which some analysts
estimated at around 60 billion euros. "If Pinault goes to see banks saying he has a commitment
from GDF to buy Suez's energy business for 40 billion euros,
and from Veolia to take the environmental unit for 10 billion,
he will have no problem raising the cash," said a sector
analyst, who asked not to be named. "But maybe nothing is agreed yet and this is why Suez is
trying to force him (Pinault) into the open," the analyst
added. Pinault may also have problems convincing some shareholders
to tender their shares, a banker close to the situation said,
pointing in particular to Albert Frere, who owns around 8
percent of Suez's capital and 12 percent of the voting rights. "Albert Frere would not say no to a hefty capital gain, but
I doubt he will feel like making a present to Pinault," the
banker said. Frere could opt to launch his own breakup bid for Suez, the
banker said, a scenario which some analysts believe is
possible, given recent delays in the completion of the Suez-GDF
merger. Officials at Groupe Bruxelles Lambert LAMBt.BR, the
financial holding company controlled by Belgium's Albert Frere,
declined to comment.
 (Additional reporting by Marcel Michelson, Yann Le Guernigou,
Elisabeth Pineau and Dominique Vidalon)












</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/suez-gdf-government-idUSL0343543720070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 3 - french watchdog wants pinault to declare suez hand</title></story></items>