<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:03 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates with New York closing copper prices, adds price
history in paras 4-5) By Pratima DesaiLONDON Jan 3 (Reuters) - Copper prices tumbled below
$6,000 a tonne on Wednesday to touch their lowest since early
April as rising stocks fuelled worries about a surplus this
year, analysts said. The losses dragged down other base metals and weighed on
London-listed miners such as Xstrata XTA.L, Vedanta (VED.L)
and Antofagasta (ANTO.L), which were down more than 5 percent. Copper for delivery in three months MCU3 on the London
Metal Exchange (LME) hit $5,822 a tonne, a level last seen on
April 7, before ending at $5,855, down 4.2 percent from
Tuesday's $6,110 close. At the New York Mercantile Exchange's COMEX division,
copper for March delivery HGH7 ended down 22.20 cents, or 7.7
percent, at $2.6490 a lb, its cheapest price since April 12. Since topping out at $4.16 a lb in early May of last year,
COMEX copper prices have erased more than 36 percent of their
value, but were still up a respectable 33 percent year over
year. LME Lead MPB3 bucked the downtrend and rose by $68, or
4.1 percent, to $1,720, near its record high of $1,785. "It is all a bit unstable at the moment ... some are
closing close to their highs so maybe we have seen the worst of
the sell-off," an LME trader said. Copper has lost more than 30 percent since hitting a record
high of $8,800 in May and more than 25 percent since early
September on growing worries about falling demand as global
economic growth slows. Forecasts of a copper surplus this year then accelerated
losses. "Clearly the increase in inventories has got people
worried. We're (forecasting) a surplus of about 250,000 tonnes
this year," Jim Lennon, analyst at Macquarie Bank, said. "People are saying it's all over as far as copper is
concerned and clearly it is. Our price forecast this year is
$2.60 a pound." That would work out to an average around $5,730 this year. DEBATE Stocks of copper at LME warehouses have risen to more than
190,000 tonnes from little more than 25,000 in July 2005. On Tuesday, copper stocks jumped 7,775 tonnes and on
Wednesday the rise was 1,975. "It's possible copper could hit $5,000 during the course of
this month, although you might see some hesitation at around
$5,500," a trader said. Expectations were, however, that copper might bounce before
resuming its downtrend, but the debate over how much further it
would fall was still raging, analysts said. Lately, fears of a sluggish U.S. housing sector have
dampened sentiment in the markets. But a better-than-expected December reading on the U.S.
manufacturing sector from the Institute for Supply Management
could be a sign of the U.S. macroeconomic trend becoming more
supportive, a Barclays Capital report said. "We do not see much evidence that weakness in the U.S.
construction sector is having significant spillover into
manufacturing activity," the report said. The bank expected a bottoming out for the residential
housing sector to emerge earlier than others believed. Some market participants said recovery would take a while
because copper had been overvalued for some time now. "It went up too high," said London-based Ian Morley, chief
executive at fund management company Dawnay Day Brokers. "The
fundamentals are good in the long term, but they are not that
good in the short term and the rises were driven by liquidity,
(commodity) index and fund management flows." Aluminium MAL3 fell 1.7 percent to $2,740 against
Tuesday's close of $2,787, whilst zinc MZN3 saw a late
recovery and was quoted at $4,149/4,150 versus $4,130 in the
previous session. Tin MSN3 hit $10,800, the lowest since December 13 and
was indicated at $10,875/10,900 at the close. On Tuesday, it
was last quoted at $11,450/11,500. (Additional reporting by Anna Stablum and Chris Kelly in
New York)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-metals-idUSL0315306720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>update 5 - copper ends below $ 6 , 000 on surplus worries</title></story></items>