<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:38 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts, adds quote, updates prices) By Nick OlivariNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - The dollar gained broadly on
Wednesday, hitting two-month highs against the yen, after a
survey showed the U.S. factory sector expanded in December,
defying forecasts of another modest contraction. The dollar jumped after the Institute for Supply Management
said its manufacturing index climbed to 51.4, above the 50
threshold that separates expansion and contraction. The
greenback erased losses spurred by an earlier report showing
the first contraction in the U.S. private sector job market
since April 2003. The dollar pared gains midafternoon after the release of
minutes from the Federal Reserve's December policy meeting,
which showed the central bank sees increased downside risks to
economic growth. However, the overall trend for the dollar
remained up on the day. "The fact that ISM came back above 50 puts the whole
soft-landing, dollar-positive scenario back in play," said
Boris Schlossberg, senior currency strategist at Forex Capital
Markets in New York. The euro EUR= was last down 0.8 percent at $1.3167.
Dollar/yen JPY= was last up 0.6 percent at 119.50 yen. Participants in the policy-making Federal Open Market
Committee meeting said the slowdown in the housing sector
continued to weigh heavily on economic activity in the United
States. Although there was evidence that home sales might be
stabilizing, residential investment was likely to fall further
in coming quarters as builders reduced inventories, officials
felt.  "I think people are taking tentative profits on their
dollar gains so far today because the minutes are very much
'permanent hold' kind of minutes and I think they reflect an
FOMC that was discussing a somewhat more downbeat economy on
Dec. 12," said Lara Rhame, senior FX strategist at Credit
Suisse in New York.
 (Additional reporting by Steven C. Johnson and Amanda Cooper)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSN0342197620070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - dollar rallies after ism beats forecasts</title></story></items>