<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:20 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>EAST RUTHERFORD, New Jersey Defensive stalwart Antonio Pierce is less than optimistic about the New York Giants' chances against the high-flying Philadelphia Eagles in the opening round of the playoffs on Sunday."They (the Eagles) have a running back (Brian Westbrook) who should be in the Pro Bowl," Pierce told reporters at Giants Stadium on Wednesday. "They've got a big offensive line, probably the biggest in the league."The way they've been playing, it doesn't seem anybody has been doing well against them the last five games. The way things look with the Eagles, it doesn't look good for us."The Eagles swept their last five games, led by Westbrook and back-up quarterback Jeff Garcia, to finish the season with a 10-6 record and claim the NFC East title.The injury-riddled Giants started the campaign 6-2 before scrambling into the playoffs with an 8-8 record."We're going in hoping we can give them a great little challenge and see how the chips fall," added middle linebacker Pierce. "We're taking on an us-against-the-world mentality."Whether the reverse psychology works in the Giants favor is likely to boil down to whether New York can slow Philadelphia's offense and handle the defensive pressure the Eagles are known for."We have a lot to prove. Obviously, we're the underdogs," said Giants head coach Tom Coughlin.The Giants won 27-21 in Philadelphia early in the season before losing to the visiting Eagles 36-22 last month.SHIN INJURYHelp might be on the way for the Giants after regular guard Rich Seubert, sidelined for three weeks with a shin injury, practiced on Wednesday.Tight end Jeremy Shockey was also hopeful his injured ankle would heal enough to allow him to practice on Thursday.Coughlin said he expected the Eagles to concentrate on stopping running back Tiki Barber, who rushed for 234 yards in last week's win over the Redskins.That could mean putting the onus on New York's struggling young quarterback Eli Manning, the player Eagles defensive end Trent Cole said this week can be rattled by the pressure brought by Philadelphia's blitz-happy defensive coordinator Jim Johnson."It's an aggressive defensive style. There's always something new and different for you," Coughlin said about the Eagles."You might play a game and have, for example, 15 or 16 pressures in that game, and 10 of them be 10 different types. There's not any one specific thing you can zoom in on."Giants center Shaun O'Hara said: "Some defenses are only good at doing certain pass-rushing blitzes. The Eagles team does a good job of running a plethora of different blitzes."A lot of teams aren't capable of doing that because their players can't adjust and can't handle the volume of blitzes so they do a good job with that, which is what makes it so tough."</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-nfl-giants-pierce-idUSN0235416320070103</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>giants defender pessimistic about grounding eagles</title></story></items>