<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:21 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (New with government reaction, previous TORONTO)OTTAWA Jan 3 (Reuters) - The Canadian military denied on
Wednesday it had singled out an Italian-built company to make
new search-and-rescue planes. Globe and Mail newspaper said on Wednesday that only one
aircraft, the Spartan C-27J, was considered a "viable bidder"
for the contract, which the newspaper pegged at C$3 billion
($2.6 billion), including 20 years of maintenance. It reported long-standing complaints by rival EADS-CASA,
the Spanish unit of Airbus parent EADS EAD.PA EAD.MC, that
the requirements laid out by the military effectively excluded
EADS-CASA's C-295s. But Canadian Air Force spokesman Lt. Col. John Blakeley
said the military and the government had not finalized
requirements for the planes, which will replace a combination
of Buffalo and Hercules planes. "The project is still progressing toward departmental and
governmental approval," he told Reuters. In theory, that means the C-295s still can compete with the
C-27J, made principally by a subsidiary of Italy's Finmeccanica
SpA (SIFI.MI). The potential Canadian project would be done
jointly with a division of L-3 Communications Holdings Inc.
(LLL.N) and with Rolls-Royce Plc (RR.L). EADS-CASA has for years complained that Canada is looking
for a plane faster than its C-295. Blakeley said he could not
comment on specific requirements but said that Canada was so
vast and cold it did need to fly to accident sites quickly if
it wanted to rescue survivors rather than dead victims. "There's no question that Canada has a unique requirement
when it comes to search and rescue," he said. Canada's previous Liberal government in 2004 earmarked
C$1.3 billion for search-and-rescue planes but no contract was
signed. Last year Canada said Boeing Co. (BA.N) was probably the
only firm able to meet its need for C$8.1 billion of purchases
-- for 16 Chinook helicopters and for four C-17 heavy cargo
planes. It gave other companies a chance to prove otherwise and
is now in contract negotiations with Boeing. It subsequently determined that Lockheed Martin Corp.'s
(LMT.N) C-130 Hercules was the only aircraft which qualified
for a C$5 billion contract for transporters. ($1=$1.17 Canadian)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/canada-planes-contract-idUSN0341600520070103</link><sectors><value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - canada denies settling on italian planemaker</title></story></items>