<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:22 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Corrects headline to show company name is CVRD not CRVD)
 (Adds comments from CVRD Inco CEO, details)TORONTO Jan 3 (Reuters) - Inco Ltd. N.TO shareholders
voted on Wednesday to seal the takeover by Brazil's Companhia
Vale do Rio Doce (VALE5.SA) (RIO.N), the final step in taking a
mining sector icon out of Canadian hands. CVRD, the biggest iron ore producer in the world, took
control of Inco in October and up until this morning held 87.8
percent of Inco's outstanding shares. Inco had called a meeting for shareholders to consider a
transaction by way of amalgamation, a legal procedure so that
CVRD could take up 100 percent of the nickel producer. The motion to amalgamate passed unceremoniously at a
special meeting in Toronto with about three dozen shareholders
present. Inco shares will stop trading on the TSX within the next
few days. Its stock stopped trading on the New York Stock
Exchange in November. Remaining shareholders will receive C$86 for every share
held. The total value of the deal is worth C$19.35 billion. Shares of Inco were up 6 Canadian cents at C$85.96 on
Wednesday on the TSX on volume of about 80,000 shares by early
afternoon. At the meeting, where Inco's name was displayed by itself
for the last time, one shareholder asked former Inco CEO and
current CVRD-Inco's chief executive, Scott Hand, to translate
Companhia Vale do Rio Doce to English from Portuguese. It
means: Company of the valley of the sweet river. Another investor spoke about how three generations of
family members owned Inco stock. INCO NAME LIVES ON For Hand, who failed to create a made-in-Canada mining
powerhouse by merging Inco with former compatriot Falconbridge,
at least the 'Inco' name will live on. "The new company is called CVRD Inco Limited, so the Inco
name continues as a great name and I think that was one of the
smart things that CVRD decided in acquiring Inco --  to keep
the Inco name," Hand told a reporter after the meeting. "We consider marketing to be very important and so does
CVRD and I think that lots of places around the world...Inco
nickel is seen as something that is pretty good." Inco was known as the world's No. 2 nickel producer and
CVRD is set to become the largest producer of the metal when
new nickel projects come on stream over the next few years. Hand lost Falconbridge to a sweeter offer from Swiss-based
Xstrata Plc XTA.L in July 2006. After shopping around for
other buyers, Inco agreed to be taken over by CVRD in
September. CVRD chief executive Roger Agnelli appointed Hand as the
head of CVRD Inco, in charge of all nickel operations. Since
then, the two companies have been integrating assets and Hand
said it is "going well." "I think everything will be completed probably by the end
of this month or early in February. Everything is on schedule,"
he said. Hand will be with the company until integration is
complete. After that, Hand and Agnelli will discuss Hand's next
role. Meanwhile, CVRD and Xstrata have started general talks
about combining operations in the Sudbury, Ontario basin, where
CVRD Inco and Xstrata Nickel (formerly Falconbridge) have major
nickel operations. "You can assume during the new year that (discussions) will
proceed," said Hand. When Inco and Falconbridge were trying to merge, the two
companies touted millions of dollars in synergies from
combining their operations in Sudbury. "Today it's two separate companies talking instead of one.
It takes discussions, it takes time, it takes work. It takes
willingness on both parties." ($1=$1.17 Canadian)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/inco-cvrd-idUSN0340385520070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A</value></value></sectors><title>corrected - update 2 - shareholders seal cvrd ' s takeover of inco</title></story></items>