<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:00 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds details) By Deborah HaynesLONDON Jan 3 (Reuters) - German Chancellor Angela Merkel
said in comments published on Wednesday the European Union and
the United States should more closely harmonise their financial
market regulations, patent laws and other economic mechanisms. In an interview with the Financial Times before a trip to
Washington this week, Merkel outlined her goals for Germany's
six-month rotating presidency of the European Union and its
year-long presidency of the Group of Eight nations. Merkel said closer harmony between the 27-nation EU bloc and
the United States would boost investment flows and trade. "We have accumulated a certain expertise about single
markets in Europe, which we can apply on the transatlantic
level," she told the newspaper, according to an edited
transcript of the interview published on the FT's Web site. "With increasing globalisation, this can be a good basis for
transatlantic cooperation." Merkel said she would touch on this topic during talks with
U.S. President George W. Bush in Washington this week. "The EU and the U.S. have sophisticated patent legislation.
We have regulatory mechanisms governing our financial markets.
We should be looking for ways to keep developing these together
at a transatlantic level," she said. "We must watch out that we do not drift apart, but instead
come closer together, where there are clear advantages for both
sides." Germany's relationship with the United States cooled under
previous Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder but has improved since
Merkel took over in 2005.
 "QUITE SENSELESS" Merkel dismissed concerns that countries such as China and
Japan would regard a closer partnership between the United
States and Europe as hostile. "Building bulkheads against Asia would be quite senseless,
and certainly not in our interest," she said. "But no one can stop us from combining our efforts. Of
course, if this works, it will make us stronger competitors. But
this is certainly not about restricting trade in any way." Merkel said the development of the hedge fund sector would
be discussed during Germany's presidency of the G8. "The result does not have to be new legislation. It can be
self-regulation or improved supervision," she said. In the wide-ranging interview, Merkel said she was hopeful a
problem over a ban by Moscow of Polish meat imports would be
solved, enabling talks between the EU and Russia on a new
cooperation pact to begin. "I am very optimistic that we will solve the problem of
Polish meat exports to Russia. Then we can start the
negotiations, although I am not saying they will be very easy." Merkel said Russia had the right to seek greater access to
Western European markets but that European investors should be
equally able to enter Russian markets. "If obstacles are being erected to protect Russian companies
from European investors, nobody should resent it if the
Europeans take reciprocal action," she said. Merkel said no one should expect Germany's presidency to
solve the problems in the EU over adopting a constitution but
she aimed to develop a form of road map to move the process
forward.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/eu-us-merkel-idUSL0353271220070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 3 - merkel seeks closer eu - us ties on economic issues</title></story></items>