<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:08 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds comments, details throughout, byline) By Jonathan StempelNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - A former Morgan Stanley (MS.N)
regional director in wealth management sued the Wall Street
investment bank on Wednesday, saying he was fired because of
his age. Edward Sullivan, 56, who had been a managing director,
accused human resources executives Jeffrey Brodsky and Eric
Kayne of conspiring to end his employment, in part to make room
for a friend of Brodsky's who lacked an assignment. Sullivan said the executives interfered with his 2005
annual review, even preparing a "made-up, poison-pen critique"
of his work to advance their cause. The Darien, Connecticut, resident said their actions helped
lead to his May 13, 2006 dismissal, 10 days before his 56th
birthday. Brodsky "marked the aging Mr. Sullivan for termination,"
and enlisted Kayne's help, according to the complaint. "He
(Brodsky) wanted Sullivan terminated even though there was no
reason to terminate him, and he wanted it done now, before
Sullivan got any older." Jim Wiggins, a Morgan Stanley spokesman, said: "The lawsuit
has absolutely no merit, and we will contest it vigorously." He
said Brodsky and Kayne still work for Morgan Stanley and were
not available for comment. "Morgan Stanley holds itself out as subscribing to a
culture of excellence and management transparency. Our client
alleges that those promises were not honored," said John
Crossman, a partner at Zukerman Gore &amp; Brandeis LLP who
represents Sullivan. "He was a 25-year veteran, well-respected,
frequently commended, and all of that has been taken away." Sullivan sued Morgan Stanley and the executives in the U.S.
District Court for the Southern District of New York. He is
asking for his job back with seniority and benefits, and at
least $30 million of compensatory and punitive damages. The plaintiff was one of six regional directors who lost
that title last March when James Gorman, who runs Morgan
Stanley's global wealth management unit, streamlined the
business's management structure. Gorman halved the number of regional directors to four. He
kept two of the existing directors and hired two others from
Merrill Lynch &amp; Co. MER.N, his former employer. Sullivan had worked for Morgan Stanley or its predecessors
since 1981, according to the complaint. He rose to managing
director in 1999 and was paid between $800,000 and $1 million
annually from 2001 to 2005, the complaint said. Wall Street investment banks regularly face bias lawsuits.
In 2004, Morgan Stanley agreed to pay $54 million to settle
bias charges filed on behalf of hundreds of women who claimed
they were denied raises and promotions and subjected to lewd
behavior.







</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/morganstanley-discrimination-idUSN0341619320070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - morgan stanley sued by former exec for age bias</title></story></items>