<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:59 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>CHICAGO Catalyst Pharmaceutical Partners Inc. (CPRX.O) said on Wednesday that a study of its experimental cocaine addiction drug in Mexico is delayed and it is changing the design of another set of studies, pushing its stock down about 8 percent.The study of cocaine-dependent prisoners in Mexico will be delayed because the recently elected government in Mexico has requested more information on the trial, Catalyst said. Conservative Felipe Calderon became president of Mexico in December.Catalyst, which went public in November, said it is helping fund that study, but it is not part of its submission for U.S. regulators. It called the delay the red tape of a new administration.The company also announced the redesign of another set of studies which it plans to submit for U.S. regulatory review. Catalyst will now study between 100 and 150 patients for cocaine addiction, down from 375 patients, and it will add a second trial of methamphetamine addicts.The two new studies could speed it toward its final study required for U.S. approval, it said."Investors just don't like change more than anything," Catalyst Chief Executive Officer Patrick McEnany said in an interview, of the stock decline. "This is a deviation of course from our prospectus."He said he expects the U.S. Food and Drug Administration to approve the new study design.The company is studying the chemical used in a drug already approved outside the United States for epilepsy called vigabatrin.It expects to have results on the cocaine addiction trial in the second quarter of fiscal 2008 and results for methamphetamine addiction shortly after that.The U.S. Food and Drug Administration has granted the drug "fast track" status, giving it a faster-than-typical review time by regulators.Shares were down 38 cents or 7.9 percent to $4.45 on Nasdaq in later afternoon dealings.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-catalyst-cocaine-idUSN0339467020070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets, </value><value>Regulatory News, </value><value>IPOs</value></value></sectors><title>catalyst pharma trial delayed , stock off</title></story></items>