<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:35 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts lead, adds background in paragraph 10) By Rachel SandersonLONDON Jan 3 (Reuters) - Online retailers look set to be
crowned among the victors of Britain's Christmas trading war
this year alongside an uneven showing on the high street. Internet sales in Britain for the first time peaked during
the start of seasonal discounting last week after surging more
than 50 percent in the run up to Christmas, online retail
tracker IMRG reported. It was the opposite story for Britain's high street with
the number of Britons visiting stores down 6.8 percent in the
week after Christmas, according to data from FootFall on
Wednesday. "This has definitely been an online Christmas," James
Roper, chief executive of the Interactive Media in Retail Group
(IMRG) said. "We think 25 million people now shop on the
Internet." Roper said early evidence showed online Christmas sales are
looking to be around half a billion pounds better than already
strong industry forecasts, and will top 7.5 billion pounds ($15
billion) in the 10 weeks leading up to the holiday. More surprisingly, Roper said data from IMRG and eDigital
Research showed that unlike in previous years, there was no
sign of a post-Christmas fall in online demand. Instead, visits to the online stores of leading British
retailers on Dec. 27 -- the start of the holiday discounting
season -- spiked 30 percent higher than any previous peak. "The young Internet shopping industry is already a huge
success, with potential to continue to grow at 40 percent per
annum for the foreseeable future," Roper said. INTERNET ADVANTAGE Early reports suggest British retailers made an uneven
showing during crucial Christmas trading while many consumers
struggled with soaring household bills, higher borrowing costs
and tame wage growth. Premium grocers, luxury goods stores as well as Britain's
biggest retailer Tesco (TSCO.L) are expected to have performed
strongly while middle market store owners have struggled. However, there are indications a strong Internet strategy
will have helped to separate winners from the losers. Tesco, the world's fifth largest retailer, which forecast a
"good Christmas," saw visitors to Tesco.com swell to 1.3
million over the holiday period. PC World and Curry's are
expected to benefit from parent company DSG International's
DSGI.L early push into online selling. Analysts predict the Christmas fortunes of clothing
retailer Next (NXT.L), which reports on Thursday, rest on the
success of its home and online shopping Directory business. "Part of the reason why high street retailers are having a
tough time is due to the inexorable rise of home shopping via
the Internet," Investec Securities analyst Mark Charnock wrote
in a note last month. Among those hardest hit are some middle market retailers
and sellers of music and movies who are suffering from a boom
in downloads from the likes of Apple's iTunes. Woolworths WLW.L and HMV HMV.L issued profit warnings
before Christmas while Music Zone, a privately-owned DVD and CD
store, filed for administration on Wednesday. Data from Internet tracker Hitwise showed visits to music
download sites rose 50 percent from Christmas Day 2005.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/britain-christmas-internet-idUSN0342758920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - online retailers winners in uk christmas trading</title></story></items>