<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:48 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Updates with Woodside's Legendre shut) By Fayen WongSYDNEY Jan 3 (Reuters) - Cyclone Isobel, Australia's first
tropical cyclone of the season, shut in at least 162,000
barrels per day (bpd) of offshore oil production on Wednesday,
but operators said the disruption would be short-lived. Woodside Petroleum Ltd. (WPL.AX) and Santos Ltd. (STO.AX)
said they planned to resume operations shortly after the
cyclone passed the coast. Meteorologists said Isobel made
landfall about mid-afternoon local time. Woodside, Australia's top independent oil and gas company,
suspended production from its 100,000-bpd Cossack Pioneer field
and 7,000-bpd Legendre field off the coast of Western Australia
on Tuesday evening,. Rival oil and gas producer Santos said it had shut
production at its Mutineer-Exeter field. "We are expecting to resume production by this afternoon
and we should be back to full production tomorrow," Peter
Kermode, spokesman for Woodside, told Reuters. Operations at Legendre field, in which Apache Corp. (APA.N)
and Santos also have stakes, was expected to resume later in
the week, Woodside said. Production capacity at the Mutineer-Exeter field was
recorded at 55,000 bdp at the end of the third quarter last
year. Tropical Cyclone Isobel was rated as a category one storm,
the lowest in a five-point scale, and has winds of up to 100
kmh (62 mph) near its centre. Woodside's shares ended down 1.6 percent at A$37.68, while
Santos' shares closed 1 percent lower at A$9.79 in an overall
market down 0.4 percent. Woodside's Kermode said production at two other offshore
gas platforms, North Rankin and Goodwyn, had not been affected
by the cyclone. Cyclone Isobel revived memories of Cyclone Glenda, a
destructive category four storm, which forced oil and gas
fields to shut down and thousands of people to take shelter
when it hit the region last March. Australia's Bureau of Meteorology (www.bom.gov.au) said
Cyclone Isobel was expected to weaken below tropical cyclone
strength after it crossed the coast. But it warned that remnants of Cyclone Isobel were expected
to produce "widespread damaging and locally destructive winds
and very heavy rainfall" in southern districts of Western
Australia. The six equal partners in the North West Shelf joint
venture, which operates Cossack, are Woodside Petroleum Ltd.
(WPL.AX), BHP Billiton Plc./Ltd. (BHP.AX)(BLT.L), Chevron Corp.
(CVX.N), BP Plc. (BP.L), Japan Australia LNG (MiMi) Pty. Ltd.
and Woodside's 34 percent shareholder, Royal/Dutch Shell Group
(RDSa.L) (RDSb.L). Nippon Oil Corp. 5001.T, Kuwait Foreign Petroleum
Exploration Co. and Woodside are partners with Santos in the
Mutineer-Exeter field.
 ($1=1.26 Australian Dollar)

</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/woodside-shutin-idUSSYD24748520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 4 - cyclone cuts 162 , 000bpd of australian offshore oil</title></story></items>