<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:26 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds Kremlin reaction, background) By Andrei MakhovskyMINSK Jan 3 (Reuters) - Belarus slapped big new charges on
Russian oil crossing its territory on Wednesday, causing
headaches for refiners in northern Europe and further
unravelling Belarus' once cordial ties with the Kremlin. Belarus President Alexander Lukashenko -- described by
Washington as Europe's last dictator -- imposed transit duty of
$45 per tonne on Russian oil in retaliation for Moscow cutting
subsidies on energy supplies to Belarus. One million barrels of oil a day, or about a fifth of
Russian exports, pass through Belarus. Most of that crude goes
to refiners in Poland and Germany. Market watchers said the transit duty would not affect world
oil prices or cause shortages but it was likely to cause
short-term disruption to the supply chain as refiners in Poland
and Germany look for cheaper alternative supplies of crude. "I do not exclude the Belarussians could do something weird,
which may paralyse Russian oil exports to Europe," one trader
with a Russian oil major told Reuters. "The volumes in question -- to Poland and Germany -- are
huge. I am coming to work tomorrow despite the holidays." Russia has been Lukashenko's closest ally after the
tough-talking former collective farm boss was cold-shouldered by
the West over his human rights record.  But the Belarus leader angrily denounced Moscow for
"extremely unfriendly steps" toward its neighbour and said the
transit tariffs were his response. "If Russia, choking on this influx of petrodollars ..., is
still willing to make a scapegoat of Belarus ... then let's ask
the Russian Federation -- so huge and so rich -- to pay us in
full for our services," state news agency BelTA quoted
Lukashenko as saying.
 TIT-FOR-TAT Lukashenko has been angered by Moscow imposing full duties
on exports of Russian crude to Belarus. This oil is treated
separately from transit crude. Until now, this fuel has been shipped duty free to
refineries in Belarus and then re-exported as refined products
to other countries in a lucrative tax loophole. Further angering the Belarus leader, his government was
forced on Jan. 1 to agree to pay twice the previous level for
natural gas it imports from Russia. Officials in Moscow said they wanted clarification from the
Belarus government about the new charge on oil transit. "Questions arise as to the substance of the measures, which
was not explained by the Belarussian side," Kremlin deputy
spokesman Dmitry Peskov said. "There are also some questions about how it could be imposed
on Jan 3, effective from Jan. 1. We need additional details to
analyse this decision." Sergei Grigoriyev, Vice-President of Russia's oil pipeline
monopoly Transneft, told Reuters he did not understand how
Belarus could impose the duty on Russian oil.  He said though if there was to be a charge it should be
negotiated by the two countries' economy ministers. The transit duty was announced to reporters by Lukashenko's
Prime Minister Sergei Sidorsky. Up to now Belarus has charged a
shipping fee on Russian oil pumped across its territory but no
transit duty. Moscow says its ex-Soviet neighbours -- even those closely
allied to it like Belarus -- should be weaned off subsidies and
start paying market prices for energy. Some in Minsk though see that policy as a betrayal of the
special relationship between Moscow and Belarus. The two
countries are talking about merging into a single state, as they
were for centuries before the Soviet Union broke up. Just days ago, a different row between Minsk and Moscow over
energy briefly threatened to disrupt supplies of natural gas
from Russian to Europe. Belarus threatened to disable a gas pipeline across its
territory if a deal was not reached with Gazprom on new prices.
Minsk backed down at the last minute.
 (Additional reporting by Dmitry Zhdannikov in Moscow)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/belarus-russia-idUSL0371417220070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 3 - belarus slaps duty on russian oil exports</title></story></items>