<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:25 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 Gold futures erased early gains
to end the first trading day of the year down more than 1
percent in heavy trading, hurt by a surging dollar and sharply
lower energy prices. Benchmark gold for February delivery GCG7 on the COMEX
metals trading division of the New York Mercantile Exchange
settled down $8.20, or 1.3 percent, at $629.80 an ounce on
Wednesday. Estimated COMEX volume was 44,000 contracts, and options
turnover was 10,000. Turnover in the Chicago Board of Trade's
electronically traded 100-oz gold contract was just 69,987
contracts as of 2:51 p.m. EST (1951 GMT).
(www.cbot.com/cbot/pub/page/0,3181,297,00.html). Gold initially gained on fund buying, traded as high as
$647.30 an ounce, near its four-week high of $648.80. But the February contract turned south by late morning,
hitting a low of $627.00, as the dollar reversed course and
gained broadly after a survey showed the U.S. factory sector
expanded in December. Scott Meyers, senior analyst at Pioneer Futures, attributed
gold's decline to a sharply higher currency and plunging energy
prices. "After the initial rally, there's just no follow-through
early on. I think that the gold just ran out of steam early,"
Meyers said. "Everybody thought that we would have a rally. The rally
fell apart. The next thing you know this market just gave back
virtually everything," said Meyers. The dollar jumped after the Institute for Supply Management
(ISM) said its manufacturing index climbed to 51.4, above the 50
threshold that separates expansion and contraction. Stephen Platt, analyst at Archer Financial, called the
dollar's surprising strength a big factor to gold's pullout. "The energy complex is starting to break through some key
areas, also lending itself to rather negative bias to the
precious metals as well," Platt said. Oil prices dropped a whopping 4 percent to below $59 a
barrel as mild weather in the U.S. Northeast cut fuel demand in
the world's biggest heating oil market. Gold is generally seen
as a hedge against energy-led inflation. Spot gold XAU= was quoted at $627.70/8.70, down from
$640.20/1.20 in late trade on Tuesday. London's afternoon gold
fix was $642.60. In other metals, COMEX copper futures HGH7 tumbled almost
8 percent to a near nine-month low after a hefty influx of
visible London warehouse supplies fueled speculation of a supply
glut hitting the market this year. [ID:nN03518754] Lower copper prices often pull the precious metals markets
down as well. COMEX March silver SIH7 ended down 26.5 cents, or 2.1
percent, at $12.670 an ounce, trading between $12.600 and
$13.280. Spot silver XAG= was down at $12.580/2.650, against
$13.080/3.140 late on Tuesday. Silver was fixed in London at
$12.910 an ounce. NYMEX January platinum PLF7 finished down $6.90 at
$1,132.40 an ounce. Spot platinum XPT= fetched
$1,126.00/1,132.00. NYMEX March palladium PAH7 closed up $3.55, or 1.1
percent, at $342.05 an ounce. Spot palladium XPD= was quoted
at $334/339.00.






















</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-precious-comex-idUSN0342075420070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>us gold erases early gains to end lower , dollar up</title></story></items>