<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:52 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> By Dhara Ranasinghe SINGAPORE, Jan 3 The euro held firm against
other major currencies on Wednesday, while sterling and the
Australian dollar extended gains on the back of strong appetite
for high-yielding plays. The euro EUR= stood at about $1.3286 in Asian trade after
rising 0.6 percent on Tuesday, breaking resistance at $1.3245,
and rose to 1.6141 Swiss francs EURCHF= -- the strongest
level in almost seven years. It was at 157.77 yen EURJPY=, holding close to Tuesday's
record peak at about 157.90. Traders said speculative buyers
were looking to break option barriers above 158.00. Carry trades, in which investors sell low-yielding
currencies for high yielders, were expected to dominate trade
as the new year got under way. "Carry trades are definitely the focus in the market --
liquidity conditions are still very ample and there is no
reason why the carry trade is going to fall out of favour yet,"
said Sharada Selvanathan, a currency strategist at BNP Paribas. "That explains why the European currencies are holding up
quite well and also why the more high-yielding currencies like
the Aussie and Kiwi are also doing quite well." The European Central Bank is expected to raise borrowing
costs to 3.75 percent in coming months from the current 3.5. By
contrast, the next move on U.S. interest rates is likely to be
a cut from 5.25 percent after a steady policy in recent months. Japanese rates are seen rising at a very gradual pace from
0.25 percent -- maintaining the euro's yield advantage. The yen remains the funding vehicle of choice for the carry
trade, ahead of the Swiss franc, said Peter Pontikis, a
treasury strategist at Suncorp. "There's no political or bureaucratic consensus for a rate
hike in Japan right now, so it seems safe to borrow in yen," he
said. Funds borrowed in yen tend to end up in higher-yielding
currencies such as sterling and the Australian and New Zealand
dollars. The Australian dollar firmed to $0.7983 AUD=, its
strongest level since March 2005. A move above $0.7989 would
take the Aussie dollar to its highest since Feb. 2004. It rose
to 94.77 yen AUDJPY=, its highest in more than nine years. Sterling hit a one-month high of $1.9751 GBP=, with talk
of another rise in British interest rates to 5.25 percent early
this year helping it outperform in recent months. The pound set
an eight-year peak at around 234.58 yen GBPJPY= on Tuesday.
"The search for yield is what everybody seems to be focusing on
at the moment and I guess it will be the focus for the next few
months," said a trader in Singapore. U.S. DATA IN FOCUS The U.S. dollar was relatively quiet at 118.78 yen JPY=,
a tad softer from 118.85 late in New York, with a holiday in
Tokyo keeping liquidity thin. Minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's December meeting to
be released later on Wednesday could help refine the outlook
for interest rates. Fed officials have been talking tough on inflation even as
the market wagered on rate cuts and dollar bears will be
looking for any hint of a softer tone. The Institute for Supply Management's reading on the U.S.
manufacturing sector is also due on Wednesday, while Friday
brings the nonfarm payrolls report for December. A reading below 50 in the ISM index, which dipped below the
boom-or-bust level for the first time in three-and-a-half years
in November, would reinforce concerns about an economic
slowdown. "Today's focus will be the ISM's manufacturing report and
any weakness there will keep the dollar on the back foot," said
Selvanathan at BNP Paribas. Elsewhere, Bank of Japan Deputy Governor Toshiro Muto told
the Nikkei newspaper in an interview published on Wednesday
that a hawkish monetary policy by the central bank would be
consistent with Prime Minister Shinzo Abe's emphasis on
pro-growth policies. The comments had little immediate impact on the market.Currency bid prices at 0641 GMT.  All data taken from
Reuters with percent change calculated from the daily U.S.
close at 2130GMT.                  Last     US Close  %Chg   YTD %  2006 Cls                           .
-------------------------------------------------------------
Euro/dlr   EUR=    1.3281   1.3274   +0.05   +0.64   1.3196
Dlr/yen    JPY=    118.79   118.85   -0.05   -0.18   119.01
Euro/yen   EURJPY= 157.78   157.79   -0.01   +0.42   157.12
Dlr/swiss  CHF=    1.2147   1.2130   +0.14   -0.30   1.2184
Stg/dlr    GBP=    1.9732   1.9730   +0.01   +0.74   1.9588
Dlr/can    CAD=    1.1650   1.1654   -0.03   +0.00   1.1650
Aus/dlr    AUD=    0.7970   0.7958   +0.15   +1.01   0.7890
Euro/swiss EURCHF= 1.6136   1.6107   +0.18   +0.32   1.6085
Euro/stg   EURGBP= 0.6731   0.6726   +0.07   -0.10   0.6738
 (Additional reporting by Wayne Cole in Sydney)






</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSSP15148320070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - euro holds firm as yield plays dominate</title></story></items>