<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:21 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds Cowen, Aon, others)  PHILADELPHIA/LONDON Jan 3 (Reuters) - The following
financial services industry appointments and moves were
announced on Wednesday. To inform us of other job changes
please e-mail: moves@reuters.com. COWEN GROUP INC. (COWN.O) Cowen said it created Cowen Healthcare Royalty Partners
(CHRP) as it expands its alternative asset management business.
The firm hired three executives from Paul Capital Partners with
experience in life-sciences investing. Todd Davis and Clarke
Futch have recently joined Cowen and Gregory Brown will join
the firm in October, 2007. CHRP will raise interim capital, and
will launch a more formal fund-raising effort after Brown
joins. AON CONSULTING Aon Consulting, a unit of Aon Corp. AOC.N, said it
created a threat management and security services unit, which
will be part of the corporate investigative services group.
Gregory Boles has joined as a director and leader of the threat
management arm of the new unit. Boles most recently led the
global threat management practice at Kroll, the company said. ASSURED GUARANTY (UK) LTD. Assured Guaranty Ltd. (AGO.N) said its London subsidiary,
Assured Guaranty (UK) Ltd., named Craig Lee as managing
director, Asia Pacific. He will be responsible for developing
business in the Asia Pacific and Australian regions. Prior to
joining the firm, Lee worked at Sumitomo Mitsui Banking Corp.
in Sydney. EVERGREEN INVESTMENTS Evergreen Investments, the brand name of Wachovia Corp.'s
investment management business, said its institutional division
hired two sales directors. Kirsten Burton joined as vice president and director of
Midwest regional sales. She previously served as vice president
of institutional sales and client service at Advantus Capital
Management. Meanwhile, Sean Kelly joined as vice president and director
of sub-advisory sales. Kelly previously worked at Wellington
Management, Evergreen said. QUADRISERV INC. Quadriserv said it named Rick Geisman to the newly created
position of head of sales, overseeing sales and business
development for hedge fund and institutional managers. He
previously served as head of sales trading for CIBC World
Markets. WARBURG PINCUS The private equity firm said David Krieger and Justin
Sadrian, both based in New York, have been promoted to managing
director. Both executives have been with the firm since 2000.
Krieger works in the energy group, while Sadrian works in the
technology, media and telecommunications group. ERNST &amp; YOUNG [ERNY.UL] The accounting and consulting firm has appointed David
Baker, Jon Blackie and Louise Hogan as directors in its London
valuation and business modeling team. Baker, who joins from rival accounting firm Deloitte, will
continue to specialize in the energy sector. Blackie joins from
financial advisory firm Duff &amp; Phelps to specialize in complex
transactional modeling. Hogan is moving over from Australia to
support the valuation team in the context of IFRS accounting. FIDELITY AMERICAN FUND Fidelity International, Britain's largest mutual fund
manager, has appointed Aris Vatis as manager of Fidelity
Investment Funds American Fund from Feb. 1, 2007. He takes over from Jason Weiner, who managed the fund for
the past three years. Weiner is to concentrate on his new
portfolio management responsibilities at Fidelity Management
and Research Corp (FMR), the U.S. affiliate. Vatis joined Fidelity in June 2006 after a long career with
Pictet Asset Management. He is a member of the recently
expanded global equity team based in London, which was set up
three years ago.  Since then, the team has grown to nine
members who now manage more than $6.7 billion of assets in
global and U.S. equity portfolios. PAUL, HASTINGS, JANOFSKY &amp; WALKER LLP The international law firm has hired Scott Joachim who will
join the corporate department, based in the firm's Palo Alto,
California, office. Prior to joining Paul Hastings, Joachim was a partner in
the business and finance department at law firm Drinker Biddle
&amp; Reath and head of the firm's West Coast-based corporate
practice. In his new post, Joachim will focus on mergers and
acquisitions, private equity and capital markets transactions.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/financial-moves-idUSL0386527320070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Bonds, </value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - moves - cowen , aon , evergreen , warburg pincus</title></story></items>