<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:22 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 Emerging government debt
spreads tightened on Wednesday on the back of firm U.S.
Treasury prices after minutes from the last Federal Reserve
meeting cited increased downside risk to economic growth. Overall spreads tightened 4 basis points to 167 points
above safe-haven U.S. Treasuries, according to JP Morgan's
Emerging Markets Bond Index Plus (EMBI+)11EMJ.JPMEMBIPLUS.
Total returns rose 0.53 percent. Yields of the 10-year Treasury note US10YT=RR eased to
4.67 percent compared with 4.68 percent. Bond yields and prices
move inversely. The concern over potentially slower growth helped to
marginally boost investor expectations that the Fed may be
considering the possibility of an official interest rate cut
later this year. Lower U.S. rates free up money for investors to put into
high-risk emerging market bonds. Emerging market investors are experiencing a dream scenario
that includes a moderate slowdown of the U.S. economy that
would not hurt demand for exports from developing economies but
would allow U.S. rates to remain stable. Meanwhile, Ecuador's sovereign bond spreads tightened 50
basis points to 872 bps on the EMBI+ after the country's
Economy Minister designate Ricardo Patino said he was
considering forcing bondholders to accept a buyback of the
global bonds due in 2012 ECUGLB12=RR by threatening not to
pay interest. Patino said a buyback managed through a Dutch action "is an
alternative." For details see [ID:nN03406083]. A Dutch auction
starts with an asking price that moves downward until it is
accepted by a bidder. "The Dutch auction comments are positive. It is very
difficult to say exactly what it means, because they could
offer half the price or a 5 to 10 basis (points) haircut, but
the market has interpreted it as they won't default," said
Marjorie Hernandez, emerging markets analyst at HSBC. Ecuador's global bond due in 2012 was 1.688 percentage
points higher to bid 80.188 in price and to yield 19.269
percent. "The incoming administration does not, at this stage, know
with precision which strategy it intends to follow or even what
level of debt service relief it is seeking," said Alberto
Ramos, senior economist at Goldman Sachs. President-elect Rafael Correa will take office on Jan. 15
after causing jitters on Wall Street for months with threats to
interrupt bond payments as he seeks to lower the country's debt
burden. "What seems clear at this stage is that the tight cash-flow
fiscal picture the incoming government is about to inherit --
payment arrears of about $900 million -- could turn into a
decisive variable to the definition of nature and timing of
debt strategy," Ramos added. The government has already made abundantly clear that
servicing external debt is possibly at the bottom of its
spending priorities, Ramos said. Argentine bond spreads kept tightening further on Wednesday
by 13 basis points to 206 bps on the EMBI+, gaining 2.88
percent on the day amid a continuation of solid macroeconomic
policies and strong returns. Argentina's portion on the EMBI+ returned more than 50
percent of the original investment in 2006, by far the biggest
winner on JP Morgan's benchmark.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-emergingdebt-idUSN0357137820070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>emerging debt - spreads tighten following us bonds</title></story></items>