<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:52 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 3 European shares are seen opening
mixed on Wednesday, with investors awaiting key manufacturing
data from across the Atlantic as the euro holds firm. U.S. markets were shut on Tuesday to mourn former president
Gerald Ford and Japanese markets were shut on Wednesday as part
of the New Year holiday, meaning that there are few other cues
available from other regions.
The U.S. ISM manufacturing index, delayed from Tuesday, is
the main economic data due, while investors are also keeping an
eye on minutes from the Federal Reserve's last monetary policy
meeting due for release later in the day. The data will give indications about how the U.S. economy is
doing and how hawkish monetary policy is likely to be. Here's how the day looks: * Spread betters in London are calling the FTSE 100 .FTSE
2-14 points lower, the CAC 40 .FCHI between 1 point higher and
10 points lower and DAX .GDAXI between 4 points higher and 10
points lower. * The FTSEurofirst 300 .FTEU3 index of leading European
shares closed up 1.24 percent at 1,501.83 points on Tuesday.
Double click on [.EU] to read the closing European market
report. * U.S. stock markets were shut on Tuesday to mourn former
president Gerald Ford. * U.S. government bond prices rose slightly on Tuesday on
light volumes. Benchmark U.S. 10-year yields were trading at
around 4.69 percent. Comparable 10-year euro zone government bonds yielded 3.93
percent. Double click on [US/] for the latest Treasury market
report and [EUR/GVD] for the latest euro zone debt report. * Oil prices held below $61 a barrel as mild weather was 
projected to persist in the United States, slowing down heating
oil demand. U.S. light crude CLc1 traded at $60.91 a barrel by
0605 GMT. Double click on [O/R] to read the latest oil market
report. * The euro held firm against the U.S. dollar and the yen.
The euro hit 157.7 yen EURJPY=, while the dollar was trading
at $1.3279 per euro EUR= and was buying 118.73 yen JPY=.
Double click on [USD/] to read the latest forex market report. * Markets were closed in Japan for New Year's holidays,
while other Asian indexes were mixed. Both the Hang Seng .HSI
(up 0.2 pct) and Straits Times .STI (up 1.24 percent) hit
record highs but Korea's Kospi .KS11 fell 1.8 percent after
the country forecast a slowdown in 2007 export growth. Double click on [MARKETS/AS] to read a wrap of the action in
Asian asset markets. * Gold was at $639.70 an ounce, having earlier having gone
up as much as $640.40. The precious metal had jumped to its
highest in nearly a month at $640.80 on a weaker dollar on
Tuesday. Double click on [GOL/] to read the latest gold market
report.
 COMPANIES SUEZ LYOE.PA French stock market regulator AMF will rule within days on a
standoff between utility Suez LYOE.PA and billionaire
entrepreneur Francois Pinault over whether he should be forced
to declare his takeover intentions. For more double click on [LYOE.PA-E]
 UBS UBSN.VX Massachusetts has subpoenaed UBS over whether its Boston
"hedge fund hotel" charges fees that may create conflicts of
interest and harm investors, a spokesman said on Tuesday. UBS
and other banks lease space to start-up hedge funds and provide
other support, hoping that in time these funds will grow into
bigger, lucrative customers. For more, double click on [UBSN.VX-E]
 THALES (TCFP.PA) Dassault is to quit a shareholder pact in Thales when the
company completes its satellites merger with Alcatel Lucent, but
keep most of its shares for now, the French regulator AMF says. For more, double click on [TCFP.PA-E]


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-europe-factors-idUSL0293337520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>european stocks -- factors to watch on jan 3</title></story></items>