<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:12 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds ExxonMobil comment, paragraphs 3, 17-19) By Deborah Zabarenko, Environment CorrespondentWASHINGTON Jan 3 (Reuters) - Energy giant ExxonMobil
borrowed tactics from the tobacco industry to raise doubt about
climate change, spending $16 million on groups that question
global warming, a science watchdog group said on Wednesday. "ExxonMobil (XOM.N) has manufactured uncertainty about the
human causes of global warming just as tobacco companies denied
their product caused lung cancer," Alden Meyer of the Union of
Concerned Scientists said at a telephone news conference
releasing the report. An ExxonMobil spokesman dismissed the report as "an attempt
to connect unrelated facts, draw inaccurate conclusions and
mislead the audience with a fiction about ExxonMobil's true
positions." The union, a nonprofit group based in Cambridge,
Massachusetts, said ExxonMobil, the world's biggest publicly
traded corporation, had succeeded in parlaying a relatively
modest investment into unwarranted public doubt on findings
that have been overwhelmingly endorsed by mainstream science. ExxonMobil did this by using the same methods used for
decades by the U.S. tobacco industry, the report said,
including: -- raising doubts about even the most undisputed science; -- funding a variety of front organizations to create the
appearance of a broad platform; -- recruiting a number of vocal climate change
contrarians; -- portraying its opposition to action as a quest for
"sound science" rather than business self-interest; -- using its access to the Bush administration to shape
federal communications and policies on global warming. TOBACCO TACTICS U.S. tobacco companies used these tactics for decades to
hide the hazards of smoking, and were found liable in federal
court last year for violating racketeering laws. Global warming has been blamed for stronger hurricanes,
more wildfires and worse droughts. While there have been cycles
of warming and cooling throughout Earth's history, the last 30
years have seen a steep warming trend which most scientists say
is due to emission of so-called greenhouse gases by the burning
of fossil fuels in vehicles, factories and power plants. ExxonMobil has funded legitimate scientific studies on
climate change, the watchdog report said, but noted it has also
spent approximately $16 million between 1998 and 2005 on 43
organizations that have cast doubt on the reality of
human-caused global warming. The report said these have ranged from $30,000 for the
group Africa Fighting Malaria, which argues on its Web site
against urgent action on climate change, to $1.6 million to the
American Enterprise Institute, a pro-business think tank in
Washington. James McCarthy, professor of biological oceanography and
director of the Museum of Comparative Zoology at Harvard
University, noted a 2005 statement issued by the U.S. National
Academy of Sciences and 10 science academies from other
countries, affirming that "climate change is now sufficiently
clear to justify nations taking prompt action." "This report reveals for the first time the degree to which
efforts to exaggerate uncertainty in climate science produce
non scientific reports designed to cast doubt on published
scientific climate studies have been orchestrated by
ExxonMobil," McCarthy said at the news conference. Company spokesman Dave Gardner said in an e-mail that the
company acknowledged the burning of fossil fuels is a major
source of greenhouse gas emissions. He said ExxonMobil supports various public policy groups
but said financial support does not mean it has control over
the groups' positions. "We find some of them persuasive and enlightening, and some
not. But there is value in the debate they prompt if it can
lead to better informed and more optimal public policy
decisions," Gardner said.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/environment-exxonmobil-idUSN0343235220070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - exxonmobil cultivates global warming doubt - report</title></story></items>