<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:37 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>DETROIT The U.S. sales of General Motors Corp. (GM.N) and Ford Motor Co. (F.N) fell in December, hurt by declines in demand for trucks, while Japanese rival Toyota Motor Corp. (7203.T) continued to gain ground.GM and Ford sales fell about 10 percent each, when adjusted for an extra selling day a year earlier. DaimlerChrysler AG's DCXGn.DE Chrysler unit was the lone U.S. automaker to make gains as its adjusted sales rose 4 percent. Toyota's sales rose more than 16 percent, driven by strong demand for its Corolla and Camry sedans.Ford said its sales were hurt by a 21 percent decline in sales of F-series pickup trucks -- its top-selling vehicle. Explorer SUV sales fell 29.5 percent. Overall truck sales were down 14 percent due to higher gas prices and a soft housing market."The (truck) segment will still continue to be under pressure ... at least in the early part of 2007," Ford sales analyst George Pipas said on a conference call. "The new products will help offset some of the softness we are seeing in housing."Ford's car sales fell almost 10 percent.The combined monthly U.S. market share for Detroit's Big Three is estimated to be 54.3 percent in December, down from 56.6 percent a year earlier, according to industry-tracking firm Edmunds.com.Honda Motor Co. Ltd. (7267.T) said U.S. December sales rose 3 percent and Nissan North America Co. Ltd. (7201.T) said sales rose 4.4 percent, driven by demand for its new Altima, Sentra and Versa cars.Asian automakers have gained ground this year as consumers shifted away from larger gas-guzzling sport utility vehicles to  smaller SUVs and cars.Toyota, Nissan, Honda and Hyundai Motor Co. Ltd. (005380.KS) have relied on cars in the U.S. market, while domestic automakers have focused on larger SUVs and trucks, which account for at least 60 percent of their sales.GM'S TRANSACTION PRICE UPGM's average U.S. transaction price on vehicles rose 8 percent in December from the prior year, its chief sales analyst told reporters and analysts on Wednesday.Paul Ballew, GM's chief sales analyst said transaction prices were up 7 percent during the fourth quarter and up 2 percent for 2006.But GM cut its 2006 fourth-quarter production by 13 percent, Ford forecast a 22 percent cut and Chrysler reduced second-half production by as much as 17 percent.JP Morgan analyst Himanshu Patel expects Ford and GM to cut production further in 2007.New U.S vehicle sales for December are expected to reach a seasonally adjusted annual rate of between 16.5 million and 16.8 million vehicles, according to analysts. That would be down from last December's 17.1 million rate.(Additional reporting by Poornima Gupta in Detroit and David Bailey in Chicago)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-autos-sales-idUSN0339857020070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>gm , ford december u . s . sales down , toyota gains</title></story></items>