<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:41 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts lead paragraph, updates prices) By Chris ReeseNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. government bond prices
rose on Wednesday on weak private-sector jobs data and minutes
from the last Federal Reserve policy meeting that showed a
central bank wary of slowing economic growth. Price gains were tempered, however, by a
stronger-than-expected U.S. factory activity index for
December. The Fed's concern over potentially slower growth, expressed
in the minutes of its Dec. 12 policy meeting, helped to
marginally boost investor expectations that the central bank
may be considering the possibility of an official interest rate
cut later this year. "One bullish item for Treasuries was that several members
of the Fed monetary policy committee saw a 'subdued tone' to
the economic data and thought the downside risk to growth had
increased," said Cary Leahey, managing director at Decision
Economics in New York. Leahey cautioned however that a good portion of the
indicators released since the December meeting have shown an
economy that is looking more resilient, and the central bank's
concern over slowing growth was based on relatively old data. "The one headline that could be viewed as bullish for bonds
is probably, correctly, considered by the market to be out of
date," Leahey said. Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR traded 5/32 higher in
price for a yield of 4.66 percent from 4.68 percent late on
Tuesday. Treasuries rallied early in the day after a surprise
contraction in a private jobs report which hinted the nonfarm
payrolls report on Friday could prove soft. After the data,
economists at some Wall Street banks cut their forecasts for
the government's nonfarm payrolls report. The ADP National Employment Report showed U.S. private
sector employment likely declined by 40,000 in December, the
first contraction since April 2003. "Clearly, going into the employment data this Friday,
people coming into the New Year with a clean book would
certainly feel that this (the ADP report) is something people
want to be buying bonds on," said Michael Cheah, vice president
and portfolio manager with AIG SunAmerica Asset Management in
Jersey City, New Jersey. However, those early bond gains were later tempered by
stronger-than-expected U.S. factory data. The Institute for
Supply Management's December manufacturing report reading was
51.4, above the 50 mark that divides expansion from
contraction. Economists had forecast the index would rise to
49.9 from November's 49.5 reading. Two-year notes US2YT=RR traded 2/32 higher in price for a
yield of 4.77 percent from 4.81 percent late on Tuesday, while
five-year notes US5YT=RR traded 3/32 higher in price for a
yield of 4.66 percent from 4.68 percent. Thirty-year notes US30YT=RR traded 11/32 higher in price
for a yield of 4.77 percent from 4.79 percent.
  (Additional reporting by John Parry and Ellen Freilich)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-bonds-idUSN0358640620070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - prices rise on fed economic growth concern , jobs</title></story></items>