<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:24 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts, adds trader comment, other details) By Marcy NicholsonNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - A sustained bout of increased
green coffee prices caused the largest U.S. roaster and industry
trendsetter to raise its list prices for some of its Folgers
coffee, a spokesman said on Wednesday. Procter &amp; Gamble (PG.N) raised list prices for Folgers roast
and ground coffee by 4 percent, or up 10 cents per 11.5 and 13
ounce equivalent small-sized canister, spokesman Lars Atorf
said. P&amp;G also increased the Folgers gourmet selections by 20
cents per 11.5 ounce equivalent, a 5 percent increase, Atorf
said. "This price move is reflecting the sustained green coffee
price increase for arabica beans on the New York arabica 'C'
market," Atorf said. There were no more price moves planned at this time, Atorf
said. Roasters typically buy green coffee beans, roast them and
package them to be sold as either ground or whole beans. Arabica coffee trades on the New York Board of Trade, and
dealers said that other roasters typically follow suit after one
company makes the first move. "Usually when one goes, they all go," one NYBOT trader
said. As of late Wednesday, none of the other large roasters
contacted by Reuters had announced price increases. U.S. arabica coffee futures contracts settled lower on
Wednesday with benchmark March KCH7 falling 2.60 cents at
$1.2360 per lb, but its settling price has climbed from $1.1070
on Oct. 23, 2006. "The price hike should allow the roasters to pay up a little
bit all through the week," the trader said, looking ahead to
coffee futures trading on Thursday. The last time P&amp;G increased prices was three months ago, on
Oct. 3, 2006. Two days later, Kraft Foods Inc. KFT.N raised
suggested retail prices on some Maxwell House products, and
Massimo Zanetti boosted prices on Chock full o'Nuts and other
ground and instant coffee brands. Both cited gains up to 70
percent in green robusta prices in the last year.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/coffee-price-proctergamble-idUSN0347691620070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 2 - procter &amp; gamble hikes some coffee prices</title></story></items>