<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:32 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds statement from AFL-CIO in paragraphs 9-10) By Martha GraybowNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - Robert Nardelli's
multimillion-dollar pay as chief of Home Depot Inc. (HD.N) made
him, and the retailer, a favorite target of shareholder activists.
Now, his exit package is giving critics a new round of
ammunition. Nardelli stepped down from his job as chairman and chief
executive on Wednesday, walking away with about $210 million in a
severance deal -- the equivalent of about $96,000 for every day of
his 6-year tenure. The payout comes on top of earnings of at least $119.2 million
in salary and bonus, not including options, that Nardelli, 58,
collected as CEO through the end of fiscal 2006. All the while, Home Depot shares lost nearly 8 percent of
their value during Nardelli's tenure. "He should be giving money back, not taking more money out,"
said Nell Minow, co-founder of The Corporate Library, a research
group that rates companies' governance practices. "Performance has
been poor and he has been hugely overpaid every step of the way." Investor activists have a long list of complaints over how
Home Depot is run -- and they say the board should have cut a much
less generous exit deal with Nardelli. The Atlanta-based company has been under pressure amid
weakening sales and profits and it faces a regulatory probe into
its stock options award practices. It drew particular wrath last
year when board members skipped the 2006 annual meeting amid
criticism of Nardelli's compensation. "The golden parachute he's been given is not acceptable to
shareholders," said Richard Ferlauto, director or pension and
benefit policy at the American Federation of State County and
Municipal Employees, a union umbrella group that has been critical
of executive compensation. The AFL-CIO on Wednesday called on Home Depot to freeze all
payments to Nardelli until the company can determine whether the
compensation pact was properly entered into and whether the former
CEO "complied with his obligations under those agreements." The union group also called for the resignation of lead
director Kenneth Langone, who was sued by the New York attorney
general's office over the pay package of former New York Stock
Exchange chairman Richard Grasso in a separate case. The group
said it also wants further disclosure from the company about the
findings of an internal probe into the timing of stock options
awards. Janna Sampson, a fund manager at OakBrook Investments outside
Chicago that holds about 513,000 Home Depot shares, said the board
likely had little choice but to give Nardelli the large payout --
as his severance terms were outlined in his employment agreement. The company is paying a "pretty steep price" to get rid of
Nardelli, she said. But Home Depot "may be trying to remove what
had become kind of a block to moving forward." Some politicians were quick to weigh in on the exit package.
Nardelli's severance is "further confirmation of the need to deal
with a pattern of CEO pay that appears to be out of control," said
U.S. Rep. Barney Frank, chairman of the House Financial Services
Committee. MONEY, MONEY, MONEY Home Depot isn't the only company that's come under criticism
recently for payouts to outgoing chiefs. Ex-Pfizer Inc. (PFE.N) CEO Hank McKinnell, who was replaced
following a steep decline in the company's market value, will get
about $198 million upon his departure. Meanwhile, shareholder watchdogs say they are awaiting details
of how much the new Home Depot chief, 57-year-old Vice Chairman
Frank Blake, will be paid. Both Nardelli and Blake were formerly
executives at General Electric Co. (GE.N). "My guess is the pay package (for Blake) is not going to be
high profile -- his package will probably be more run of the
mill," said Joseph Carcello, director of research at the
University of Tennessee's Corporate Governance Center. The company's board, he said, has been shown that "you need to
align the compensation more closely with the returns to
stockholders." But Minow, of the Corporate Library, which gives Home Depot an
"F" grade for overall governance practices, says that it won't be
clear if the board has learned its lessons until the specifics of
the new CEO's pay package are released. "We will get a chance to see if they have learned from their
mistakes," she said. "Based on this departure package, it looks
like they haven't." (Additional reporting by Joseph Giannone)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/homedepot-nardelli-exitpackage-idUSN0343153820070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>update 1 - home depot still needs to learn lessons , critics say</title></story></items>