<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:31 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 The U.S. dollar advanced
broadly on Wednesday, hitting two-month highs against the yen,
after a survey showed the U.S. factory sector expanded in
December, defying forecasts of another modest contraction. The dollar jumped after the Institute for Supply Management
said its manufacturing index climbed to 51.4 from 49.5 in
November and above the 50 threshold that separates expansion
and contraction. For details, see [nnN03391475] The dollar pared gains midafternoon after the release of
minutes from the Federal Reserve's December policy meeting even
as the overall trend for the greenback remained up on the day.
The minutes indicated the central bank sees increased downside
risks to economic growth even as inflation remained the
predominant concern. "The fact that ISM came back above 50 puts the whole
soft-landing, dollar-positive scenario back in play," said
Boris Schlossberg, senior currency strategist at Forex Capital
Markets in New York. Led by strong gains against European currencies including
sterling, the euro and the Swiss franc, the dollar had its
biggest rise in around six months against a basket of six major
currencies .DXY. The euro EUR= was trading down 0.9 percent on the day at
$1.3159, its biggest one-day decline since mid-July of last
year. Meanwhile, sterling tumbled 1.2 percent to $1.9495 GBP=,
its biggest one-day decline since July 2005. The dollar was up 0.5 percent at 119.35 yen JPY= after
reaching as high as 119.68 on electronic trading platform EBS. The dollar rose around 1.1 percent against the Swiss
currency, to 1.2264 francs CHF=.  Participants in the policy-making Federal Open Market
Committee meeting said the slowdown in the housing sector
continued to weigh heavily on economic activity in the United
States. Although there was evidence that home sales might be
stabilizing, residential investment was likely to fall further
in coming quarters as builders reduced inventories, officials
felt. "The minutes are very much 'permanent hold' kind of minutes
and I think they reflect an FOMC that was discussing a somewhat
more downbeat economy on Dec. 12," said Lara Rhame, senior FX
strategist at Credit Suisse in New York. Earlier in the session, the dollar had given up some ground
after a report showed employment in the U.S. private sector
contracted unexpectedly in December. [ID:nNAT002355] The soft report led some traders to speculate that the more
closely watched nonfarm payrolls report -- due on Friday --
could also come in softer than expectations. "It points to a pretty poor payroll number on Friday," said
Shaun Osborne, senior currency strategist at TD Securities in
Toronto. A weak reading in that payrolls report would likely
strengthen the view that the Federal Reserve may start cutting
interest rates in coming months to shore up a slowing economy. Late afternoon in New York, the futures market was still
only pricing in a 12 percent chance of a rate cut by March,
though chances of a rate cut by July had edged up to 84 percent
from 80 percent. [ID:nCHB000247] Elsewhere, the euro climbed to an eight-year high against
the Swiss franc on Wednesday, as investors continued a broad
trend of selling low yielding currencies.
 (Additional reporting by Steven C. Johnson and Amanda Cooper)







</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSN0343224420070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - dollar gains as us dec ism beats forecasts</title></story></items>