<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:43 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>BUENOS AIRES Jan 3 Argentine stocks fell on
Wednesday after six days of gains that had pushed the market to
a record high close a day earlier, hurt by profit-taking in
market heavyweight Tenaris and led by declines in other
regional markets. The MerVal index .MERV of 15 leading stocks fell 1.94
percent to 2,097.55 points after hitting an intraday record
high early in the day. The index had gained almost 5 percent
over the last six sessions. Tenaris (TENA.BA) (TS.N), the global leader in seamless
steel pipes for the oil industry, fell 3.42 percent to 73.5
pesos per share, its lowest close in two and a half weeks. Oil
prices slumped 4 percent due to mild weather in the U.S. cut
fuel demand, and as slowing economic growth has undercut
investor interest in commodities. Tenaris shares, weighted more than one third of the MerVal,
had doubled in value in 2006 due to strong oil prices. "It was profit-taking led by the Tenaris correction, which
then deepened due to Wall Street," said Oscar Campos, a trader
wtih Intervalores brokerage. Brazil's Bovespa index .BVSP fell 2.7 percent, while
Mexico's IPC .MXX slipped 0.17 percent. The Dow Jones
Industrial Average .DJI dipped earlier in the day, but then
recovered at the end of the session to close up just 0.09
percent. Volume on the Buenos Aires Stock Exchange was $40.2
million, the heaviest since Dec. 13. On the foreign exchange market, the peso currency closed
flat in trade between foreign exchange houses ARSB= at
3.085/3.08575 per U.S. dollar. In interbank trade, where the
central bank intervenes heavily, the peso fell 0.08 percent to
3.0575/3.06 per dollar ARS=RASL. "The volume of dollars on offer was higher than on Tuesday
and the market's only buyer (of dollars) was the central bank,
which had to act firmly since early in the session the peso
fell to 3.052 (per dollar) due to the selling pressure," said
Fernando Izzo, analyst with ABC foreign exchange. Izzo said exporters, banks and investors all shed dollars
to buy peso-denominated government debt, which despite a
narrowing spread against U.S. treasuries, still have attractive
yields.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-argentina-idUSN0342934720070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>argentine stocks succumb after six days of gains</title></story></items>