<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:51 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 Alltel Corp.'s (AT.N) credit
spreads will widen significantly if the company is targeted in
a leveraged buyout, which many analysts view as a strong
possibility. However, the wireless telecom company's credit default
swaps are already trading much wider than its debt ratings
imply, and if the company is instead bought by a competitor,
such as Verizon Communications Inc. (VZ.N), they will narrow. The cost to insure Alltel's debt with credit default swaps
has doubled since early December on LBO speculation to around
100 basis points on Wednesday, or $100,000 per year for five
years to insure $10 million in debt. "The debt is going to be very volatile," said Zhiping Zhao,
senior analyst at research company CreditSights. If Alltel is bought in a leveraged buyout, its ratings
would go into junk territory and its spreads will widen by
another 100 basis points or more, Zhao said. If the company if bought by Verizon, however, its swaps
could trade in the 20 basis point area, she added. The Wall Street Journal reported on Thursday that
private-equity firms are exploring the idea of a leveraged
buyout for the fifth-largest U.S. wireless operator, resulting
in a 25 basis point spread widening from 75 basis points. An Alltel spokesman said the company does not "comment on
speculation." Spreads had also widened ahead of the report as speculation
increased the company may be a LBO target, said Dave Novosel,
analyst at New York-based Gimme Credit. "If you look at the good cash flow they generate, solid
margins, very low leverage compared to many other telecom
operators: that in of itself tends to be a good candidate" for
an LBO, he said. Smaller telecommunications companies are under pressure to
consolidate to cut costs and compete against larger firms. "If you are a wireless player you need network coverage and
quality," said CreditSights Zhao. Wireline operators,
meanwhile, need to reduce costs "given that revenue is flat at
best," she added. "The only way you can actually maintain your earnings per
share, or margin is to reduce costs," she said. Alltel is subscale and needs to do something to increase
its size, Zhao said. The company is probably more attractive to
private equity buyers than to Verizon, which is the most likely
strategic buyer, she added. Due to Alltel's low leverage, the buyer of the company has
a lot of potential to significantly increase its leverage and
extract a lot of value from the firm, she said. From Verizon's perspective, however, other competitors such
as Qwest Corp. (Q.N) may be more attractive as it would offer
greater synergies and cost reduction possibilities, Zhao said. Barclays Capital analysts have assigned a 70 percent
probability that Alltel may be sold to a private equity buyer
if it is sold, compared with a 30 percent probability of a
strategic buyer. "While we believe management's first preference might be to
merge with a strategic buyer, the relative lack of strategic
buyers versus the economics of an LBO may make the latter too
compelling to ignore," the analysts wrote in a research report
on Wednesday.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-credit-idUSN0356969220070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>us credit - lbo risk looms large over alltel ' s debt</title></story></items>