<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:29 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>PHILADELPHIA Shipping company EGL Inc. EAGL.O 
on Tuesday said Chief Executive Officer James Crane and private 
equity firm General Atlantic LLC have offered to buy the 
company for $36 per share in cash. The offer price represents a 21 percent premium to the 
stock's Friday closing price. Crane is EGL's largest 
shareholder, owning 18 percent of its stock. Crane said he would continue as chairman and CEO following 
the buyout of EGL, which provides services including air and 
ocean freight forwarding and local delivery service. Management-led buyout offers are becoming more popular, 
helped in part by the large amount of private equity money 
willing to partner on such deals. Private equity firms buy companies and sell them later, 
typically changing management teams and streamlining the 
businesses along the way. Management-led buyouts are deals in 
which chief executives and/or other top officers are among the 
buyers and plan to stay in control of the company. Executives usually extol such buyouts as a way to grow the 
business in private and focus on long-term goals, free of Wall 
Street's short-term pressures. These deals also invite scrutiny 
because the company is pressed to evaluate the best offer, even 
as its management is the one presenting the bid. EGL's board of directors has formed a special committee of 
independent directors to review the proposal. Crane said Bank of America Securities LLC, Goldman Sachs 
Credit Partners L.P., Merrill Lynch, and Pierce, Fenner &amp; Smith 
Inc. provided letters regarding the buyout group's ability to 
raise the $1.125 billion of debt financing needed for the deal. 
Merrill Lynch also is serving as financial advisor to the group 
in connection with the offer. (Additional reporting by Swagata Gupta in Bangalore and 
Jessica Hall in Philadelphia)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/businesspro-egl-takeover-dc-idUSN0233736020070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>egl gets $ 36 a share management - buyout offer</title></story></items>