<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:00 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds share price, background)LOS ANGELES Jan 3 (Reuters) - Goth-inspired retailer Hot
Topic Inc. HOTT.O on Wednesday slashed its earnings outlook
for the fourth quarter due to disappointing sales of music and
clothing during the holiday shopping season, and shares tumbled
11 percent. The company, which has faced dwindling demand at its
mall-based Hot Topic chain, said it expects to earn between 20
cents and 22 cents per share for the quarter, down from a
previous view of 33 cents to 38 cents per share. Wall Street analysts, on average, had been expecting
earnings of 34 cents a share, according to Reuters Estimates. Sales at the company's stores open at least a year, a key
retail measure known as same-store sales, fell 5.1 percent in
December. The company also operates the Torrid chain, which
sells hip, plus-sized apparel for young women. In a statement, Hot Topic said sales were particularly weak
during the first half of the month, prompting the chain to
offer more discounts than planned. "We are very disappointed by our consolidated December
results and their implications for the quarter," Hot Topic
Chief Executive Betsy McLaughlin said. To clear inventories, the retailer said it is increasing
markdowns and expects same-store sales to be down in the mid
single digits for the quarter. Inventories at the end of the quarter are expected to be
about flat compared to last year on a per square foot basis,
Hot Topic said. On a positive note, Hot Topic said sales of men's and
women's licensed and fashion novelty T-shirts were positive
during the month. Some Wall Street analysts have recently considered Hot
Topic to be at a positive point in a turnaround, as it opens
new stores with brighter, more inviting layouts and introduces
new merchandise geared at reversing nearly 2 years of sluggish
sales. Hot Topic shares fell $1.44 to $12.10 in extended trade
after closing at $13.54, up 20 cents, on Nasdaq. (Additional reporting by Alexandria Sage)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/hottopic-outlook-idUSN0339869920070103</link><sectors><value><value>Markets</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - hot topic slashes outlook on weak december</title></story></items>