<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:53 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>  (Recasts, adds closing prices)MEXICO CITY Jan 3 (Reuters) - Mexican stocks fell and the
peso currency weakened on Wednesday after copper prices plunged
and minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's most recent meeting
renewed concerns about a U.S. economic slowdown. The benchmark IPC stock index .MXX closed down 0.17
percent to 26,619.37 points, snapping a five-day rally. The peso  MXN= MEX01 fell 0.52 percent since Tuesday's
local trading close to 10.8320 per dollar, also hurt by a 4
percent drop in crude futures traded in New York. In stock trading, Miner Grupo Mexico (GMEXICOB.MX), a major
copper producer, dragged hardest on the stock index, shedding
3.77 percent to 38.05 pesos after copper futures in New York
slumped to their lowest level since April of last year. The stock index dropped to as low as 26,319 points
immediately after the minutes from the Fed's Dec. 12 policy
meeting revealed central bankers see an increased risk to
economic growth. Mexico sells more than 80 percent of its exports to the
United States, so slower U.S. growth is bad news for the
Mexican economy. Dominant retailer Wal-Mart de Mexico WALMEXV.MX fell 0.82
percent to 47.16 pesos. Shares in cement maker Cemex (CMXCPO.MX), the world's third
largest producer of cement, fell 0.86 percent to 36.88 pesos,
while its New York traded shares (CX.N) were off 0.41 percent
to $34.802. On the winning end, dominant cellphone company America
Movil (AMXL.MX) rose 1.22 percent to 24.95 pesos. Its New York
traded shares (AMX.N) rose 2.19 percent to $46.21, while its
holding company America Telecom AMTELA1.MX closed up 0.83
percent to 100.90 pesos. Shares in Mexico's fifth largest bank Banorte (GFNORTEO.MX)
were among the top winners, rising 2.23 percent to 43.52
pesos. The IPC index rocketed up almost 49 percent in 2006 on
strong corporate profits and as perceptions of Mexico's country
risk fell dramatically, and many analysts expect the bull to
continue its charge this year, though at a slower pace.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-mexico-drop-idUSN0343237720070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>mexico stocks off on copper , worry over us economy</title></story></items>