<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:08 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MIAMI South Carolina Gov. Mark Sanford on Wednesday proposed a $6.5 billion state budget for fiscal 2007-08 that includes tax cuts, a down payment against looming retiree costs, and a big hike in a cigarette tax.The Republican governor, who was re-elected last year, said his plan keeps overall spending increases to 6.5 percent and was in line with the state's population growth and price inflation.The plan will be taken up starting next week by the state legislature.South Carolina's state government is expecting an $803 million revenue surge this year, with Sanford proposing to spend only half the rise during the fiscal year beginning in July.The rest would go for a $205 million income-tax cut, to create a fund to help pay for a forecast $9 billion of future, unfunded spending liabilities such as retiree health care, according to the governor's budget proposal.The governor also wants to pay off $21 million of outstanding debt and urged the legislature to reduce the state's cap on overall debt service costs at the current 4 percent of general fund revenue."By holding spending to a sustainable level and returning more dollars to ... taxpayers and small businesses, we can both fund the state's core needs and use the excess to grow the economy instead of growing government," Sanford said in a news release.The governor also proposed raising South Carolina's 7-cents-a-pack cigarette tax by 30 cents, an action which would add an estimated $107 million a year to state revenue and help pay for the proposed income tax cut.Both Democratic and Republican leaders have questioned Sanford's tax proposals, which the governor has been previewing in public meetings in recent weeks.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-southcarolina-budget-idUSN0341951920070103</link><sectors><value><value>Politics</value></value></sectors><title>s . carolina governor proposes $ 6 . 5 bln annual budget</title></story></items>