<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:00 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>BOSTON Jan 3 Two Parkinson's disease drugs
cause the same kind of heart damage that led to the withdrawal
of the diet drug combination "fen-phen," according to two
studies published on Wednesday. Patients taking the drugs pergolide, developed by Eli Lilly
&amp; Co. (LLY.N) and sold under the brand name Permax, and
cabergoline, developed by Pfizer Inc. (PFE.N) and sold under
the brand Dostinex, had a sharply higher risk of heart valve
damage than those taking other therapies, the studies said. The studies, one of which analyzed the records of 11,417
patients in Britain and one of which tested 245 patients in
Italy, reinforce the results of earlier, smaller studies
showing that drugs which activate a cellular receptor known as
5-HT2b can cause damage to the heart valve, a serious condition
that can lead to heart failure and sudden death. "We recommend that physicians not prescribe drugs that have
this biochemical property," said Bryan Roth, a researcher at
the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, who was not
involved in the trials but viewed the data and commented on it
in The New England Journal of Medicine, where both studies
appeared. Such drugs also include the migraine headache drug
ergotamine and the amphetamine derivative known as "ecstasy." Roth said his team, in a separate piece of research that
has yet to be published or reviewed by the scientific
community, has identified several other big-selling drugs that
have until now not been known to activate the 5-HT2b receptor. He declined to reveal the names of the drugs until the
research has been published. "We recommend that every drug be screened at this receptor
before it goes into humans," Roth told Reuters in an interview.
"It costs just pennies per drug for such a screen." The British study showed that patients taking pergolide
were 7.1 times more likely to develop heart valve damage than
those who took other treatments. Patients taking the highest
doses of the drug had a 37 times greater risk. The study showed that patients taking cabergoline were 4.9
times more likely to develop heart valve damage. At higher
doses patients were 50.3 times more likely to suffer damage. Both drugs are available in generic form. A second study, conducted in Italy, tested 245 people, of
whom 155 had Parkinson's disease. Of the diseased population,
one group received pergolide, one group received cabergoline,
and one group received an alternative Parkinson's treatment.
The non-diseased control group received nothing. The results showed that 23.4 percent of patients taking
pergolide and 28.6 percent of patients taking cabergoline
suffered heart damage, compared to just 5.6 percent in the
control group. "These are huge risks," said Roth. He said they were
similar to the kind of damage seen with fen-phen, whose main
ingredients were withdrawn in 1997 and forced the drug-maker
Wyeth WYE.N to take more than $21 billion in charges to cover
liabilities. Wyeth's recalled drugs were fenfluramine, or Pondimin, and
dexfenfluramine, or Redux. To make fen-phen, one or the other
was combined with another drug called phentermine that is still
sold by other companies. Wyeth, then called American Home Products, recalled
Pondimin and Redux after some of the 6 million Americans who
had taken fen-phen developed heart-valve problems. Roth said pergolide is also used to treat restless leg
syndrome, a condition in which patients feel a crawling
sensation in their legs combined with a need to move them. (Additional reporting by Ransdell Pierson in New York)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/parkinsons-drug-idUSN0341272520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>parkinson ' s drugs can cause heart damage - studies</title></story></items>