<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:57 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TOKYO Jan 4 U.S. Treasuries were little changed
in Asia on Thursday as investors awaited a flurry of economic
data that could offer more clues about whether the Federal
Reserve will start cutting interest rates this year. Trade in Asia was quiet as many Japanese investors were still
away for the new year's holidays. The Japanese bond and stock
markets were closed on Jan. 1-3 and resumed trading for a half
day on Thursday. Treasury prices rose on the previous day as weak
private-sector jobs data and minutes from the Fed's Dec. 12
policy meeting helped marginally to boost expectations that the
central bank may be considering the possibility of lowering the
funds rate from the current 5.25 percent later this year. But the Institute for Supply Management's December factory
activity index came out stronger than expected, capping gains in
Treasury prices. "The market is rather deadlocked today, waiting for more
clues on the Fed's future monetary policy," said a trader at a
Japanese trust bank. The market will watch for a variety of economic data due
later in the session as it could help strengthen or weaken
expectations for a rate cut by the Fed, traders said. The ISM will release its service sector index for December at
1500 GMT. November readings of factory orders and pending home sales
are also due at 1500 GMT. Investors will pay close attention to
weekly initial jobless claims as the report comes right before
Friday's highly-watched non-farm payrolls report for December,
traders said. The benchmark 10-year Treasury yield stood at 4.66 percent
US10YT=RR as of 0440 GMT, unchanged from late U.S. trading on
Wednesday. The two-year yield was little moved at 4.77 percent
US2YT=RR.


















</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/markets-treasuries-asia-idUST27294020070104</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>treasuries - sit tight in asia , await data</title></story></items>