<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:16 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> By Cameron French TORONTO, Jan 3 The Canadian dollar plunged to
nine-month lows against the U.S. currency on Wednesday, felled
by sliding oil prices and a broadly rallying greenback. Domestic bond prices edged higher, as concerns about U.S.
growth sent a mild charge into North American debt prices. The currency finished at C$1.1723  or 85.30 U.S. cents,
down from C$1.1636 to the U.S. dollar, or 85.94 U.S. cents, at
Tuesday's close. Crude oil prices fell nearly $3 per barrel as unseasonably
warm weather in the U.S. Northeast kept consumption low,
putting pressure on demand for heating fuels. With Canada's trade surplus heavily reliant on oil exports,
the retreat put pressure on the currency, which also felt the
sting from a broad U.S. dollar rally. The Canadian dollar dropped as far as C$1.1732, or 85.24
U.S. cents, its lowest level since last April, falling hard
overnight and sliding at a slower pace during the daily
session. "The move that we've seen today has really been a U.S.
dollar move rather than a Canada move," said Jack Spitz,
director of foreign exchange at National Bank Financial. "I think it's more of a reflection of risk being taken off
the table ahead of Friday's nonfarm payroll, rather than a
feeling that the U.S. dollar is going to catch a longer term
bid." Canada will also release December jobs data on Friday, and
analysts will be looking for signs the economy has not slowed
significantly. The greenback got a bit of a boost after the U.S. Institute
for Supply Management said its manufacturing index climbed to
52.4 from 49.5 in November. But the U.S. currency pared gains
in the afternoon after the release of the minutes from the U.S.
Federal Reserve's December policy meeting. Spitz said the overall direction for the Canadian dollar is
to weaken, but said the its recent sharp fall suggests it may
be due for a short-term retracement of its losses. He noted
that International Monetary Market futures showed record levels
of betting against the Canadian dollar. "I think that's seen as extreme and we could be in store
for a (U.S. dollar) pullback, certainly if Friday's payroll
data in Canada surprises to the upside," he said. BONDS EDGE HIGHER Canadian bond prices strengthened slightly, continuing to
unwind last week's losses and drawn higher by U.S. treasuries,
which were helped by the Fed minutes. The Fed expressed concern over potentially slower growth,
according to the minutes of its last meeting, slightly raising
expectations of an interest rate cut later this year. The Bank of Canada is also expected to ease rates, but
analysts are split on when it will happen. The central bank
makes its next announcement on Jan. 16, but it is expected to
leave rates steady. Thursday's trading could take its cue in part from the
release of November producer prices and raw materials prices. The two-year bond climbed 3 Canadian cents to C$100.49 to
yield 3.982 percent, while the 10-year bond rose 12 Canadian
cents to C$99.66 to yield 4.043 percent. The yield spread between the two-year and 10-year bond
moved to 6.1 basis points from 6.0 at the previous close. The 30-year bond rose 30 Canadian cents to C$126.45 to
yield 4.100 percent. In the United States, the 30-year treasury
yielded 4.764 percent. The three-month when-issued T-bill yielded 4.15 percent,
unchanged the previous close.
































</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-canada-dollar-bonds-idUSN0341717320070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>canadian dollar sags as oil falls ; bonds rise</title></story></items>