<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:20 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 The United States was the
single biggest recipient of investments from oil exporters
between 2003-2006, according to a Federal Reserve Bank of New
York study released on Wednesday. With oil revenues, or so-called petrodollars, expected to
have reached about $968 billion in 2006 from around $300
billion in 2002, NY Fed analysts Matthew Higgins, Thomas
Klitgaard, and Robert Lerman said investments by oil exporters
in U.S. assets likely totaled about $314 billion between
2003-2006. The $314 billion invested in the United States represented
less than one-fourth of the more than $1.3 trillion oil
exporters invested globally over the three-year period, the
largest investment so far. The figures suggested that oil exporters' windfall "whether
directly or indirectly" has increasingly financed the large and
growing U.S. current account deficit, the analysts said. The
U.S. current account shortfall ballooned to an estimated $869
billion in 2006, from about $472 billion in 2002, according to
NY Fed estimates. The NY Fed study also indicated that most petrodollar
investments found their way into the United States indirectly,
as countries like Japan, which had received investments from
oil exporters, funneled such inflows back to the United States
through the purchase of U.S. securities. On the trade side, oil exporters purchased more goods and
services from the euro zone and China, which offset both
regions' crude oil imports, the study said. The euro zone's oil imports more than doubled between
2002-2006, rising roughly by $192 billion to $316 billion, but
the region's exports to oil-producing nations climbed $77
billion to hit $167 billion. All told, the NY Fed analysts said
41 U.S. cents of each $1 of oil imports came back to the euro
zone in the form of higher purchases of euro zone goods.  Euro zone exports to oil-producing countries were higher
because of geographic proximity, the analysts said. Europe is
closer than the United States to the major oil exporters of the
Middle East, and two large oil exporters -- Norway and Russia
-- are in Europe itself. In the case of China, 60 cents of each $1 in oil purchases
sent overseas returned to purchase Chinese goods. "This high figure accords with the explosive growth of
China's exports to all markets. ... Given China's gains in
market share, the country might well have seen its sales to oil
exporters climb sharply, even if oil exporters' purchases
worldwide had remained flat in recent years," the NY Fed
analysts said. By contrast, just 20 cents of each $1 imported by the
United States came back for the purchase of American goods.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/economy-usa-oil-idUSN0343612720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>us single biggest recipient of petrodollars - study</title></story></items>