<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:43 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds background, market close, byline) By Mark FelsenthalWASHINGTON Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. Federal Reserve
officials agreed at their December meeting inflation was the
predominant concern, but some felt the "subdued tone" of
economic data meant risks to growth had increased, minutes
released on Wednesday showed. "Several members judged that the subdued tone of some
incoming indicators meant that the downside risks to economic
growth in the near term had increased a little and become a bit
more broadly based than previously thought," said the minutes
of the Dec 12 meeting. "Nonetheless, all members agreed that the risk that
inflation would fail to moderate as desired remained the
predominant concern," the minutes added. The Fed's concern over potentially slower growth helped
boost investor expectations the central bank may cut interest
rates in 2007, boosting U.S. Treasury debt prices and U.S. rate
futures. Stocks reversed gains and ended little changed on the
day, and the dollar also pared gains but was up on the day. "The biggest change is that they are showing a little more
anxiety about the economy," said Sam Rahman, a portfolio
manager for Baring Asset Management Inc., in Boston. "While inflation remains a key focus, the FOMC is showing
clearer signs that the weakening economic environment has
raised concerns," he said. The U.S. central bank at the Dec 12 meeting held benchmark
interest rates steady at 5.25 percent, renewing a warning on
inflation but also nodding to "mixed" economic signals and a
"substantial" housing slowdown. The minutes showed one member of the policy-setting
committee was concerned enough about growth to favor a
statement saying monetary policy could be adjusted in either
direction. The statement the Fed issued last month said only that
additional firming -- increases in interest rates -- might be
necessary to address risks from inflation. Participants in the Federal Open Market Committee meeting
said the slowdown in the housing sector continued to weigh
heavily on economic activity in the United States. Although
there was evidence that home sales might be stabilizing,
residential investment was likely to fall further in coming
quarters as builders reduced inventories, officials felt. The housing slowdown has not spilled over significantly
into consumer spending, but "considerable uncertainty"
surrounding housing activity meant its impact on spending could
eventually become more evident, especially if house prices
decline significantly, officials said. At the same time, central bank officials said a slowdown in
business investment and production, along with high inventories
for automobiles and in other sectors, added to a picture of
slowing economic expansion. However, economic data released since then has pointed to
resilience in the economy. Consumer confidence was at its highest level in December in
eight months, existing homes sales rose in November for the
second month in a row, and Chicago purchasing managers snapped
back into expansion mode in the last month of the year, reports
released at the end of December showed. All of the participants in the meeting remained concerned
about inflation, the minutes said. "Although readings on core inflation had improved modestly
since the spring, nearly all participants viewed core inflation
as uncomfortably high and stressed the importance of further
moderation," the minutes said. The FOMC saw "considerable uncertainty" regarding how much
and how fast core inflation would recede and believed that the
risks around the desired downward path remained to the upside.








</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/usa-fed-minutes-idUSN0340865420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 3 - some at fed saw increased risks to growth - minutes</title></story></items>