<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:20 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>CHICAGO Jan 3 Many option investors appear to
be betting on a big move in the shares of an energy fund in
what can be called a volatility play after a 4 percent drop in
crude oil prices, traders said on Wednesday. Shares of energy companies such as Exxon Mobil Corp.
(XOM.N) were a big drag on the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 Index
.SPX as U.S. crude oil for February delivery CLG7 fell
$2.73 to settle at $58.32 a barrel. Oil prices headed south during this first day of trading
in 2007 due to mild winter weather in the U.S. Northeast,
which cut demand for fuel in the world's biggest heating oil
market. The slide in crude oil prices prompted many market
participants to focus on both the puts and calls pegged to the
shares of the Energy Select Sector SPDR fund (XLE.A)(XLE.N),
where roughly 180,800 contracts -- dominated by 143,897 puts
-- traded late on the day. The exchange traded fund, down 3.86 percent at $56.48, is
one of the most active of the SPDR sector funds, tracking the
energy-related stocks from within the benchmark S&amp;P 500
index. "Both puts and calls were active in the XLE due to the
fact that people are speculating that oil prices are going to
fluctuate over the near-term," said William Lefkowitz, options
strategist at brokerage firm vFinance Investments in New
York. In a volatility play, investors who expect
greater-than-anticipated stock moves will buy puts or calls
that they deem to be underpriced and will rise in value due to
a stock swing in either direction. A LITTLE SOUTHERN EXPOSURE Some investors have turned to puts in the fund, betting
that oil prices are heading down as the weather in the
Northeast has been unusually warm and continued to stay that
way this week, Lefkowitz said. But other players were looking at upside XLE calls,
speculating that oil prices will rebound quickly as they have
done many times in the past, Lefkowitz added. Susquehanna Financial Group chief options analyst Stacey
Briere Gilbert also noted that volatility option buyers
dominated order flow in the fund during the session. She noticed investors were mostly buying puts with strike
prices of $54, $57 and $59 in January, February and March.
Players also were purchasing calls that grant them the right
to buy the fund at $58 and $61 by mid-January. The flurry of option interest was also accompanied by a
rise in the fund's option projected volatility -- a
statistical measure related to how much a security is expected
to move up or down based on near-term option prices. "At-the-money volatility is up approximately 2 points in
each of the front three months," Briere Gilbert said.





</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/energy-options-spdr-idUSN0342387920070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>energy etf options draw interest in volatility play</title></story></items>