<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:46 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds Reid comments) By Steve HollandWASHINGTON Jan 3 (Reuters) - With Democrats poised to take
over Congress, President George W. Bush on Wednesday used a
Rose Garden ceremony and a newspaper opinion piece to push for
spending cuts and rally support for an Iraq policy he has yet
to announce. Speaking at a ceremony after a Cabinet meeting, Bush used
the White House stage to announce a proposal to balance the
U.S. budget by 2012. He also wrote a rare opinion article in
The Wall Street Journal promoting his new strategy for Iraq to
be announced in coming days. Bush called upon Democrats to set aside politics, but
Democrats, who are preparing to flex their muscle with a
legislative push when they take command of Congress on
Thursday, responded cautiously. "We hope that when the president says compromise, it means
more than 'do it my way,' which is what he's meant in the
past," said New York Democratic Sen. Charles Schumer. "I'm encouraged that President Bush said today that he
wants to work in bipartisanship, and I hope he means it," said
incoming Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid of Nevada. In his White House comments, Bush said he would present a
five-year plan to Congress next month that would balance the
budget by 2012 -- three years after his presidency ends -- and
make lower tax rates permanent. Bush called on Congress to reform the process in which
billions of dollars in individual spending items, known as
"earmarks," for specific congressional districts are able to
get approved without a vote. Balancing the budget in that time frame would require
substantial spending discipline, given that recent projections
by the White House showed it expected a budget gap of $127
billion by 2011. In early February, Congress expects Bush to request about
$100 billion in additional "emergency" funds to pay for combat
in Iraq and Afghanistan. The wars currently are being funded
with $70 billion put into the pipeline a few months ago. "We welcome the president's newfound commitment to a
balanced budget, but his comments make us wary," said incoming
House Budget Committee Chairman John Spratt of South Carolina.
"They suggest that his budget will still embody the policies
that led to the largest deficits in history." Bush also wrote in a rare opinion article in The Wall
Street Journal on Wednesday that his new strategy for Iraq
would help the "people gain control of the security situation
and hasten the day when the Iraqi government gains full control
over its affairs." "We now have the opportunity to build a bipartisan
consensus to fight and win the war," he wrote. NEW IRAQ STRATEGY Bush is to announce a new strategy for Iraq as early as
Tuesday and he is considering a short-term increase of
thousands of U.S. troops to try to bring stability to Baghdad. The White House described him as "narrowing the choices"
and said he was focusing on a package of options that included
"the military front, the economic front and the political
front" to announce as a whole. Bush has two years left in office and believes he can
accomplish some of his legislative agenda, even though his
Republican Party has lost control of the House of
Representatives and the Senate and Americans are increasingly
turning their attention to the 2008 race to succeed him.
 (Additional reporting by Glenn Somerville, Richard Cowan and
Thomas Ferraro)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/bush-cabinet-idUSN0343870720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - bush seeks backing for agenda on u . s . budget , iraq</title></story></items>