<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:47 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MADRID A party seen by Spain's government as the political wing of Basque guerrillas ETA said on Wednesday it was caught by surprise by Saturday's deadly car bomb, which led the government to end the country's peace process.Rescue workers at Madrid Airport on Wednesday found the body of one of the two Ecuadorean immigrants believed to have been sleeping in their cars at the time of the blast, which injured another 19 people.It was the first ETA attack to claim a life for more than three years and ended a nine-month ceasefire."I don't think anyone expected an attack like the one in Madrid," Joseba Alvarez, a leading member of Batasuna, told Basque radio in a remark which some might interpret as signaling divisions within the region's independence movement.The government broke off attempts at dialogue with ETA after the car bomb, which wrecked a multi-story car park at the capital's international airport.The Interior Ministry said 35-year-old Carlos Alonso Palate had been found in his car covered by a blanket."Justice will be done," Spanish Prime Minister Jose Luis Rodriguez Zapatero said after meeting with the families of the victims on Wednesday. "The people who committed this awful crime will be brought to justice."Speaking to reporters, Zapatero said the airport bomb was not only a crime but was, "completely useless as far as any objective the terrorist group may have."The Spanish government sees Batasuna as ETA's political wing. The banned party refuses either to admit to links with the guerrillas or to condemn its attacks, in which more than 800 people have been killed in four decades of separatist struggle.A split between Batasuna and ETA could further complicate attempts to negotiate a solution to the Basque conflict, which began in the final phase of the Franco dictatorship when the region's distinctive language and culture were suppressed.ETA has not claimed responsibility for the attack, although the government said that one of three warning calls received in the hour before the blast claimed to be from the guerrillas.Before the airport blast, the last ETA killings had been in May 2003 when a car bomb killed two policemen in the northern Spanish town of Sanguesa.Batasuna had warned for months of a crisis in the peace process that Zapatero began in June.Batasuna wants to be legalized again, as well as demanding police ease pressure on Basque nationalists and that ETA prisoners be transferred to jails closer to the Basque Country.About one in seven Basques support Batasuna, polls show.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-spain-eta-idUSL0324047820070103</link><sectors><value><value>World</value></value></sectors><title>basque separatists say surprised by deadly eta bomb</title></story></items>