<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:42 31 December 2006 (UTC)</date><text> NEW YORK (Billboard) - In the troubled music industry, flat 
sales are the new up for retailers. According to Nielsen SoundScan, album sales totaled 105.3 
million for the six-week period ended December 24. That's 4.1% 
down from 2005's total of 109.8 million. And 2005 was 
considered the weakest holiday selling season in memory. Still, retailers choose to see a half-full glass. Billboard 
spoke with more than 20, responsible for roughly 40% of U.S. 
sales. "We had a good week Christmas week, and (the day after 
Christmas) was great," says Rob Perkins, president of 67-unit, 
Marietta, Ga.-based Value Music. "For the overall holiday 
selling season, we made plan, which means comparable-store 
sales were slightly down." Music label executives may cheer the volume of purchases: 
when digital track, music video and singles sales are included, 
sales totaled 47.4 million units for Christmas week, according 
to SoundScan. That tops the prior best-week sales total of 46.5 
million units, recorded during the Christmas week of 2000, the 
year that U.S. album sales peaked. However, digital sales are still not offsetting declines in 
the physical space. Using SoundScan's album equivalency of 10 
digital tracks sold -- generous, considering a typical album 
has more -- this year total album sales equaled 111.4 million 
units for the holiday selling period, still a 2.1% decline from 
last year's equivalent total of 113.8 million. Varying from merchant to merchant, 2006 holiday selling 
season comparable-store sales ranged from slightly down to 10% 
down. In Brighton, Mass., Mike Dreese -- CEO of 25-store chain 
Newbury Comics -- says the holiday selling season was "OK. 
November was not good, but December was pretty good." On a comparable-store basis, the chain's sales were down 
about 7% during December. In Nashville, Music City VP Scott Perkins reports that in 
the nine days leading up to Christmas, the 25-unit chain was 
down about 10% on a comparable-store basis. "We have seen worse 
percentages down in (comparable-store) sales," he says. "We 
will take any positive spin we can get." Likewise, in Omaha, Neb., Mike Fratt, GM at the six-store 
Homer's chain, reports that comparable-store holiday sales were 
down "high single digits." Fratt says, "We couldn't tell if there were any hits, 
because we lost that business to the big boxes (like Target and 
Best Buy) who were all selling the top hits at $9.99 . . . 
Business kicked in for us about 10 days out, I guess because 
the mass merchants ran out and were unable to reload in time." Joe Nardone Jr., VP at the 11-unit Gallery of Sound chain 
in Wilkes-Barre, Pa., says he saw a few hits emerge, including 
new releases from Nas, Eminem and the Beatles. Hinder's 
"Extreme Behavior," Daughtry's self-titled album and Twisted 
Sister's "Twisted Christmas" did better than expected, he says. 
And right at the end of the season, according to Nardone, 
Justin Timberlake's "FutureSex/LoveSounds" exploded while My 
Chemical Romance's "The Black Parade" and Akon's "Konvicted" 
also picked up.
 SURPRISE SELLERS At Newbury, Dreese reported that the chain underestimated 
the fire power of Sarah McLachlan's "Wintersong," James 
Taylor's "At Christmas" and Tony Bennett's "Duets: An American 
Classic." Other titles that did well include Young Jeezy's "The 
Inspiration," Beyonce's "B'Day," Ciara's "The Evolution" and 
the J.J. Cale &amp; Eric Clapton album "The Road to Escondido," 
Value Music's Perkins reports. One surprise this year was the superb performance of 
Christmas music. In fact, one major-label executive says, "If 
it weren't for holiday music, everybody would be in the 
toilet." Retail executives regularly cited Christmas albums by 
Taylor, McLachlan and Il Divo as showing up in their top 10 
best-selling albums of the season. At Starbucks in Seattle, the chain's own exclusive "Santa 
Baby" compilation drove music sales, Starbucks Entertainment 
president Ken Lombard says. Issued in November, it has since 
crossed the 250,000-unit mark, he reported just before 
Christmas. While most brick-and-mortar merchants reported sales 
declines, online merchants selling physical goods had a banner 
year, according to one wholesaler who does fulfillment for such 
retailers. Indeed, Amazon claimed it had its best holiday 
selling season ever, though it declined to release specific 
numbers. SoundScan reports that nontraditional merchants--which 
include catalog merchants and albums sold at concerts or 
through TV direct-marketing campaigns -- enjoyed a 35.5% 
increase during the holiday. Reuters/Billboard</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/music-sales-dc-idUSN3126663420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Music</value></value></sectors><title>a blue christmas for music business</title></story></items>