<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>02:44 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON (Citywire) - Aberdeen Asset Management has won the mandate to run the Guinness Flight Venture Capital Trust (GFVCT).Inflexion Private Equity Partners, GFVCT's previous manager, has decided to focus on the buy-out side of its business. It recently closed its 2006 Buyout fund after assets hit 165 million pounds.Aberdeen took control of the VCT on December 22 and the firm's growth capital team has signed a contract to run the fund for a minimum of four years. Aberdeen's investment director Neil MacFadyen will run GFVCT.Head of the Aberdeen growth capital team Bill Nixon said: "We are very excited at the prospect of managing Guinness Flight VCT."We welcome the opportunity to reinvigorate the fund in the same way we have done for the other maturing Aberdeen VCTs and allow shareholders to benefit from our access to dealflow across the UK."GFVCT, which runs 19.1 million pounds in assets, originally launched in 1986 at 100p per share. Its share price has since fallen to 60p.Shareholders over the years include Tory MP Howard Flight, who founded Guinness Flight Asset Management alongside Investec Asset Management fund manager Tim Guinness. Other investors have included Lord Hollick, Bestinvest boss John Spiers and IMS chief Richard Timberlake.According to the Association of Investment Companies, GFVCT shares have risen 107.5 percent in the last five years versus a 148.9 percent gain in the FTSE Small Cap excluding investment trusts index. Its net asset value has risen by 92.3 percent over this period.In the last year the trust has marginally outperformed, returning 121.7 percent versus a gain of 120.2 percent in its benchmark.The VCT business was a good growth area for Aberdeen in 2006. In the first quarter the group raised 15 million pounds through a C-Share issued by Aberdeen Growth Opportunities VCT.This year the group intends to actively start marketing the S shares of its Aberdeen Growth Opportunities VCT 2, which have raised 15 million pounds.(c) Citywire Financial Publishers Ltd 2007.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/citywire-funds-aberdeen-idUSNOA32771120070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>aberdeen wins guinness flight vct mandate</title></story></items>