<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:19 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> TORONTO (Hollywood Reporter) - "Little Mosque on the 
Prairie," a Canadian sitcom that debuts Tuesday, depicts 
immigrant Muslims bumping up against white locals in rural 
Saskatchewan. Zarqa Nawaz, creator and writer of the groundbreaking, 
insists she's an equal-opportunity satirist taking dead-aim at 
both Muslim and Canadian stereotypes in a post-September 11 
world. "I expect both groups will be wondering if the other finds 
the show funny," says Nawaz. There are predictable jokes about Muslim beliefs clashing 
with Canadian traditions. In one scene, a father wearing a 
kufi, or a knitted cap worn by devout Muslims, protests that 
his Canadian-born daughter wearing a revealing tank top looks 
"like a Protestant." "Don't you mean prostitute?" the daughter asks. "No, I meant a Protestant," the father replies. In another scene, a young man of Middle Eastern origins 
with a Canadian accent is heard in an airport check-in line 
telling his mother via cell phone that his father shouldn't 
think his choosing to stop being a Toronto lawyer to become an 
Imam in Saskatchewan amounts to career "suicide." "This is Allah's plan for me," the young man says in 
passing, before an arresting cop appears suddenly and tells the 
surprised lawyer that he won't be making that appointment in 
Paradise. Nawaz, a British-born Muslim and mother of four who settled 
on the Prairies with her family a decade ago, downplays the 
idea that the homegrown comedy may spark widespread 
controversy. She insists her comedy springs from a relatively uneventful 
life in multicultural North America, unlike Europe, for 
example, where relations between Muslims and the wider 
Christian community are often a powder keg. "North America should be the first place where a comedy 
like this would come about, where Muslims can be comfortable in 
their own skin and questions of Canadian identity can produce a 
sitcom," she says. To ensure it doesn't cause unforeseen offense with "Little 
Mosque on the Prairie," the government-owned Canadian 
Broadcasting Corp. (CBC) has hired an independent 
Muslim-Canadian consultant to comb through the sitcom's 
creative elements and suggest possible alterations. Kirstine Layfield, CBC executive director of network 
programming, says recent preview screenings with select Muslim 
audiences elicited encouraging results -- laughter. "Just doing the series is a risk in itself, but one the 
public broadcaster should take on if we're to help communicate 
authenticity of living in Canada," Layfield adds. Mary Darling, one of three executive producers shopping the 
Canadian comedy stateside, says a U.S. airing may help break 
down barriers between faith communities. "It won't do any harm, and maybe it can do some good," she 
says. Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/television-canada-sitcom-dc-idUSN0226952120070103</link><sectors><value><value>Television</value></value></sectors><title>canadian sitcom : allah in the family</title></story></items>