<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:13 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> LOS ANGELES (Hollywood Reporter) - Bravo has ordered a 
third season of its culinary competition series "Top Chef." In other cable news, Court TV is developing a new show 
titled "Most Dangerous," which will be part of the network's 
R.E.D. (Real. Exciting. Dramatic.) lineup. Bravo said Tuesday that it will kick off its nationwide 
casting call for Season 3 this month with cook-offs in Dallas, 
Las Vegas, Miami, New York and San Francisco. The third season 
is set to debut later this year. The second season of Bravo's "Top Chef," which features 
host Padma Lakshmi and judge Tom Colicchio, is averaging 1.2 
million total viewers season-to-date (eight episodes), up 56% 
from the first season. Season 2 continues at 10 Wednesday with 
a special 70-minute edition featuring guest appearances by Ted 
Allen (Bravo's "Queer Eye for the Straight Guy"), Debi Mazar 
(HBO's "Entourage") and chef Robert Ivan. Meanwhile, Court TV's "Most Dangerous" follows on the heels 
of the network's launch of "Most Shocking," which spotlights 
the most outrageous crimes ever caught on video. "Most 
Dangerous" will tell the stories of officers who have survived 
extremely dangerous situations through actual footage of the 
events. "Most Shocking" also airs during the R.E.D. lineup, which 
focuses on "action-packed" reality series and airs from 8-9 
weeknights. Court TV said the block, which is celebrating its 
one-year anniversary, helped give the channel its best year 
ever in primetime, with total viewers for the time period up 
16% over the same period in 2005 and the adults 18-49 delivery 
up 31% over the same period in 2005. Other series in the rotating R.E.D. lineup include "Beach 
Patrol: San Diego," "Beach Patrol: Miami Beach," "Cops," 
"S.W.A.T. USA," "Hot Pursuit" and "World's Wildest." "Most 
Dangerous" joins the block this year. Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/television-cable-dc-idUSN0335894620070103</link><sectors><value><value>Television</value></value></sectors><title>chef returns to bravo kitchen for season 3</title></story></items>