<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:10 01 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> NEW YORK (Hollywood Reporter) - Tuesday's state funeral for 
President Gerald R. Ford has been years in the making, a result 
of the wishes of Ford and his family and, in the coverage, 
years of work by TV networks. Ford's six days of memorials began Friday, when his casket 
was brought to a Palm Springs church, and continued during the 
weekend in Washington, where his body lay at state in the 
Capitol Rotunda. After Tuesday's funeral, it will be brought to 
Grand Rapids, Mich., where another service will be held and 
then interment at the president's library and museum. Even though they didn't know when it would occur, network 
TV's preparations for Ford's services were in the planning 
stages since before President Ronald Reagan's passing in 2004. 
Ford at 93 was the longest-living former president and had been 
in ill health for a while. "We've been having pool conversations about this story for 
a while now," said Phil Alongi, executive producer of NBC News 
special coverage. "This has been in the planning stages for 
years." Like such other big national events as inaugurations and 
State of the Union Addresses, a presidential funeral is covered 
by the so-called network pool that includes ABC, NBC, CBS, Fox 
News Channel, CNN and MSNBC. Each network takes responsibility 
for a portion of the event, which will take place in three 
regions of the country and in four states and the District of 
Columbia. "These logistically are very, very big projects," Alongi 
said. "This is one time when all the networks pull together." CBS is the pool network for the motorcade and Andrews Air 
Force Base, where the casket was flown to Saturday and due to 
be flown out of Tuesday. NBC is the pool for the Capitol, ABC 
for the Washington National Cathedral and Fox News Channel 
handles the pool for the initial viewing in California and the 
burial in Grand Rapids. CNN is the overall pool producer. "The assignments are done and the right people have been to 
Grand Rapids a couple of times, they've known where the cameras 
are going to be," CNN Washington bureau chief David Bohrman 
said. Planning began in earnest after Reagan's funeral in June 
2004, when executives from the networks discussed how the 
coverage went and what could be improved. Network personnel 
have gone to the Ford museum and library, where the former 
president will be buried, several times over the years to plan 
the coverage. The networks have met several times since 2004 
about the coverage of the state funeral; those calls became 
daily and more frequently after Ford died. While the networks waited until well after the family 
announced the plans Wednesday, executives said it generally was 
understood what each of the former presidents wish when their 
time comes. "We know as much as the (National) Military District and 
each presidents' library has decided to share with us," Bohrman 
said. "It's usually a lot. The planning is complex and it's in 
everybody's best interest." There haven't been many state funerals in recent years, 
with the first in 30 years for President Reagan. The last one 
was in 1973 for President Lyndon Baines Johnson. Richard M. 
Nixon declined to have a state funeral when he died in 1994. Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/television-ford-dc-idUSN2921897720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>Television</value></value></sectors><title>networks pull together for ford funeral coverage</title></story></items>