<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:55 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> LOS ANGELES (Hollywood Reporter) - "The Megan Mullally 
Show" is the first syndicated newcomer of the 2006-07 season to 
get the axe. Its syndicator, NBC Universal Domestic Television 
Distribution, told "Megan" staff Wednesday that it was stopping 
production immediately. The hourlong show, which launched in September, is 
averaging a 0.8 household rating season-to-date. Anything below 
a 1.0 is generally considered problematic. The show will remain on the air through the end of the 
month, airing a previously scheduled mix of original and repeat 
episodes. NBC Universal is planning to work with each station 
currently airing "Megan" to find "potential programming 
solutions" that fit their needs following the show's departure, 
a company spokesman said. "We are very proud of the hard work and effort that our 
staff put into the production of this show," NBC Universal said 
in a statement. "And our host, Megan Mullally, is truly one of 
the most talented people in our business. We are grateful to 
have partnered with her on the show and are appreciative for 
her tireless commitment, effort and dedication to this 
endeavor." Mullally, an Emmy-winning former star of "Will &amp; Grace," 
said a year ago that she wanted her show to draw on the best 
elements of all her favorite talk shows and hosts. "I want it to be a 'best of talk shows' talk show," she 
told the Hollywood Reporter in January. "I've always been a big 
fan of talk shows, ever since I was a kid -- (Johnny) Carson, 
Merv (Griffin) and Mike (Douglas). I think it's cool to pull 
elements from all the best shows." In announcing Mullally's talk show in June 2005, NBC 
Universal said it was confident the show would have "wide 
appeal" to the target audience of women aged 25-54 because the 
actress was "very funny, intelligent, inquisitive and ... 
passionate." Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/television-megan-dc-idUSN0343706720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Television</value></value></sectors><title>low - rated ' megan mullally ' talk show axed</title></story></items>