<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:04 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MIAMI Duke University has invited back two former students suspended after they were charged with raping a black stripper at a lacrosse team party, the school president said on Wednesday.Prosecutors dropped rape charges last month against the two students and a teammate, all of them white, after their accuser told investigators she was uncertain about crucial details. The athletes still face charges of kidnapping and sexual assault and have repeatedly said the allegations are false.On Wednesday, Duke President Richard Brodhead issued a statement saying "the right and fair thing to do" is to allow the two, Reade Seligmann and Collin Finnerty, to return to the North Carolina school for the upcoming spring semester.The third athlete, David Evans, graduated in May."Although the students still face serious charges and larger issues require Duke's collective attention, the circumstances in this case have changed substantially, and it is appropriate that the students have an opportunity to continue their education," Brodhead said.There was no immediate word whether Seligmann and Finnerty would accept the offer.Finnerty's attorney, Wade Smith, said in a televised news conference that "This announcement speaks to Duke's integrity as an institution, to its mission and to its belief in Collin Finnerty's innocence."The stripper accused the three athletes of raping her at lacrosse team party in March 2006 at an off-campus house in Durham, North Carolina.The case drew national attention, local protests and was portrayed as a symbol of racial and class division in the U.S. South. The university's lacrosse coach resigned and the school canceled the rest of the team's season.Laboratory tests found none of the defendants' DNA on the accuser. The rape charge was dropped in December because she told investigators she was uncertain whether there had been vaginal penetration with a penis -- the definition of rape in North Carolina.The North Carolina State Bar then filed an ethics complaint against District Attorney Michael Nifong, alleging he had violated ethics rules by making misleading, improper and prejudicial public statements about the evidence and the defendants.Brodhead said then that Nifong's decision to drop the rape charge cast doubt on the remaining charges, and urged him to step aside and let an independent party handle the case.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-usa-rape-lacrosse-idUSN1342730420070103</link><sectors><value><value>U.S.</value></value></sectors><title>duke university says accused athletes can return</title></story></items>