<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:46 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds details, quotes) By Jennifer KwanTORONTO Jan 3 (Reuters) - The Toronto Stock Exchange's
main index closed down more than 200 points on Wednesday
following a steep pullback in metal and oil prices, which
weighed on the broader market. The Toronto Stock Exchange S&amp;P/TSX composite index
.GSPTSE closed down 222.22 points, or 1.7 percent, at
12,701.44. Eight of the TSX index's 10 main groups retreated but the
hefty energy and materials groups, which include resources and
gold-mining shares, were the biggest losers, down 3.9 percent
and 4 percent respectively. The steep dive in energy issues was pegged to the slide in
oil, which dropped more than 4 percent to settle below $59 a
barrel, as unusually warm weather in the U.S. Northeast cut
heating-oil demand in the world's biggest energy market. Copper prices tumbled to their lowest levels since early
April, which weighed on other base metals. "The overriding reason is potential for slower growth this
year weighing on commodity markets," said Fergal Smith,
managing market strategist at Action Economics. "Then, of course, the energy sector has had to contend with
warmer weather forecasts," he added. "These are quite big moves
in percentage terms." Despite this, Smith said he does not expect a sustained
pullback. Natural gas heavyweight EnCana Corp. (ECA.TO) closed down
C$1.14, or 2 percent, at C$53.21, Suncor Energy Inc. (SU.TO)
slid C$4.41, or 4.9 percent, to C$86.61. Zinc major Teck Cominco Ltd. (TCKb.TO) sagged C$4.53, or
5.3 percent, to C$81.40, while aluminum producer Alcan Inc.
AL.TO lost C$2.38, or 4.2 percent, to close at C$53.91. "I think we're in for a sustained period of volatility that
is going to be weather related," said Rob Moss, oil and gas
analyst at Acumen Capital Partners, in Calgary. Any move by the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting
Countries to cut oil output will also be closely watched as a
turn in weather combined with a supply cut could result in a
spike in prices, he added. "Oil prices are very sensitive to those particular concerns
so we'll see how that all plays out, but it obviously has to be
managed very well." Market volume was a healthy 362 million shares worth C$6.5
billion. Decliners easily outpaced advancers 1,036 to 571. The
blue chip S&amp;P/TSX 60 index .TSE60 closed 11.49 points lower,
or 1.5 percent, at 732.66. South of the border, markets ended flat in their first
trading session of 2007 as renewed concerns about the strength
of the U.S. economy and corporate profits weighed. The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI rose 11.37 points,
or 0.1 percent, to end at 12,474.52. The Nasdaq composite index
.IXIC gained 7.87 points, or 0.3 percent, to close at
2,423.16. U.S. equity markets were closed on Tuesday for an official
day of mourning for former President Gerald Ford. ($1=$1.17 Canadian)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-canada-stocks-idUSNN0343461020070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>toronto stocks dive on energy , metals pullback</title></story></items>