<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:10 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 A criminal case against KPMG
LLP relating to alleged tax fraud has been dropped because the
accounting firm complied with terms of an agreement with the
government, federal prosecutors said on Wednesday. KPMG had agreed in August 2005 to pay $456 million, accept
an outside monitor and admit to wrongdoing in resolving a
federal investigation into questionable tax shelters. The deferred prosecution agreement expired on Dec. 31. U.S.
District Judge Loretta Preska issued an order, made public on
Wednesday, agreeing with a request by the U.S. Attorney for the
Southern District of New York to drop a criminal conspiracy
charge against KPMG. But 16 former KPMG [KPMG.UL] partners and two others still
face criminal charges accusing them of helping cheat the
government out of $2.5 billion by creating bogus tax shelters
for wealthy clients. A trial is scheduled to begin Sept. 17. "Today's dismissal of the charge reflects our commitment to
full and continuing compliance with the agreement we made with
the government," KPMG Chief Executive Timothy Flynn said in a
statement. "We regret the past activities that led to these
charges." By avoiding an indictment, KPMG may have avoided the fate
of another accountant, Arthur Andersen, which dissolved after
being indicted over its role in Enron Corp.'s 2001 collapse.
The U.S. Supreme Court in 2005 overturned Andersen's subsequent
conviction. Prosecutors have been dealt several blows in the KPMG case.
In July, U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan ruled that the
government unconstitutionally pressured KPMG to withhold
payment of legal fees on behalf of the 16 former partners. The U.S. 2nd Circuit Court of Appeals heard arguments in
November on whether Kaplan or an outside arbitrator -- as
requested by KPMG -- should decide who should pay the fees. After the case began, the U.S. Justice Department decided
to revise its policies for investigating business wrongdoing,
saying prosecutors will not be able to consider payment of
employees' legal bills -- except under rare circumstances --
when deciding whether to charge a company with a crime. At a hearing last month, Kaplan said he was likely to
reject prosecutors' request to split the defendants into two
groups for separate trials.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/crime-kpmg-idUSN0343425820070103</link><sectors><value><value>Regulatory News</value></value></sectors><title>prosecutors drop criminal case against kpmg</title></story></items>