<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:11 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts, updates comment, prices) By Ellen FreilichNEW YORK Jan 3 (Reuters) - U.S. stocks ended little
changed in their 2007 debut session  on Wednesday, as minutes
from the Federal Reserve's latest meeting renewed concerns
about the strength of the economy and corporate profits and
halted an early rally, while oil prices plunged 4 percent. Energy stocks suffered their biggest one-day fall in over a
year on the lower oil prices, with Exxon Mobil (XOM.N) and
Chevron (CVX.N) both down, but positive analyst comments
prompted a gain in the shares of Web search leader Google Inc.
(GOOG.O), which helped support the Nasdaq. U.S. government bond prices rose on Wednesday on weak
private-sector jobs data and as the minutes from the Fed's Dec.
12 policy meeting showed a central bank wary of slowing
economic growth. Gains were tempered, however, by a December
index of U.S. factory activity that came in stronger than
expected. The Fed's concern over potentially slower growth marginally
boosted investor expectations that the central bank could
consider an official interest rate cut later this year. "Stocks went from the plus column into the red after the
Fed minutes cited downside economic risks, and this helped
support bond prices as well," said Chris Rupkey, senior
financial economist at Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi in New York. DECEMBER U.S. FACTORY INDEX STRONGER THAN EXPECTED At mid-morning, news that the Institute for Supply
Management's manufacturing index climbed to 51.4, above the 50
threshold that separates expansion in the sector from
contraction, hurt Treasuries and helped stocks. But the impact of that report wore off as the day
progressed. The Dow and the Nasdaq ended the first 2007 trading session
only slightly higher, while the S&amp;P 500 dipped as a sharp
sell-off in energy shares and worries about economic growth
eclipsed Wal-Mart Stores Inc.'s (WMT.N) upbeat sales forecast
and a jump in Home Depot Inc. (HD.N) after its chief executive
officer quit. The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI rose 11.37 points,
or 0.09 percent, to finish at 12,474.52. The Nasdaq Composite Index .IXIC gained 7.87 points, or
0.33 percent, to end at 2,423.16. But the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 Index .SPX slipped 1.67
points, or 0.12 percent, to close at 1,416.63. BONDS RISE AFTER JOBS REPORT Treasuries had also rallied early in the day after a
surprise contraction in a private jobs report which hinted the
nonfarm payrolls report on Friday could prove soft. After the
data, economists at some Wall Street banks cut their forecasts
for the government's nonfarm payrolls report. Data showed that U.S. private sector employment likely
declined by 40,000 in December, the first contraction since
April 2003, according to the ADP National Employment Report. The falling oil prices also contributed to the rally in
bonds. "Falling commodity prices, especially oil, are exactly what
you see in a slowing economy, so this trend accentuated buying
of bonds," Rupkey said. Benchmark 10-year notes US10YT=RR rose 5/32 in price for
a yield of 4.66 percent from 4.68 percent late on Tuesday. DOLLAR RISES ON FACTORY DATA The U.S. dollar advanced broadly on Wednesday, hitting
two-month highs against the yen, after the Institute for Supply
Management a survey showed the U.S. factory sector expanded in
December, defying forecasts of another modest contraction. "The fact that ISM came back above 50 put the whole
soft-landing, dollar-positive scenario back in play," said
Boris Schlossberg, senior currency strategist at Forex Capital
Markets in New York. Led by strong gains against European currencies including
sterling, the euro and the Swiss franc, the dollar had its
biggest rise in around six months against a basket of six major
currencies .DXY. The euro EUR= was trading down 0.9 percent on the day at
$1.3159, its biggest one-day decline since mid-July of last
year. Meanwhile, sterling tumbled 1.2 percent to $1.9495
GBP=, its biggest one-day decline since July 2005. The dollar was up 0.5 percent at 119.35 yen JPY= after
reaching as high as 119.68 on electronic trading platform EBS. The dollar rose around 1.1 percent against the Swiss
currency, to 1.2264 francs CHF=. Oil prices plunged 4 percent to below $59 on Wednesday --
the biggest one-day percentage drop in front month crude since
a 4.78 percent drop on April 27, 2005 -- as mild weather in the
U.S. Northeast cut fuel demand in the world's biggest heating
oil market and signs emerged that investor interest in
commodities was flagging. U.S. crude CLc1 settled down $2.73 to $58.32 a barrel,
the lowest settlement since Nov. 17, before trading down to
$57.72 in after hours electronic trade. London Brent LCOc1
plunged $2.48 to $57.96 a barrel.
 ( ((Additional reporting by Emily Chasan, Chris Reese and Nick
Olivari))



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-global-idUSN0362045720070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>global markets - stocks little changed on renewed economy worries</title></story></items>