<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:32 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>SAN FRANCISCO The San Francisco Giants presented Barry Zito, the most expensive pitcher in baseball history, as a new team leader on Wednesday, but stayed silent on controversial slugger Barry Bonds.The Giants signed Zito, the 2002 American League Cy Young winner, last week to a seven-year, $126 million contract. Local media reported he would be earning nearly $5,000 a pitch as someone who plays only every four or five games.Zito talked about his leadership qualities for a National League team long divided by Bonds, whose reputation has been clouded by the BALCO steroid scandal."Half of my role here is to pitch on the field. The other half is to help everyone else be the best they can," the left-handed thrower, who was 16-10 with a 3.83 ERA in the 2006 season with the American League A's across San Francisco Bay in Oakland, told a news conference.Other team mates have privately grumbled about the team's longtime dominant pitcher Bonds, who is within striking distance of becoming the all-time Major League Baseball home-run king next season. Recent books have chronicled sometimes abrasive behavior by Bonds toward team mates.The Giants reportedly agreed last month to pay the record seven-times MVP $16 million to carry on for another season, but declined on Wednesday to discuss the player that has brought them so much joy as well as headaches."I'm not gong to say anything about the other Barry," team president Peter Magowan said when asked if the contract had been finalized.A spokesman later said the deal has not been completed. Bonds also faces legal uncertainty, as federal prosecutors are believed to be investigating whether he lied to a grand jury when he testified that he had never knowingly used steroids.UPBEAT OUTLOOKZito contrasted the other Barry with a sunny disposition, speaking at one point about "a lot of good vibes flowing around here."Magowan highlighted Zito's attributes that do not appear in the statistics on a baseball card."What I think sets Barry above so many other very skilled players are the other things he brings to the table," Magowan said."He is a combination of charisma and dedication and desire that makes him a truly special player and that's the kind of things this organization wants to be associated with on a long-term basis," he said.Magowan acknowledged that a record long-term contract posed risks, but cited Zito's work ethic, track record of not missing a start throughout his career and relatively young age of 28."Those are three factors that don't eliminate the risk but reduce it," he said.Asked about the risk of such a lucrative deal, Zito said: "I think my work ethic has led to the durability....My work ethic and determination are only going to increase."</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-baseball-zito-idUSN0343289420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>san francisco hails zito ' s arrival , silent on bonds</title></story></items>