<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:34 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TORONTO Jan 3 Canadian automakers finished
2006 with stronger sales in December, with the exception
General Motors of Canada (GM.N), which continued to lose ground
to its rivals, company figures showed on Wednesday. Industry leader GM Canada saw sales fall marginally to
36,258 vehicles during the month, as truck sales rose 2.8
percent, while car sales sagged 3.8 percent. For the year, sales at GM dropped 7.7 percent to 421,299 in
what the company termed a "transition year" as it tried to
reduce its reliance on sales incentives to attract customers. Canada's other major automakers managed to notch gains for
2006, helped by resurgent end-of year sales. DaimlerChrysler Canada DCXGn.DE had its fifth straight
monthly gain in vehicles sales as it moved 18,589 units off its
lots in December, up 26.5 percent from 14,695 sold in the same
month of 2005. The company said total vehicle sales for 2006 inched ahead
1.7 percent to 220,553 compared with 2005. Ford Motor Co. of Canada (F.N), meanwhile, notched a 3.5
percent rise in December vehicle sales to 17,191, as car sales
rose 14.7 percent, helped by stronger sales of the Focus and a
full year of sales of the Fusion. Trucks, which made up the lion's share of Ford sales,
slipped 0.1 percent. For the year, overall sales rose 8 percent
to 229,316, paced by a 25 percent increase in car sales. The industry "shot the lights out in the last half of 2006
and managed to turn what looked like a relatively bad sales
year, midway through the year, into a slightly positive
performance once the year was completed," Dennis DesRosiers,
president of DesRosiers Automotive Consulting Inc. said in a
statement. DesRosiers said total auto sales in 2006 rose 2 percent to
1.61 million units from 1.58 million in 2005, marking the
second highest sales year on record in Canada. Toyota Canada Inc. (7203.T) saw sales edge up 2.8 percent
to 12,189 vehicles December, as stronger truck sales made up
for weaker car sales at its Toyota division, while the luxury
Lexus division had the opposite experience, with stronger car
sales and a decline in trucks. For the year, Toyota's Canadian sales climbed 1.9 percent
195,780. Sales at Honda Canada Inc. (7267.T) surged 22 percent to
15,951 vehicles in December as a 27 percent jump in sales at
its Honda division offset an 8 percent drop at its Acura
division. Honda said 2006 was the "best-ever" calendar year in its
36-year history in Canada, as it sold a combined 165,985 units,
a 7 percent increase over its 2005 sales.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/autos-canada-sales-idUSN0342019120070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>canadian auto sales end year mostly stronger</title></story></items>