<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>16:51 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON U.S. drivers started the new year 
with a break at the pump as the retail price for gasoline fell 
for the first time in three weeks, dropping almost a penny a 
gallon, the government said on Wednesday. The national price for regular unleaded gasoline declined 
0.7 cent over the last week to $2.33 a gallon, but was 9.6 
cents higher than a year ago, according to the federal Energy 
Information Administration's weekly survey of service stations. Pump prices could fall more if crude oil costs continue to 
drop. U.S. oil fell $2.73, or 4.5 percent, to settle at $58.32 
a barrel on Wednesday on the New York Mercantile Exchange, as 
mild Northeast weather cut into heating oil demand. The price 
of crude accounts for about half the cost of making gasoline. The EIA, which is the Energy Department's forecasting arm, 
expects regular unleaded gasoline to average $2.40 a gallon in 
the current quarter, 6 cents higher than a year earlier. The 
agency's revised monthly forecast comes out next week. In the EIA's new weekly survey, West Coast service stations 
had the most expensive gasoline by region, up 0.2 cent to $2.58 
a gallon. Among major cities, Seattle had the highest pump 
price at $2.66 a gallon, up 1.7 cents from a week ago. By region, the cheapest gasoline was found on the Gulf 
Coast at $2.20 a gallon, down 1.3 cents from a week ago. Denver 
had the most affordable fuel among surveyed cities at $2.15 a 
gallon, unchanged from the prior week. The EIA also reported that pump prices were down a penny to 
$2.29 in Cleveland, down 0.8 cent to $2.33 in Boston, down 2.7 
cents to $2.34 in Chicago, down 0.8 cent to $2.39 in New York 
City, down 0.3 cent to $2.39 in Miami and up 0.1 cent to $2.59 
in Los Angeles, Separately, the EIA said that the price truckers pay for 
diesel fuel fell by 1.6 cents to $2.58 a gallon, up 13.8 cents 
from the same time the previous year. The West Coast had the priciest diesel, down 0.3 cent to 
$2.85 a gallon. Diesel was cheapest along the Gulf Coast, down 
1.4 cents to $2.50 a gallon.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/businesspro-energy-gasoline-price-dc-idUSN0343528620070103</link><sectors><value><value>Health, </value><value>Tech</value></value></sectors><title>us gasoline price falls first time in 3 weeks</title></story></items>