<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:53 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK The decline in the Manhattan apartment 
market seems to have been over in a New York minute in contrast 
to the sluggish U.S. housing market, according to an 
influential property report released on Wednesday. And the Manhattan market could be set for a surge in 2007, 
according to the author of the report, Jonathan Miller 
president of real estate appraisal and consultant firm, Miller 
Samuel Inc. "It would not be unreasonable to see a brisk real estate 
market in '07 based on early signs in the fourth quarter and 
the economic stimulus that we're expecting to see from bonus 
money and low unemployment," Miller said. While most of the rest of the U.S. housing market saw 
prices drop and sales fall dramatically in 2006, the New York 
City condominium and co-operative market experienced only a 
mild hiccup that lasted only a few months in the fall. "The housing bubble burst thing didn't really touch this 
market," Miller said. In the fourth-quarter, the median price of a home in 
Manhattan rose 5.1 over the year-ago period, according to the 
report, the Prudential Douglas Elliman Manhattan Market 
Overview. The number of sales during the fourth-quarter rose 15.5 
percent to 2,441 from the prior quarter and 55 percent from the 
year ago quarter. The inventory of homes shrunk 22.2 percent 
from the third quarter to 5,934 and 0.5 percent from the year 
ago quarter. Sale prices slipped 5 percent to $1,187,404 in the fourth 
quarter from $1,288,748 in the third quarter 2006, but Miller 
attributed that to seasonality. The price drop has happened in 
each of the past 16 years, he noted. The average price per square foot fell 0.4 percent to $998 
in the fourth quarter of '06. That was 5 percent below the 
third quarter's $1,050 per square foot. Meanwhile, the median sales price, in which half the units 
sold were more expensive and half were less, rose 5.1 percent 
to $799,000 from $760,000 the prior year but was 5.5 percent 
below the third quarter 2006 median sales. Mortgage rates, which have held within a narrow band, and a 
strong local economy have supported New York apartment prices. 
But the market's blessing, Miller said, has been the lack of 
speculators who bought with the intention to quickly sell. Such investors, bid up prices in other markets such as San 
Diego, California, Las Vegas, Nevada, and parts of Northern 
California and Florida, and then hurt the markets there when 
they left, driving sales down in certain markets by as 50 
percent. Dottie Herman, chief executive of residential brokerage 
company Prudential Douglas Elliman said New York apartment 
prices in 2007 could be as strong as prices seen in the boom 
times of 2004-2005 if inventory continues to decline, and Wall 
Street bonuses get spent on apartments. "If you see inventory going down any further, you're going 
see what happened in 2004," Herman said. She was referring to 
the 20-plus percent price hikes seen in much of 2004 and 2005. "There was virtually no inventory then," she said. "Right 
now it looks healthy and balanced. You've got to watch now."</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/businesspro-apartments-new-york-dc-idUSN0235383620070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>manhattan apartment downturn short - lived : report</title></story></items>