<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:52 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>VIENNA The International Atomic Energy Agency is reviewing its technical aid projects in Iran to see if any violate a new U.N. resolution imposing sanctions on Tehran over concerns it is secretly trying to build atom bombs.Diplomats said the IAEA's 35-nation board of governors could convene a special session, as early as the second half of January, but a decision would await the outcome of the review by experts in the U.N. nuclear watchdog's secretariat.The board's next scheduled meeting is March 5-9. But some Western powers want an early session, an IAEA diplomat said.Developing nations on the board oppose this as they would see it as a Western gambit to apply restrictive interpretations to the resolution's references to technical aid, a precedent they fear would damage their own nuclear-energy aspirations.The U.N. Security Council voted on December 23 to ban transfers to Iran of nuclear materials or know-how of possible use in uranium enrichment, fuel-reprocessing or heavy-water reactors. Each process can yield energy for electricity or explosives.The resolution also prohibits IAEA technical aid related to enrichment, fuel-reprocessing or heavy-water activity, while exempting projects that are for "food, agricultural, medical, safety or other humanitarian purposes".IAEA diplomats said the agency was not providing technical aid in the banned sectors to Iran or any other member state -- reflecting its covenant to both foster peaceful atomic power and deter diversions to bombmaking through regular inspections.RADIOISOTOPESBut in a December 27 letter to board members, IAEA chief Mohamed ElBaradei said the Council had "decided to restrict the scope" of nuclear technical aid to Iran and the board would need to "consider the relevant obligations" for the agency.Pending the IAEA Secretariat's evaluation, ElBaradei said he would ensure that existing technical aid would be "limited to activities authorized" by the Security Council.Of the 20-odd items of technical aid Iran has received since 1997, most involve work in radiopharmaceuticals, radioactive waste management, radioisotopes for medical care, nuclear power planning, and nuclear safety regulations.But at least one project dating to 2001, on the "feasibility of upgrading a research reactor", could well be killed off by the sanctions resolution, one senior IAEA diplomat said.A European Union diplomat said up to 11 of the projects could be in jeopardy as they could be associated with fuel production targeted by the Security Council, "but we will see what the agency (secretariat) has to say".At the last regular board meeting in November, Iran's bid for IAEA safety expertise for a heavy-water reactor was put on indefinite hold after days of haggling between developing and Western states, who originally wanted more projects slashed too."The catch now, under sanctions, is how do we interpret the technical aid projects designated as 'humanitarian'? Those who want to put the squeeze on Iran can find ways to do that," said an ambassador for a major developing nation on the IAEA board."But ElBaradei has things under control. So a special board will only raise temperatures, not cool them down which we need so at the end of the day we get a return to negotiations on a diplomatic solution (on Iran)," he said.Iran, the world's No. 4 oil exporter, says it wants nuclear fuel only for power plants, not for bombs as the United States and EU allies -- who sponsored sanctions -- suspect.But Iran bred mistrust abroad by hiding atomic research from the IAEA for 18 years, failing to satisfy agency investigators since that its goals are wholly peaceful, and ignoring a Security Council demand in July to halt enrichment work.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-iran-nuclear-iaea-idUSL0314401020070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>atom watchdog reviews iran aid amidst sanctions</title></story></items>