<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:55 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>GRAND RAPIDS, Michigan Friends and colleagues from Gerald Ford's years in official Washington gave the former U.S. president a final salute on Wednesday as a week of national memorials came to an end in his Michigan hometown."As president I relished his sound advice," said 82-year-old Jimmy Carter, who succeeded Ford in the White House.He provided "support on some of my most difficult challenges," Carter told a funeral service at Grace Episcopal Church in Grand Rapids.Carter said he could find no more fitting words than those he used in his inaugural address nearly 30 years ago after defeating Ford in the presidential election: "I want to thank my predecessor for all he did to heal our land."Donald Rumsfeld, the former defense secretary who served as Ford's White House chief of staff, said the former president was "special and needed" in a dark and dangerous time. Taking over the presidency after Richard Nixon resigned in disgrace, Rumsfeld said, was akin to stepping into a plane in mid-air knowing neither crew nor flight plan.About 400 people stood outside the stone church in bright blue weather during the service. Before that, thousands more filed past Ford's flag-draped casket at his presidential museum, some waiting hours to pay respects to a man many remembered as a long-serving local congressman who embodied simple, Midwestern virtues."I had a great respect for him. I think one of the great things about him was that he had no great ego, which is practically impossible in politics," said Anna Mae Bush, 35, who was waiting to file past the casket.Gerald Bagouckis, a 56-year-old veteran of the Vietnam War, said Ford helped him receive federal veterans' benefits when Ford represented the Grand Rapids area in Congress in 1971."He was a very good man," Bagouckis said. "I feel an affinity for him as one veteran to another."The casket containing Ford's body arrived in Grand Rapids on Tuesday afternoon as a band played the fight song from Ford's alma mater, the University of Michigan, and tens of thousands lined the streets to watch the 75-car motorcade.On Tuesday, a national day of mourning that shut U.S government offices and financial markets, more than 3,000 people -- including all three living former U.S. presidents -- attended a memorial service at the National Cathedral in Washington.Ford's grave site was at his presidential museum in Grand Rapids, on the banks of the Grand River.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-ford-funeral-idUSN0233068120070103</link><sectors><value><value>U.S., </value><value>Politics</value></value></sectors><title>carter , rumsfeld give final salute to ford</title></story></items>