<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>18:28 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TOKYO Jan 4 Japanese stocks are expected to inch
higher on Thursday, the first trading day of 2007, with investors
buying exporters such as Kyocera Corp. (6971.T) encouraged by a
softer yen, though gains may be limited as investors worry that
stocks might have risen too much. Tokyo markets are open for a half day of business on Thursday
from 09:00-11:00 a.m. (0000 GMT-0200 GMT). They were closed
Monday through Wednesday for New Year's holidays. "Trading is expected to be solid with investors buying
blue-chip stocks, led by hi-tech exporters, though gains will
likely to be capped as investors are concerned stocks might have
gone up too high too rapidly," said Hiroichi Nishi, general
manager of equity marketing at Nikko Cordial Securities. "Investors are expected to continue buying on dips, also
helped by the currency and high Chicago futures." In Chicago, Nikkei futures expiring in March 2NKc1 finished
at 17,320, 50 points above their close in Osaka JNIc1. The Nikkei is likely to move between 17,200 and 17,400, Nishi
said. On Wednesday, the U.S. dollar hit two-month highs against the
yen. The dollar was up 0.5 percent at 119.35 yen JPY= after
reaching as high as 119.68 on electronic trading platform EBS. A weaker yen is a boon to Japanese exporters as it boosts
profits when earnings from abroad are brought home. U.S. stocks ended little changed in their 2007 debut session
on Wednesday as minutes from the Federal Reserve's latest meeting
renewed concerns about the strength of the economy and corporate
profits. The Dow Jones industrial average .DJI rose 0.09 percent to
end at 12,474.52 after hitting an intraday record high. On Dec. 29, the Nikkei ended 2006 with a 6.9 percent gain for
the year, marking its fourth straight year of growth and its
longest bull run in nearly two decades. The benchmark added 0.01
percent to 17,225.83.











</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-japan-stocks-idUST15118420070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>tokyo stocks expected to start 2007 higher</title></story></items>