<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>15:41 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK U.S. manufacturing rebounded in 
December after a contraction in November, while construction 
spending fell less than expected in November, according to data 
on Wednesday suggesting a moderate economic expansion. However, the data was eclipsed by minutes from the Federal 
Reserve's December 12 policy meeting, which showed some members 
were becoming a bit anxious about the economy and a separate 
report saying private-sector employment fell in December -- the 
first time in three years. The Fed minutes released on Wednesday said that while 
inflation was the predominant concern, some members felt the 
"subdued tone" of economic data meant risks to growth had 
increased. "Several members judged that the subdued tone of some 
incoming indicators meant that the downside risks to economic 
growth in the near term had increased a little and become a bit 
more broadly based than previously thought," said the minutes. Government bond prices edged higher, while the dollar 
initially fell on the minutes. Stocks dipped after the minutes 
were released. But analysts said little weight should be attached to the 
minutes as they had been overtaken by recent data pointing to a 
resilient economy. "This Fed meeting was held before the spate of reports, 
starting with retail sales in the middle of December, that 
showed the economy looking more resilient," said Cary Leahey, 
managing director at Decision Economics in New York. Earlier, the Institute for Supply Management said its index 
of national factory activity climbed to 51.4 from 49.5 in 
November -- above the 50-threshold that separates growth from 
contraction. Analysts had forecast a reading of 49.9. "That makes the general economy look steadier and even 
firmer than it was thought to be," said Pierre Ellis, senior 
economist at Decision Economics in New York.
 INFLATION PRESSURES MODERATING Analysts were also encouraged by the decline in the ISM's 
prices paid index, which measures inflation pressures at the 
industrial level. The index fell to 47.5 from 53.5, while a 
measure of new orders climbed to 52.1 from 48.7. "The fact the price index is down is good news," said 
Robert MacIntosh, chief economist at Eaton Vance Management in 
Boston. However, for the Fed the overall index is "a small 
piece of data but everything else being equal, this would make 
them hold off from a cut." The data was seen as further confirmation that the Fed 
would probably hold interest rates unchanged well into the 
first half of 2007. The central bank raised its target for the federal funds 
rate 17 times to 5.25 percent between June 2004 and June 2006. 
Analysts expect it to start easing monetary policy sometime 
this year. The next policy-setting meeting for the Fed is 
scheduled for the end of the month. A major component of factory output appeared to stabilize 
in December according to sales figures on Wednesday. Paul 
Ballew, General Motor's chief sales analyst said the industry's 
U.S. light vehicle sales in December ran at an annual adjusted 
rate of 16.9 million, while sales for 2006 are estimated down 
about 2.3 percent to 16.7 million. Construction spending also pointed to a resilient economy. 
Spending fell 0.2 percent in November, led by an eighth 
straight drop in private residential building that more than 
offset record highs in nonresidential and public construction.
 HOUSING MARKET RESLIENT More current data showed some resilience in the U.S. 
housing market. Mortgage applications rose last week, led by 
demand for home purchase loans even as interest rates climbed 
for a fourth consecutive week, an industry trade group said. The Mortgage Bankers Association said its seasonally 
adjusted index of mortgage application activity, which includes 
both refinance and purchase loans, rose 3.6 percent last week. But analysts were cautious on the economy and pointed to a 
report that showed U.S. private sector employment contracted in 
December for the first time since April 2003. The monthly ADP National Employment Report showed private 
sector employers shed 40,000 jobs after adding 158,000 jobs in 
November. The report is based on payroll data and measures the 
change in total private sector nonfarm employment each month. "The ADP number suggests we are only starting to feel the 
impact of a slower economy," said Boris Schlossberg, senior 
currency strategist at Forex Capital Markets in New York. The ADP report hinted the government's closely watched 
nonfarm payrolls report for December, due on Friday, might 
prove soft, although economists debate the extent of the 
correlation between the two reports. "This is a big surprise. ... There is no evidence of 
systematic problems in the ADP survey," said Ian Shepherdson, 
chief U.S. economist at High Frequency economics in New York. He said his firm would cut its estimate for the Labor 
Department's report to 75,000 jobs created, from an original 
estimate of 100,000. "ADP is not perfect and is sometimes horribly wrong, but it 
is the best of a bad bunch of payroll indicators and cannot be 
completely ignored." According to the latest Reuters poll, Economists expect 
Friday's report show 110,000 nonfarm payroll jobs were added in 
December, slowing from a 132,000 gain in November.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/businesspro-usa-economy-dc-idUSN0339794520070104</link><sectors><value><value>U.S., </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>factories rebound , fed cites growth concerns</title></story></items>