<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:17 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 Law firm Wachtell, Lipton,
Rosen &amp; Katz is again at the center of a massive and
controversial CEO payout, representing the board of Home Depot
Inc. (HD.N) that gave its departing boss a $210 million
goodbye. Wachtell's work for Home Depot marks the third time in
recent years that it gave advice to boards during other large
payout controversies, including executive ousters at Morgan
Stanley (MS.N) and the New York Stock Exchange NYX.N. Home Depot confirmed Wachtell is representing its board.
Wachtell, a respected New York city corporate law firm led by
prominent takeover attorney Martin Lipton, did not respond to a
call seeking comment on Home Depot. The home improvement retailer said on Wednesday that
Chairman and Chief Executive Robert Nardelli had resigned after
a year of heavy criticism of the company's underperformance and
Nardelli's pay package. The company also found past problems
with its stock option grants. Nardelli's $210 million exit package sparked widespread
criticism and thrust Wachtell back in the CEO pay spotlight. Martin Lipton was also chairman of the legal-advisory
committee of the NYSE, where former Chairman Richard Grasso was
forced out in 2003 after a furor over his $187.5 million pay
package. Home Depot co-founder and board director Kenneth Langone
chaired the NYSE's compensation committee at the time of
Grasso's pay flap. Wachtell advised Morgan Stanley's board at the time when
its former CEO, Philip Purcell, was forced out at the end of
June 2005 in the wake of management turmoil, legal setbacks and
the loss of many top bankers and traders. Purcell was awarded a
separation payment of $44 million. Lipton gave a spirited defense of executive pay packages in
November in an interview with Reuters, insisting U.S. corporate
leaders deserve their multimillion-dollar pay packages. "Most of the high executive compensation has stemmed from
the equity incentive plans and there's no way in which they
could have created that compensation unless the company
prospered and the equity appreciated," Lipton said at the
Reuters Investment Banking Summit in New York. A founding partner of Wachtell, Lipton, Rosen &amp; Katz and
the developer of the "poison pill" takeover defense mechanism,
Lipton told Reuters at the time that such compensation levels
were needed to retain top management. Wachtell Lipton also worked with Salomon Brothers shortly
before the ouster of top executives in 1991 amid a trading
scandal.
  (Additional reporting by Megan Davies)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/homedepot-lipton-idUSN0341492320070104</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Mutual Fund Center</value></value></sectors><title>u . s . law firm again at center of big ceo payout</title></story></items>