<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:01 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 4 Tesco, Cadbury Schweppes and Coca
Cola will lead Britain's biggest food and drink companies in
launching a massive new food labeling program this month that
rivals an official campaign by the food watchdog. The coalition of 24 manufacturers and retailers will launch
the television and print campaign, costing 4 million pounds ($8
million), beginning Jan. 8, following government pressure for
action on food labels to help fight obesity. However, the advertisements will promote a labeling system
of guideline daily amounts (GDAs) of salt, sugar and fat that
goes head-to-head with the Food Standard Agency's official
campaign promoting "traffic light" labeling. The color-code system recommended by the agency proved too
much for many food manufacturers and retailers who have baulked
at slapping red "stop sign" logos on the front their colas,
chocolate bars and breakfast cereals. "This isn't just about a label, it's about a lifestyle. We
have made it simple to compare what's inside thousands of
every-day foods so you can choose what best suits your diet,"
GDA campaign director Jane Holdsworth said in a statement. Food labeling is a hot topic in the developed world with
spiraling obesity and associated illness putting huge strain on
medical services. One million British children are forecast to be obese by
2010 and the UK's creaking national health service has said it
will have difficulty coping with that rise. The campaign, which will run for 18 months and has divided
the British industry, is the biggest joint initiative ever by
the food industry with GDA labels added to nearly 40 percent of
UK retail food and drink packs, Holdsworth said. The voluntary traffic-light plan, promoted by the Food
Agency, which says it is easier to understand, has won backing
of national grocers J. Sainsbury (SBRY.L), Waitrose, Wal-Mart's
Asda (WMT.N), Marks and Spencer (MKS.L) and McCain. Tesco (TSCO.L), Britain's biggest retailer that has led the
calls for GDA food labeling, has 4,000 products already under
the plan and will be marking up thousands more. "All moves to improve labeling have to applauded. But our
scheme works best for us and our customers. It's simpler, it's
practical. You can plan your whole daily diet more easily,"
Tesco Chief Executive Terry Leahy said last year. Yet, labeling is not showing uniform signs of success. Studies in the United States have shown although half of
Americans regularly read food labels, many of them lacked the
skills to understand them.
 ($1=.5071 Pound)


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/food-labels-britain-idUSL0322343520070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>tesco leads britain ' s food label campaign against obesity</title></story></items>