<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:00 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TOKYO Jan 4 Japanese personal consumption is
stalling, but the economy itself is not at a standstill,
Economics Minister Hiroko Ota told the Nikkei newspaper in an
interview published on Thursday. "The economic recovery has not spread much from companies to
households since last summer, and consumption growth is
stalling," the business daily quoted Ota as saying. "But companies are actively hiring new graduates and seem to
have a strong sense of a labour shortage," Ota said. "I don't think the economy itself is at a standstill," she
told the Nikkei. Ota side-stepped the question of whether the government will
request a delay in voting at the Bank of Japan's policy meeting
if its board members consider hiking interest rates in the near
future. "I can only say that we'll consider what to do when the time
comes," she said. Many analysts expect the BOJ to raise its overnight call rate
target to 0.50 percent from the current 0.25 percent early this
year, and speculation is heightening that the central bank may
act at this month's meeting to be held on Jan. 17-18. The government is opposed to the BOJ raising rates too
hastily, as doing so could hurt the economy by choking off
capital spending and dampening personal consumption. Government representatives - one from the Ministry of Finance
and another from the Cabinet Office - regularly attend the BOJ's
policy-setting meetings, which are held once or twice a month.
They cannot vote on policy but can voice opinions and request
delays in voting if they feel it necessary. On fiscal policy, Ota said the government might be able to
bring forward its key fiscal reform target from the current
self-imposed deadline of fiscal 2011/12 due to rising tax
revenues. But she said the priority should be put on pursuing spending
cuts, adding that it was "disappointing" to see growing calls
among politicians that the government can restore fiscal health
without raising the consumption tax rate from the current 5
percent. Japan has vowed to balance its public budget outside debt
issuance and servicing by fiscal 2011/12, and has said it will
begin full-fledged debate this year on whether to raise the
consumption tax rate as part of steps to achieve this goal. The budget gap that needs to be filled by fiscal 2011/12 was
initially estimated at 16.5 trillion yen ($138.3 billion), but
was revised down to 9.5 trillion yen last month after taking into
account rising tax revenues and the effect of spending cuts.




</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/japan-economy-ota-idUST18718720070104</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>japan ' s ota says consumption growth stalling - paper</title></story></items>