<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:03 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON Jan 3 As the first wave of U.S.
baby boomers prepares to retire, the U.S. Treasury is hoping to
save millions of dollars by persuading them to receive their
Social Security benefits by direct deposit. The Treasury and the Federal Reserve Banks are launching a
year-long campaign to boost direct deposit use, hoping that
technology-savvy boomers would make the switch from paper
checks. The Treasury estimates that it costs 80 cents more to
process a paper benefit check than a direct deposit payment,
including postage, processing costs and claims costs related to
fraud and check replacements. In 2006 alone, more than 57,000 Treasury-issued checks --
representing $54 million in estimated value -- were forged. "About 98 percent of payment problems are related to paper
checks," said Alvina McHale, public affairs director for the
Treasury's Financial Management Service. If each of the 154 million benefit checks mailed out in
2006 had been converted to direct deposit, the federal
government would have saved around $123 million, McHale said. And with the first of the 77 million baby boomers born
between 1946 and 1964 becoming eligible to receive Social
Security benefits in 2008, when they turn 62, the check numbers
are expected to rise dramatically in coming years. In a national survey released on Wednesday, the Treasury
found that baby boomers were more than twice as likely as
today's senior citizens to bank and pay bills online. But direct deposit use among today's seniors actually
outpaces that of baby boomers. The survey found that 25 percent
of baby boomers still get paid by their employers with paper
checks, compared to only 13 percent for those aged 61 or
older. And only 18 percent of older baby boomers aged 51-60 said
they were likely to enroll in direct deposit in the next year,
compared to 30 percent of baby boomers overall. The older
boomers also were less likely to bank online, with 36 percent
using such facilities compared to 56 percent for those aged
42-50. While recent indicators show the national savings rate is
declining, the poll showed that only 16 percent of baby boomers
say all or most of their future retirement income will come
from Social Security. In comparison, twice as many (31 percent)
of existing retirees say Social Security makes up all or most
of their income. The poll also found boomers more likely to wait to collect
their Social Security retirement benefits. About 16 percent of boomers who are not yet retired plan to
start collecting Social Security at age 62, according to the
poll, compared with 34 percent of current retirees who started
collecting benefits at that age.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/usa-treasury-deposits-idUSN0344044220070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>us treasury sees savings in boomer direct deposits</title></story></items>