<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>19:26 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>ATLANTA Home Depot Inc. (HD.N) Chairman and 
Chief Executive Robert Nardelli abruptly left the company after 
a year of heavy criticism of everything from his pay package to 
the underperforming retailer's corporate governance. Nardelli, 58, will walk away with a severance package of 
about $210 million under terms of his employment. He and the 
company said in a release that his leaving was a "mutual 
decision," and Home Depot shares rose more than 2 percent. Succeeding Nardelli is Frank Blake, the 57-year-old vice 
chairman who joined Atlanta-based Home Depot in 2002. The moves 
of Nardelli and Blake, both former General Electric Co. (GE.N) 
executives, took effect on Tuesday, the retailer said. Wall Street cheered the leadership change. Many analysts 
said that although Nardelli improved operations at the world's 
largest home improvement retailer, recent unfavorable publicity 
dented confidence in Home Depot as it faces a slowing housing 
market and competition from rival Lowe's Cos. (LOW.N) "I just think it's a sign that just from a morale 
standpoint and a confidence standpoint ... from investors, from 
employees, from the market, they needed to make a change," said 
Jon Fisher, a portfolio manager at Fifth Third Asset 
Management, which owns Home Depot shares.
 BLAKE Many analysts said Blake, who played a key role in Home 
Depot's expansion into Mexico and a recent purchase in China, 
was a better consensus builder, but added his lack of retail 
experience was a drawback as store sales weaken. Blake "has never run a company or one of Home Depot's major 
operating businesses," Goldman Sachs analyst Matthew Fassler 
said in a research note. Home Depot also named Joe DeAngelo, head of its growing 
supply division geared to contractors, to the new post of chief 
operating officer and gave added duties to finance chief Carol 
Tome. The company said its board was confident about the current 
business model and long-term strategy, which includes a push to 
expand sales to contractor markets. Home Depot also said it waived the retirement age of 72 for 
directors John Clendenin, Claudio Gonzalez and Milledge A. Hart 
III and asked them to stand for re-election at the 2007 annual 
meeting.
 PILE ON Nardelli, one of the three executives in the running to 
succeed GE chief Jack Welch years ago, came to Home Depot in 
late 2000 with much fanfare, but drew mixed reviews from 
workers and some on Wall Street who expressed concern over his 
lack of retailing experience. In recent years, Nardelli drew fire from critics who 
charged his pay was out of line with company performance. Home 
Depot's stock has fallen more than 8 percent since Nardelli 
arrived, but he has earned at least $119 million in salary and 
bonus during that time. Late last year, after headlines over Nardelli's pay, the 
board's no-show at the May annual meeting, a federal probe into 
company stock-option grant practices and weakening sales and 
earnings, activist Home Depot investors became more emboldened, 
and takeover rumors sprouted. "You always had the feeling you were very unwelcome" at 
annual meetings run by Nardelli, said corporate gadfly Evelyn 
Y. Davis, who owns stock in Home Depot and many other 
companies. Ralph Whitworth, founder and principal at San Diego-based 
Relational Investors, said in mid-December that he was 
accumulating Home Depot stock and planned to nominate at least 
two directors for election at the retailer's 2007 annual 
meeting. Relational previously led a proxy battle at Sovereign 
Bancorp Inc. SOV.N and eventually took a seat on that 
company's board. Longtime shareholder Laborers' International Union of North 
America called on Home Depot to require investor approval of 
"extraordinary" benefits for officers, and said Nardelli's $210 
million severance package was "obscene." The AFL-CIO union urged the retailer to freeze all payments 
to Nardelli and seek the resignation of lead director Kenneth 
Langone, who was sued over the pay package of former New York 
Stock Exchange chief Richard Grasso. Nardelli's exit package includes cash severance of $20 
million, unvested deferred stock awards of about $77 million 
and other payments, Home Depot said. Home Depot shares, which rose 91 cents, or 2.3 percent, to 
$41.07 on Wednesday, have risen about 4 percent since early 
June, and had rallied in recent weeks on takeover speculation. Home Depot said Nardelli and Blake were unavailable to 
comment. (Additional reporting by Brad Dorfman, Jessica Wohl and Ben 
Klayman in Chicago and Patrick Fitzgiboons and Nicole Maestri 
in New York)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/businesspro-homedepot-nardelli-dc-idUSN0338394220070104</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>home depot ' s nardelli out after year of criticism</title></story></items>