<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:28 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Looking for an Atelier Versace tan chiffon evening dress, beaded bustier or catsuit worn by Grammy-winning pop star Whitney Houston? Or maybe an assortment of music awards won by her soon-to-be ex-husband Bobby Brown?Houston, one of the most celebrated pop artists of the 1980s and '90s, is being forced to sell off clothes, instruments and sound equipment to pay a debt to a warehouse storing the items.The sale, to be held at A.J. Willner Auctions on January 9, has been ordered by the New Jersey Superior Court."Whitney is selling off at auction old tour equipment that is no longer in use. Part of the proceeds will go to pay a debt owed to the storage company in keeping with court order," Houston's publicist, Nancy Seltzer, said in a statement."It is not unusual for an artist to sell off old equipment and costumes no longer needed," she said, giving no details on how much Houston owes the warehouse.Houston filed for divorce from Brown in September after 14 tumultuous years of marriage and tabloid headlines.More than 400 lots are listed for sale, including pianos, keyboards, organs, drums, designer hats, shoes and outfits from well-known names such as Giorgio Armani, Jean Paul Gaultier, Pamela Dennis, Gianni Versace and Dolce &amp; Gabbana.Among the more intriguing items are "Whitney's Throne" chair, a designer Lucite cocktail stand and a church pew.The daughter of gospel singer Cissy Houston and cousin of pop star Dionne Warwick, Houston shot to fame with her 1983 debut album and won several Grammy awards over the next decade.She also found success as an actress, appearing opposite Kevin Costner in "The Bodyguard." She and Brown also starred in television reality show "Being Bobby Brown."Houston largely retreated from performing after the release of her 1999 album, "My Love is Your Love," but surfaced alongside Brown in the tabloids, which have long reported details of their stormy marriage.In 2000, security guards in Hawaii found marijuana in the couple's luggage. Two years later Houston admitted in an ABC interview that she had used drugs in the past. Twice subsequently she has entered treatment for drugs.Brown also has had run-ins with the law, including arrests for drug possession, assault and drunken driving.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/us-houston-auction-idUSN0327627820070104</link><sectors><value><value>U.S., </value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>People</value></value></sectors><title>whitney houston to auction off clothes to pay debt</title></story></items>