<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>02:34 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK The Washington Post Co. plans to have 
its veteran editors help shape the way stories appear on the 
Web in the latest example of how top U.S. publishers are 
retooling news operations for the Internet. The Washington Post's Web site, launched more than a decade 
ago, has been a bellwether among online news publishers because 
of its early success at attracting readers online and growing 
advertising. While many newspapers beef up their Internet sites to meet 
a growing migration of readership to the Web, their print and 
Web production operations remain mostly separate divisions. The Post for example produces and packages its Web news 
with employees who work across the Potomac River from 
Washington, D.C., in Arlington, Virginia. Starting in January, print editors will "help us at the Web 
site and at the paper think smartly about more 
three-dimensional ways that you can present that news," Post 
Executive Editor Leonard Downie Jr. told Reuters. Newspaper editors have traditionally focused on assigning 
and editing articles, as well as questions of layout, such as 
where a story sits on a print page, the tenor and size of its 
headline or its relation to a photograph. Web news also requires expertise in updating breaking 
stories through the day, drawing attention to human interest or 
feature stories as well as ensuring reporters make it a 
priority to add video, audio or commentary to the page. That integration is key to the future of newspapers, as 
Internet advertising is often their fastest growing segment, 
rising 30 to 60 percent annually, depending on the publisher, 
even as print ad rates and circulation declines. "The majority of their audience is now online," said Jeff 
Jarvis, media consultant and publisher of the Buzzmachine blog. 
"They have to serve that audience where that audience is." Some have cut hundreds of jobs, narrowed their print page 
width or consolidated production plants to save costs. Others 
face shareholder pressure to improve returns or sell assets.
 NEW ROLE FOR NEWSROOMS In the meantime, many newspaper stocks are sharply 
underperforming the wider market as the pace of Internet 
earnings has yet to compensate for slower print growth. Washington Post stock has dropped 1.1 percent since the 
start of 2006, the New York Times has lost 10.4 percent and 
McClatchy Co. has shed nearly 27 percent, compared with a 14 
percent rise in the benchmark S&amp;P 500 Index. Companies aiming to bridge the gap with their own Web 
operations include USA Today publisher Gannett Co. Inc., which 
is reshaping newsrooms at nearly 90 local papers to emphasize 
Web and print news editions as equally important. More publishers anticipate similar changes to their 
operations, trying to push sometimes reluctant print staff to 
outline how they will do their jobs in the future. Dow Jones &amp; Co. is relying on its Dow Jones Newswires 
service for much of its daily coverage, focusing on exclusive 
stories and analysis for its Wall Street Journal newspaper. The 
New York Times last year said it would integrate its Web and 
print operations. "All of the desks here to varying degrees are becoming much 
more active about ... advising their reporters to call in to 
the continuous news desk or file their stories to us," said 
Neil Chase, editor at the Times' continuous news desk that 
assembles breaking news throughout the day. The Post has a similar division whose reporters and editors 
handle breaking stories for the Web, but that thinking has not 
penetrated to all levels of the print edition. "The news section sometimes can use the continuous news 
desk as a crutch rather than finding ways themselves to make 
that news happen," said Washingtonpost.com editor Liz Spayd, 
former assistant managing editor of the paper's national news 
desk. The ideal, she said, would be for section editors to 
approach their jobs as, "I'm not going to just think about like 
how it happens on the paper, but on the Web and every 
platform." She said the role of newspaper editors in building Web news 
will not take responsibility away from current Internet staff.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/industry-washingtonpost-web-dc-idUSN2925910120070104</link><sectors><value><value>Tech</value></value></sectors><title>washington post aims for closer print , web ties</title></story></items>