<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>01:57 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>SINGAPORE Jan 3 Stocks in Hong Kong, Australia
and Singapore hit record highs on Wednesday as investors bet
there was room to build on last year's rally while the
Australian dollar extended gains as dealers bought
high-yielding currencies. Gold and oil were little changed but activity was subdued
with many traders still away on holiday or awaiting minutes due
later on Wednesday of the last U.S. Federal Reserve meeting for
potential clues on the outlook for interest rates and the
dollar. Markets were also waiting for the Institute for Supply
Management's latest reading on U.S. manufacturing, due to be
released later in the day, to help determine market direction. Britain's FTSE 100 index .FTSE was seen opening down 2 to
14 points after gaining 1.45 percent on Tuesday. "Look at the liquidity in the market," said Dale Tsang,
managing director, securities trading division, Polaris Capital
(Asia) Limited in Hong Kong. "Corrections may happen here and there, but generally this
will continue to be a bull market." Hong Kong's Hang Seng index .HSI rose 1.2 percent to a
record high of 20,554.58, before retreating to end the morning
up 0.21 percent. Gains were helped by strength in heavyweight
China Mobile (0941.HK), the world's largest mobile phone
carrier, and as a market holiday in mainland China encouraged
fund inflows. Australian shares .AXJO ended 0.4 percent lower after
hitting a fifth straight record peak as investors snapped up
last year's laggard BHP Billiton Ltd. (BHP.AX) on expectations
of continued strong demand for metals. Oil companies weighed on the index late in the session as
an approaching cyclone forced some firms to halt some
production off the coast of Western Australia. In Southeast Asia, Singapore's Straits Times Index .STI
topped the 3,000 level for the first time, gaining 1.3 percent
led by banks and property stocks after the city-state posted
higher-than-expected figures for fourth-quarter economic
growth. But Thai shares .SETI tumbled nearly 3 percent to a
2-week low as investors had their first chance to react to New
Year's Eve bombings in Bangkok after market holidays. Big cap
shares suffered most on fears of new political uncertainty with
the country's biggest energy firm, PTT (PTT.BK) losing 2.9
percent. INVESTORS SEEK YIELD Japanese financial markets remained closed for the New
Year's holiday but will reopen on Thursday for a half day of
trade. The euro held firm against the U.S. dollar and the yen and
hit a near seven-year high against the Swiss franc. Sterling
and the Australian dollar extended gains against the U.S.
dollar due to strong appetite for high-yielding currencies. Sterling rose to a one-month high of $1.9749 GBP=, with
expectations of another rise in British interest rates early
this year supporting the currency. The Australian dollar firmed
to $0.7983 AUD=, its strongest level since March 2005 and
reached almost a decade high against the yen . The U.S. dollar eased to 118.71 yen JPY= from 118.85 late
in New York, but the holiday in Tokyo kept trading thin. The euro EUR= was quoted at $1.3284 in Asian trade after
rising 0.6 percent on Tuesday, breaking resistance at $1.3245
in the process. It was at 157.75 yen EURJPY=, close to
Tuesday's record peak at about 157.90. The euro also traded as
high as 1.6141 Swiss francs EURCHF=, its highest in almost
seven years. Spot gold XAU= fetched $640.40 an ounce, barely changed
from $640.10/641.10 late in London on Tuesday, when the metal
jumped to its highest in nearly a month at $640.80 on a weaker
dollar. "I think it's going to be a good quarter. There's nothing
much to say for today with the Japanese still away for a
holiday. But if you ask me where we are going for the year,
generally I will play it up," said a dealer in Singapore. "I think $540 will be a key support level. We should be
fine as long as we don't break that level and generally people
are buoyant. There's a lot of liquidity around and this points
to inflation," he said.  Oil prices were little changed just below $61 a barrel as
mild weather was forecast to persist in the United States,
reducing heating oil demand.






</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-global-idUSSP5179320070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>global markets - hk stocks hit record high , aussie dollar rules</title></story></items>