<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:27 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TOKYO Jan 4 Japanese government bond prices
plunged on Thursday, the first trading day of 2007, as investors
grew wary that the Bank of Japan may raise interest rates as
early as this month. Lead March futures extended their losing streak to a fourth
straight session, hitting their lowest levels since late October,
while benchmark 10-year yields jumped to 1-1/2-month peaks. The JGB market was closed on Jan. 1-3 and resumed trading for
a half day on Thursday. Full-day trade will resume on Friday. Market participants sold JGBs following a series of media
reports in the past week that the BOJ would discuss lifting the
overnight call rate to 0.50 percent from 0.25 percent at its Jan.
17-18 policy meeting, traders said. The Yomiuri newspaper reported on Monday that the central
bank is expected to consider raising rates as early as this
month, though a rate hike could be delayed until February or
later depending on "adjustments" among the BOJ, the government
and the ruling parties. "The market is reacting to the media reports that a January
rate hike is highly possible," said Tatsuo Ichikawa, chief JGB
strategist at ABN AMRO. Adding to the bearish sentiment, domestic share prices
extended their bull run. The Nikkei average .N225 rose 0.74
percent to finish at an eight-month closing high on Thursday. March 10-year JGB futures ended the session down 0.38 point
at 133.67 2JGBv1 after sliding to a two-month trough of 133.60. The 10-year JGB yield shot up 4 basis points to a 1-1/2-month
high of 1.715 percent JP10YTN=JBTC. The yield has jumped 15
basis points from a 10-month trough of 1.565 percent hit last
week. Despite the sharp rise in the benchmark yield, investors
remained hesitant about buying as they hoped to pick up JGBs
after BOJ rate jitters push up yields further, traders said. Also, the Ministry of Finance's auction next week of 1.9
trillion yen ($15.92 billion) in 10-year debt was keeping
investors reluctant to buy 10-year bonds, they said. "Many investors are waiting for the benchmark yield to rise
to the mid-1.7 percent level before buying," said ABM AMRO's
Ichikawa. The five-year yield rose 4.5 basis points to 1.285 percent
JP5YTN=JBTC. It hit a two-month peak of 1.290 percent earlier
in the session. The two-year yield was up 4 basis points at 0.835 percent
JP2YTN=JBTC. The 20-year yield was up 4.5 basis points at 2.105 percent
JP20YTN=JBTC after rising to a one-month peak of 2.110 percent.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/markets-japan-jgb-idUST16499720070104</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>jgbs tumble as market grows wary of jan rate rise</title></story></items>