<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:45 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LOS ANGELES (Hollywood Reporter) - Fox has pulled the plug on "The O.C," which collapsed in the ratings this season.The network said Wednesday the teen soap will end its four-season run next month. New episodes will air in the show's ultra-competitive 9-10 p.m. slot every Thursday through the series finale February 22.So far this season, the show is averaging about 4.1 million total viewers, less than half of what it garnered during its debut season, according to Nielsen Media Research. Last season it averaged 5.7 million."The O.C." got off to a promising start in August 2003, garnering plenty of buzz with its attractive cast. But at the start of Season 2, Fox moved the show to Thursday nights, where it faced an uphill battle and never recovered. Before this season began, Fox said it was cutting its order of episodes.The show, which follows a group of friends and families whose lives were changed by the arrival of an outsider (Benjamin McKenzie) to the chic California community of Newport Beach, recently saw some cast changes. Mischa Barton's character was killed off at the end of last season, and Autumn Reeser and Willa Holland came on board as regulars.The other original cast members still on board include Peter Gallagher, Kelly Rowan, Adam Brody, Melinda Clarke and Rachel Bilson.During its four seasons on the air, "The O.C." also generated buzz around the indie music featured in its episodes and spawned six soundtracks."This feels like the best time to bring the show to its close," said creator/executive producer Josh Schwartz. "Thanks to the hard work of our cast, crew and writers, we have enjoyed our best season yet, and what better time to go out than creatively on top."Reuters/Hollywood Reporter</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/us-oc-idUSN0344252420070104</link><sectors><value><value>Entertainment, </value><value>Television</value></value></sectors><title>sun setting on the o . c . next month</title></story></items>