<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:01 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds additional comments from chief executive) By Poornima GuptaDEARBORN, Michigan Jan 3 (Reuters) - Ford Motor Co.'s
(F.N) restructuring is going well and the No. 2 U.S. auto maker
will decide on the sale of its Aston Martin sports car unit
this year, Chief Executive Alan Mulally said on Wednesday. "It's going really well. It's really hard, really hard, but
it is the right thing to do," said Mulally, who took the reins
at Ford in September with a mandate to turn the struggling
company around. "The most important thing is to match the (production)
capacity to the current demand, restructure to operate
profitably," Mulally said at a media dinner, ahead of the
Detroit auto show, at Ford's Dearborn design center. Ford's third turnaround plan in five years calls for the
company to cut its work force by a third and close more than a
dozen plants. It has also raised about $25 billion in cash
through liens, bond offerings and credit lines. "We clearly are at a turning point," said Mulally, who was
hired from aircraft maker Boeing Co. "I feel more confident now
than when I arrived that we can make a viable Ford." Mark Fields, Ford's president of the Americas, said Ford
made a progress on its restructuring in 2006. "Last year, despite the numbers, was a year of incremental
progress for us," Fields said.  The company is drawing up a short list of bidders for
Aston Martin, its British premium brand. "A decision will be made this year," Mulally said of the
prospective sale. He also said the automaker continues to evaluate its brand
portfolio and did not rule out eventually selling Ford's
money-losing Jaguar luxury unit. Asked about his meeting in Tokyo last month with Toyota
Motor Corp. (7203.T) Chairman Fujio Cho, Mulally said they
discussed advanced technology and the regulatory environment
among other things for about two hours, but declined to give
details. Mulally said he admires the Japanese automaker for its
manufacturing processes and product development strategy. Asked if Ford was considering any kind of partnership with
the increasingly dominant Japanese automaker, Mulally said
there were opportunities to cooperate in technology and on free
trade agreements. "We're always looking for opportunities to collaborate on
all levels," he added. Industry analysts have speculated that Ford, which looks
set to be overtaken this year by Toyota as the No. 2 seller of
automobiles in the United States, may be interested in Toyota's
fuel-efficient hybrid engine technology. "I really want to connect with each of the manufacturers
and want to do it quickly. Because we have so many things in
common that we have to deal with," Mulally said. He said he has also met with other auto makers - including
General Motors Corp.(GM.N) and DaimlerChrysler AG DCXGn.DE
since taking over as CEO. Ford in December managed to retain its No.2 spot in the
U.S. market. Toyota had overtaken Ford in July and November
last year. Ford's overall U.S. sales, unadjusted for the number of
selling days, slipped 13 percent in December and 8 percent for
2006, partly because of lower demand for its best-selling
F-Series pickup trucks. Ford also lost $7 billion through September of last year
with further losses forecast in the October-December quarter
and beyond. By Ford's own estimate, its North American unit
will lose money until 2009 and run through $17 billion cash in
the next three years.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/ford-mulally-idUSN0344465820070104</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>update 2 - ford ceo says restructuring going well</title></story></items>