<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:28 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> The Times MACQUARIE MAY BID FOR TWO BILLION POUND EMERGENCY RADIO
BUSINESS Macquarie Communications Infrastructure Group (MCIG), a unit
of Australian bank Macquarie MBL.AX, is among the bidders for
O2's two billion pound emergency radio business Airwave. It is
believed the Airwave business would fit well with Arqiva, the UK
television and radio broadcast business in which MCIG is already
the largest shareholder with a 58.3 percent stake. The Airwave
network is made up more than 3,000 sites, about one-third of
which are shared with other operators. STANDARD LIFE WINDFALLS REMAIN UNCOLLECTED BY THOUSANDS It has emerged about 235,000 policyholders with Standard
Life have yet to claim some 90 million shares worth 272 million
pounds since the insurer demutualised in July. The group also
said a further 18 million pounds in cash payouts is yet to be
claimed by almost 20,000 people and that one policyholder from
Essex has yet to collect shares worth 138,116 pounds. The
insurer said the unclaimed shares would be kept until July 2016
after which they would most likely be used for "general
corporate purposes". Shares in the insurer have risen by about
25 percent since its flotation. BLACKSTONE SALE Blackstone is planning to sell up 40 million shares in
Southern Group, the UK's biggest operator of care homes, which
floated on the stock market in July at 225 pence per share. The
placing, which is being managed by Morgan Stanley and UBS, will
begin immediately. Southern Group runs about 600 care homes. The Daily Telegraph HIGH STREET BLIGHT FELLS TWO CHAINS The collapse of two separate retail groups -- Greeting Card
Group, the second-largest card retailer in the UK, which trades
as Cardfair and Card Warehouse, and Music Zone, the UK's third
largest music and film retailer -- have raised fears of a high
street downturn. The collapse of the two retailers into
administration puts some 3,600 jobs at risk. Music Zone, which
is private equity owned, blamed its bankers for its collapse. FLUCRUM HEDGE FUND IN BLACK FOR FIRST TIME Fulcrum Asset Management, the hedge fund set up by former
BBC chairman Gavyn Davies, has reported a profit of 8.5 million
pounds in the year to March 2006 -- its first time of making a
profit. The fund, which employs 30 people, had in the previous
period from its date of incorporation to March 2005, reported a
loss of 1.3 million pounds. DUNHUMBY PROFITS SOAR ON CLUBCARD Dunhumby has reported a 53 percent increase in turnover to
61.9 million pounds, and a 55 percent surge in pre-tax profits
to 13.1 million pounds in the year to February 2006, according
to the accounts filed at Companies House. The company, which was
founded by husband and wife team Clive Humby and Edwina Dunn,
and is behind Tesco's (TSCO.L) Clubcard, has grown tremendously
since linking up with Tesco in 1994. Last year Tesco increased
its stake in the company from 52 percent to 84 percent. The Guardian VODAFONE MOVES CLOSER TO CLINCHING INDIAN DEAL Vodafone's (VOD.L) chances of acquiring Hutchison Essar,
India's fourth largest mobile phone group with 22 million
subscribers, brightened yesterday. It emerged two of the
operator's major shareholders would be prepared to split the
company three ways -- between Vodafone, India's Essar group and
Analjit Singh, chairman of Max, the Indian private healthcare
company which owns 8.75 percent of the operator. Singh was
quoted as saying he would be prepared to play a marriage broker
between India's Essar, which partly owns the operator, and
Vodafone. Hong Kong-based Hutchison Whampoa 0013.HK, which
wants to sell some or all of its 67 percent stake in Hutchison
Essar, wants to be free to negotiate the best price for the sale
of its stake. TV FIRMS OFFERED DIGITAL HOPE TO CURB ADVERTISING'S MOVE TO
THE NET Independent Media Distribution (IMD), the UK's leading
"digital postman", which delivers a third of Britain's
television adverts to broadcasters, has said 2007 may be the
year when television companies ditch their reliance on video
tapes in a bid to stem the flow of advertising to the Internet.
IMD believes with its recent acquisition of Optimad, a dotcom
survivor, it would be able to provide a one-stop shop for
advertisers, helping them to cut the time and administration to
get commercials on air and make television just as attractive
for advertisers as the Internet. Digitising adverts will also
enable broadcasters and advertisers to adapt their adverts to
circumstances as quickly as websites do. EVOLUTEC CONSIDERS SALE AFTER DRUG IS DROPPED Evolutec, the Aim-listed drug company, said it was
considering all strategic options, including the sale of the
business after a phase II trial of rEV131 showed the compound
was ineffective in treating post-op cataract inflammation. The
company has only one compound - rEV576 - left in its pipeline. The Independent TEN HIGH STREET BRANDS THAT ARE LOOKING SERIOUSLY ZONED OUT Following the collapse of the cut-price CD retailer Music
Zone and the Greeting Card Group as well as the near collapse of
Little Chef, Susie Mesure profiles some retailers that she
believes are in danger of going belly up. These include WH Smith
(SMWH.L), whose sales are said to be in tailspin and destined to
remain so, and Woolworths WLW.L, which issued a pre-Christmas
profit warning as well as the shoe retailer Barratts, which has
been struggling for much of the past decade. BT FAVOURED FOR 300 MILLION POUND CONTRACT BT (BT.L) has been chosen as the preferred bidder for a
15-year, 300 million pound outsourcing contract by the Sandwell
Metropolitan Borough Council in the West Midlands. The telecoms
group will build a new technological centre in the process,
which will create 450 new jobs. ONE IN FOUR FIRMS PLAN FOUR PERCENT WAGE RISE A survey for the Web site, careerbuilder.com, has found more
than a quarter of firms polled plan to raise their employees'
wages by four percent. The survey found 54 percent of the
companies polled had budgeted for a three percent wage increase
while 28 percent budgeted for four percent increase or more. Prepared for Reuters by Durrants.
 </text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/press-digest-british-business-jan-idUSL0428212820070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>press digest - british business - jan 4</title></story></items>