<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>14:46 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>WASHINGTON U.S. Federal Reserve officials 
agreed at their December meeting inflation was the predominant 
concern, but some felt the "subdued tone" of economic data 
meant risks to growth had increased, minutes released on 
Wednesday show. "Several members judged that the subdued tone of some 
incoming indicators meant that the downside risks to economic 
growth in the near term had increased a little and become a bit 
more broadly based than previously thought," said the minutes 
of the Dec 12 meeting. "Nonetheless, all members agreed that the risk that 
inflation would fail to moderate as desired remained the 
predominant concern," the minutes added. U.S. Treasury debt prices and U.S. rate futures inched up, 
reflecting a view that chances of the Fed cutting interest 
rates in the first half of 2007 have increased after the 
minutes. Stocks pared gains and the dollar slipped. "The biggest change is the they are showing a little more 
anxiety about the economy," said Sam Rahman, a portfolio 
manager for Baring Asset Management Inc., in Boston. "While inflation remains a key focus, the FOMC is showing 
clearer signs that the weakening economic environment has 
raised concerns," he said. The U.S. central bank at that meeting held benchmark 
interest rates steady at 5.25 percent, renewing a warning on 
inflation but also nodding to "mixed" economic signals and a 
"substantial" housing slowdown. The minutes show one member of the policy-setting committee 
was concerned enough about growth to favor a statement saying 
monetary policy could be adjusted in either direction. The statement the Fed issued last month said only that 
additional firming -- increases in interest rates -- might be 
necessary to address risks from inflation. Participants in the policy-making Federal Open Market 
Committee meeting said the slowdown in the housing sector 
continued to weigh heavily on economic activity in the United 
States. Although there was evidence that home sales might be 
stabilizing, residential investment was likely to fall further 
in coming quarters as builders reduced inventories, officials 
felt. The housing slowdown has not spilled over significantly 
into consumer spending, but "considerable uncertainty" 
surrounding housing activity meant its impact on spending could 
eventually become more evident, especially if house prices 
decline significantly, officials said. At the same time, central bank officials said a slowdown in 
business investment and production, along with high inventories 
for automobiles and in other sectors, added to a picture of 
slowing economic expansion. All of the participants in the meeting remained concerned 
about inflation, the minutes said. "Although readings on core inflation had improved modestly 
since the spring, nearly all participants viewed core inflation 
as uncomfortably high and stressed the importance of further 
moderation," the minutes said. The FOMC saw "considerable uncertainty" regarding how much 
and how fast core inflation would recede and believed that the 
risks around the desired downward path remained to the upside.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/businesspro-usa-fed-minutes-dc-idUSTRT00019020070104</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>some at fed saw risks to growth increased : minutes</title></story></items>