<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:11 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>KAPALUA, Hawaii Adam Scott shrugged aside poor surfing conditions at Kapalua as he tried to resurrect his swing for this week's Mercedes-Benz Championship.The world number four, a keen surfer in his youth, struggled for form at last month's Target World Challenge and is determined to start the 2007 PGA Tour in the best possible way."I've surfed the last two days and the waves have not been good, and I'm not good," Scott told reporters on Wednesday as he prepared for Thursday's opening round at the Kapalua Resort."That might be a good thing. More time for me to practice, less time for surfing."The 26-year-old from Adelaide tied for second last in the Target World Challenge at Sherwood Country Club in Thousand Oaks, California after opening with rounds of 75 and 80.He experienced problems with his set-up and has worked hard to get back on track."I haven't been striking the ball like the world's number four player should but, once I get out there on Thursday and into the swing of things, I'll be fine," he said."A good range session is all I need before tomorrow."Long touted as a future world number one, Scott put behind him a 2006 campaign of several close calls with a three-shot victory at the season-ending Tour Championship two months ago.By claiming his fifth PGA Tour title, he finally convinced himself he belongs among the game's elite."If I hadn't won an event last year, it would have been very disappointing," he said."But it all came together. It just happened that I needed to put four rounds together, and that's what I didn't do earlier in the year even though I had some good results."It was a nice way to end the season and I want to carry that over into this year.Asked whether he felt he merited his number four ranking despite not yet having won a major, Scott replied: "Yeah, I think I played good enough."I believe I was the fourth-best player last year, and that my consistency proved that from last year's results. I played very well overall."Scott is scheduled to tee off at 2040 GMT with South Korea's K.J. Choi in the first pairing of Thursday's opening round.Fellow Australian Stuart Appleby, bidding for a fourth successive victory at the Mercedes-Benz Championship, tees off last with American David Toms at 2320.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/us-golf-pga-scott-idUSN0344822920070104</link><sectors><value><value>Sports</value></value></sectors><title>no bad thing surf ' s not up for scott at kapalua</title></story></items>