<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:37 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds details, changes date, company comment) By Doug Young and Sinead CarewTAIPEI/NEW YORK Jan 4 (Reuters) - SMIC (0981.HK), the
world's third-largest microchip foundry, said on Thursday it is
constantly looking for ways to boost shareholder value but would
not comment on a takeover report that drove its U.S. shares 22
percent higher. U.S shares of Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp.
(0981.HK) (SMI.N) soared on Wednesday as investors speculated
that the Chinese chip maker had been targeted by private equity
firms, Bank of America analyst Mark Fitzgerald said. But other analysts were uncertain what had driven the rally. One source familiar with the situation told Reuters that
major private equity names had approached SMIC previously, but
talks had never advanced because of management issues. "The directors of the company are always looking at strategic
and/or other opportunities to enhance shareholder value for the
company," SMIC said in a Hong Kong exchange filing. "No decision has been made about any resulting transaction.
There is no certainty that any opportunity will or will not
result in any transaction by or involving the company or its
subsidiaries." SMIC's Hong Kong shares have jumped 21 percent since the
start of the year, and rose 22 percent in New York on the first
trading day of 2007 after a four-day break. But the stock was down 2.44 percent in Hong Kong on Thursday
at HK$1.20, the same day Taiwan's Economic Daily -- without
citing sources -- reported that private equity interests intended
to make a bid for the Shanghai-based firm. Private equity firms have been investing in the chip industry
and exploring fast-growing markets like China. The firm's largest shareholders as of Nov. 30 were Shanghai
Industrial Holdings (0363.HK) with 10 percent and the city of
Shanghai with 4.7 percent, according to Reuters Research. Credit Suisse (CSGN.VX) is the next biggest shareholder with
3 percent, followed by mostly small shareholders. "Investors have seen so many private equity deals they're now
starting to shop around for what the next one could be,"
Fitzgerald said. "SMIC screens as a potential target because of
its valuation and its exposure to the Chinese market place." ON THE PROWL? Last year, a private equity consortium bought chip maker
Freescale Semiconductor, and another private equity group made a
bid for Taiwan's Advanced Semiconductor Engineering Inc.
(2311.TW) (ASX.N). Fitzgerald added that SMIC's valuation might be attractive as
it has traded close to its book value of $5 in recent months. "You could see where a financial entity might want to come in
and say we could really shake up this thing," he said. SMIC's shares closed up almost 13 percent in Hong Kong on
Wednesday after rising 9 percent on Tuesday, when the New York
Stock Exchange was closed, amid a broader rally that lifted Hong
Kong's blue-chip index to record highs. However, other analysts said they were unsure why SMIC's U.S.
shares were up. Two other sources active in Shanghai's semiconductor industry
said they had no knowledge of any recent acquisition discussions. One said any sale by Chinese government-backed entities would
be unlikely, as China -- which has heavily subsidised SMIC via
direct and indirect means -- is more interested in developing its
semiconductor industry than earning a quick profit. SMIC has reported losses in five of the last six quarters,
according to Reuters Estimates, as it was hit harder than most of
its peers during an industry downturn that has shown signs of
bottoming out. Prior to this week's rally, SMIC's shares had languished in
the nearly three years since the company raised $1.8 billion in
an initial public offering in Hong Kong and New York. Even at their current level, the stock now trades at less
than half of their IPO price of HK$2.69 per share.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/smic-shares-idUSTP14897920070104</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - top china foundry ' s us shares soar on takeover talk</title></story></items>