<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:17 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> The Financial Times DIVERSE WORKFORCE BETTER FOR BUSINESS A household survey carried out by the research company ICM
for Jobcentre Plus has found a diverse workforce is better for
business and that customers and employees will be keen to shop
and work in environments that reflect their local communities.
The survey also found though there were signs that employers
were becoming more willing to recruit staff from diverse
backgrounds or socially excluded groups, both employees and
customers thought employers could do more in this regard. FOOD LABELLING BATTLE HOTS UP Food manufacturers are expected to announce today a four
million pound advertising campaign to promote an alternative
food labelling regime -- upping their opposition to the Food
Standard Agency's "traffic light" regime of promoting healthy
eating. Under the watchdog's scheme, processed food carries
labels to identify whether products are high, medium or low in
fat, saturated fat, sugar or salt. The "traffic light" regime is
backed by J Sainsbury (SBRY.L), Waitrose, Asda (WMT.N), Marks
and Spencer (MKS.L), the Co-Op and McCain, but opposed by other
retailers including Tesco (TSCO.L) who say the scheme demonises
their brand. The food manufacturers are backed by the Food and
Drink Federation but the FSA says consumers find the industry's
labelling difficult to understand. PROPERTY AGENT CALLS TOP OF HOUSE MARKET Henry Pryor, founder of the property Web site primemove.com,
said November witnessed the beginning of an increase in the
number of home owners selling their property to move to a second
home or rented accommodation in the belief they were selling at
the top of the market. He believes this trend will make the
seasonal increase in the supply of homes on the market even more
pronounced than usual this year, leading to a downturn. David
Miles, chief economist at Morgan Stanley, had six weeks ago also
warned prices were likely to fall steeply because recent
increases had been fuelled by speculation. STEWART TIPPED TO STEP DOWN FROM STANDARD LIFE IN MAY Sir Brian Stewart is expected to step down as chairman of
Standard Life (SL.L) at the life assurer's annual meeting in
May, with his deputy Gerry Grimstone replacing him. The hint
about Sir Brian's departure came as it emerged more than 235,000
former Standard Life members had yet to claim almost 90 million
shares worth about 270 million pounds. The life assurer said
about 7,000 people were coming forward each month to claim
shares and cash from the trust. BORN-AGAIN BIKERS REV UP TRIUMPH Triumph Group reported an increase in its turnover by 23
million pounds to 200 million pounds in the year to June 30
2006, and attributed the increase partly to "Born-again bikers"
-- older customers trying to recapture the carefree spirit of
youth. The company sold 37,400 bikes compared with 31,600 the
year before. SMITHS HELD BACK BY AEROSPACE BUSINESS Smiths Group (SMIN.L), the engineering and security
detection business, whose products range from avionics to
medical syringes, underperformed the FTSE All-Share index by 16
percent over the past year largely because of concerns over its
aerospace unit. Despite a disappointing performance, some of the
group's divisions are doing well and growing in profits and
sales. In particular, its detection unit has emerged as the
world's biggest supplier of government-certified detection
technology. The company has also been chosen to supply border
systems to Russia, which wants to protect its wealthy
northwestern regions and guarantee the security of its Chinese
borders. CARD GROUP APPOINTS PWC ADMINISTRATOR Card Group, the specialist retailer behind Clinton Cards,
has collapsed into administration following poor Christmas
trading. The appointment of administrators comes after the group
unsuccessfully struggled to restructure its large store
portfolio amid a difficult climate for some retailers. The group
employs more than 2,500 staff and recorded turnover of 70
million pounds in the year to June 30, 2006. EVOLUTEC MULLS SALE AFTER DRUG FLOP The biotechnology company Evolutec EVC.L could hoist the
"for sale" sign after rEV131, its lead development drug made
from tick saliva, failed in a key trial. The drug was being
tested as a treatment for inflammation after post-cataract
surgery. SR PHARMA GRANTED RNAI PATENT Shares in SR Pharma (SPA.L) yesterday gained 1.5 pence to
hit a five-year high of 58.25 pence after the European Patent
Office granted it a key patent relating to its work in RNAi, a
booming area of biotechnology research. RNAi is thought to have
the potential to produce promising treatments for diseases such
as cancer, Aids and blindness. Prepared for Reuters by Durrants. </text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/press-digest-financial-times-jan-idUSL0428063820070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>press digest - financial times - jan 4</title></story></items>