<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>22:12 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>TOKYO Jan 4 The dollar steadied against the yen
and the euro on Thursday after rallying the previous session on
a survey that showed a surprising expansion in U.S. factory
activity in December. The dollar jumped on Wednesday after the Institute for
Supply Management (ISM) said its manufacturing index climbed to
51.4 from 49.5 in November, above the 50 threshold that
separates expansion from contraction. Analysts had forecast a
reading of 49.9.
 The data reinforced expectations for a soft-landing in the
U.S. economy and lent support to the dollar, said Kikuko Takeda,
currency strategist at Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi UFJ. "Pessimism has been receding and it seems all right to think
a soft-landing is the main scenario," said Takeda.
 The dollar was at 119.35 yen JPY= as of 0300 GMT, little
changed from the level in late U.S. trading on Wednesday, when
it rose to a 2-½   month high of 119.68 yen. The euro was nearly flat at $1.3172 EUR=, after falling
0.9 percent on Wednesday, its biggest one-day decline since
mid-July of last year. The euro was flat at 157.22 yen EURJPY=R after hitting a
record high of 158.06 yen on electronic trading platform EBS on
Wednesday. YEN ON DEFENSIVE Market players said the yen continued to look vulnerable
after also having fallen to fresh eight-year lows against
sterling GBPJPY=R and nine-year lows versus the Australian
dollar AUDJPY=R this week, dragged down by its low-yielding
status. Such falls in the yen occurred despite the possibility of
the Bank of Japan raising interest rates as early as the two-day
policy meeting that starts on Jan. 17. Even if the BOJ boosts rates this month, the yen's weak
trend is unlikely to be reversed, traders and analysts said,
adding that any subsequent hikes would probably come only
gradually. "Even if rates are raised in January or February, I think
the consensus (market) view is that any subsequent action is
only likely to be taken after the upper house elections," said
Takeda at Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi, referring to parliamentary
elections in July. Japan's Yomiuri newspaper reported on Monday that the BOJ
will likely consider raising rates as early as this month's
meeting. The Yomiuri said, however, that the decision on a rate hike
could be delayed until February or later, depending on
"adjustments" between the BOJ and the government and ruling
parties. The BOJ held rates at 0.25 percent at its policy board
meeting in December.


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/markets-forex-idUST17398320070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - dollar stalls after rallying on solid ism data</title></story></items>