<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>23:04 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Adds stocks, comment, byline) By Aiko HayashiTOKYO Jan 4 (Reuters) - The Nikkei average started 2007 by
hitting an eight-month closing high on Thursday, rising 0.74
percent, with Toyota Motor Corp. (7203.T) gaining on news that it
became one of the Big Three automakers in 2006 and other
exporters advancing on a softer yen. Tokyo markets opened the year with a half-day of trading on
Thursday. They were closed from Monday to Wednesday for New Year
holidays. "The Nikkei is up following solid growth in U.S. and European
markets during our market holidays," said Tsuyoshi Segawa, an
equity strategist at Shinko Securities. The yen has been getting softer since the end of last year
and market participants are tending to focus on promising stocks
for the year such as Toyota, he added. Toyota's shares hit a record high of 8,140 yen before closing
at 8,090 yen, up 1.6 percent. The Nikkei finished up 127.84 points at 17,353.67, the
highest close since April 21. The broader TOPIX index .TOPX
rose 1.06 percent to 1,698.95, the highest finish since May 11. Segawa said gains may be limited into next week, however, as
investors are concerned that stocks may have risen too far. Trade volume picked up with 1.06 billion shares changing
hands on the first section, the highest morning total in two
weeks. Advancing shares outnumbered declining ones by a ratio of
more than four to one. TOYOTA HIGHER, OIL STOCKS DOWN Shares of Toyota gained after news that its sales rose more
than 16 percent in the United States in December, ousting
DaimlerChrysler DCXGn.DE to become one of the Big Three
automakers in 2006. Investors were also encouraged to buy Toyota and other
automakers with the dollar trading near a 12-week high versus the
yen. Honda Motor Co. Ltd. (7267.T) gained 0.9 percent to 4,740
yen and Nissan Motor Co. Ltd. (7201.T) added 1.5 percent to 1,454
yen. A weaker yen is a boon to Japanese exporters as it boosts
profits when earnings from abroad are brought home. The dollar was around 119.36 yen JPY=. Shares of Idemitsu Kosan Co. Ltd. (5019.T), Japan's
third-largest oil refiner, and other oil-related shares were down
after U.S. crude oil prices tumbled on Wednesday due to mild
weather in the U.S. Northeast. Idemitsu fell 3.1 percent to 11,610 yen, Japan Petroleum
Exploration Co. Ltd. (1662.T) shed 1.8 percent to 6,950 yen, and
Nippon Mining Holdings Inc. 5016.T gave up 1.3 percent to 845
yen. NTT DoCoMo Inc. (9437.T) was up 2.1 percent at 192,000 yen
after the Nikkei business daily said Japan's largest mobile
operator will keep initial investment on its so-called super 3G
network down to 100-200 billion yen ($838 million-$1.68 billion),
which could enable DoCoMo to cut fees and help it retain users.
[ID:nT142263] Shares of Pigeon Corp. (7956.T), Japan's top baby care goods
maker, rose 2.6 percent to 2,140 yen after government data on
Monday showed Japan was expected to report about 1,086,000 babies
born in 2006, the first year-on-year rise in six years. Pigeon rival Combi Corp. 7935.T added 0.7 percent to 732
yen.













</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/markets-japan-stocks-idUST15416420070104</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets</value></value></sectors><title>nikkei starts new year at 8 - month closing high</title></story></items>