<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>20:18 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>SINGAPORE Growth in Singapore's economy in the 
fourth quarter was higher than expected at an annualized rate 
of 7.6 percent thanks to strong year-end demand for the 
country's manufactured goods. The seasonally adjusted advance fourth quarter figures, 
based largely on data from October and November, beat the 
median analysts' forecast in a Reuters poll of 6.2 percent and 
was faster than the revised 5.6 percent pace in the third 
quarter. "The Singapore economy continued to grow at a healthy 
pace," the Ministry of Trade and Industry said in a statement 
on Wednesday. Singapore's trade-dependent economy has benefited from 
three years of strong global growth, with a robust U.S. economy 
fuelling demand for the city-state's manufactured goods and 
high oil prices sparking a surge in output in its shipyards. Singapore has, by some measures, the world's busiest port 
and is home to two of the world's biggest oil rig 
manufacturers. But many analysts expect growth to moderate this year, 
reflecting slower growth in the United States. "I expect growth to moderate to 5.6 percent in 2007 because 
of a slight softening of consumer demand in the United States 
especially in the first half of the year," said Chua Hak Bin, 
an economist at Citigroup. The Reuters poll was conducted before a New Year's Eve 
message on Sunday from Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong, in which 
he said full-year growth reached 7.7 percent, around the middle 
of the 7.5 to 8 percent range forecast by the government. Growth in 2007 would slow to between 4 percent and 6 
percent, Lee said. Strong growth in 2006 has helped send the Singapore dollar 
SGD= to its highest level against the U.S. dollar in nearly a 
decade and the Singapore stock market .STI to record highs. The government has made a big effort to diversify the 
economy in the face of competition from low-cost countries such 
as China and Vietnam, spending billions to develop a biotech 
pipeline and promoting everything from private banking to 
education to tourism. Two huge casinos set to open by 2010 are expected to help 
double tourist arrivals to 17 million a year and triple tourism 
receipts to S$30 billion ($19.6 billion) by 2015. Economists say the formula has helped Singapore reduce some 
of its dependence on tech exports, long the lifeline of its 
economic expansion. "The broad-based growth in 2006 was a reflection of the 
healthy global economy which is ultimately key for Singapore," 
said David Cohen, an economist at Action Economics. "We saw the 
long-awaited turnaround in construction and services remain 
healthy as well." The island-state drew a record number of tourists in 2006 
and created its highest number of new jobs ever.
 SLOWER GROWTH Solid end-year output in the manufacturing sector, which 
makes up about a quarter of gross domestic product (GDP), gave 
a big boost to the economy in the fourth quarter. Gross domestic product (GDP) grew 5.9 percent in the 
quarter from a year earlier, compared with expectations of a 
5.5 percent expansion and following a revised 7.0 percent 
growth in the third quarter. Most analysts have forecast slower, albeit still healthy, 
growth this year, with regional and domestic demand helping to 
offset any big slowdown in the United States. However, in Singapore's property sector some high-end homes 
are selling at prices not seen since before the financial 
crisis in 1997/98, and wages in certain sectors are jumping 
higher. Against that background, Singapore's central bank is 
expected to maintain its policy of a gradual, modest 
appreciation in the Singapore dollar SGD=. The central bank 
conducts monetary policy through the currency rather than 
interest rates. After Wednesday's data, the Singapore dollar was largely 
unchanged at 1.5304/09 per US dollar. (Additional reporting by Saeed Azhar and Doreen Siow)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/businesspro-singapore-economy-dc-idUSSIN15122320070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>singapore ' s q4 gdp beats expectations</title></story></items>