<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:15 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text> (Recasts, adds details)HONG KONG Jan 4 (Reuters) - SABMiller Plc's (SAB.L) Chinese
venture plans to pay US$320 million to buy the leading brewer in
the country's southwest, part of an acquisition spree in the
world's largest market for beer. CR Snow, a venture between SABMiller and beverage-to-retail
giant China Resources Enterprise Ltd. (0291.HK), intends to pay
2.5 billion yuan (US$320 million) for Blue Sword, which owns part
of 14 breweries sprinkled across Sichuan province and all of a
brewery in Guizhou. The firm, the current market leader, intends to complete the
acquisition of those assets -- which collectively posted a 40
percent jump in unaudited net profit to US$12.4 million in 2005
-- in 2007's first quarter, China Resources and SABMiller said in
statements on Thursday. "This acquisition further demonstrates CR Snow's commitment
to invest in prominent local brands which not only complements
our national branding strategy but strengthens our leading
positions throughout regional markets," said Andre Parker,
managing director of SABMiller Africa and Asia. Blue Sword's 14 breweries in Sichuan can produce about 14
million hectolitres annually and the company is expanding to add
some 1.6 million hectolitres of capacity, SABMiller said. (For a full statement, please click here) SABMiller expects its Chinese beer Snow to become the group's
biggest brand in 2006 and one of the world's top four beers, but
executives concede that expanding profits will take time because
a 640 ml bottle can sell for as little as the equivalent of 12
U.S. cents. CR Snow now accounts for nearly a fifth of SABMiller's global
beer volumes but less than 5 percent of profits. That venture vies with local leader Tsingtao Brewery Co. Ltd.
(600600.SS) (0168.HK) and ahead of foreign rivals Anheuser-Busch
(BUD.N) and InBev INTB.BR, in a market that is growing at up to
10 percent annually. Analysts estimate Snow volumes could have hit 26-27 million
hectolitres for 2006, ahead of Miller Lite, which had volumes of
22 million in 2005, and probably behind only Budweiser, Brazil's
Skol and Mexican beer Corona in global rankings. Much of SABMiller's growth in China have come from takeovers
engineered alongside partner China Resources: last year, the pair
bought breweries in northern China's Shanxi province and Inner
Mongolia, among others. Their venture commands about 14.9 percent of China's market,
exceeding Tsingtao's 13.9 percent share at the end of June 2006. China Resources shares leapt 10 percent on Wednesday to
HK$24.70 ahead of the announcement, outperforming the market's
0.51 percent rally to a life's high. The stock was trading 0.2
percent higher on Thursday.
 ($1=7.813 Yuan)



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/chinaresources-acquisition-idUSHKG17215520070104</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A</value></value></sectors><title>update 1 - sabmiller ' s china jv to buy brewer for us $ 320 mln</title></story></items>