<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>04:46 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>LONDON Jan 3 European shares shrugged off
weaker mining stocks on Wednesday to hover at near six-year
highs in the absence of overnight leads from Wall Street and
Japan. Among major movers, CSR (CSR.L) tumbled after it was named
at the centre of a patent infringement case, while Husqvarna
(HUSQb.ST) gained after its biggest shareholder rejected a bid
approach.  At 0931 GMT, the FTSEurofirst 300 index of top European
shares .FTEU3 was up 0.1 percent at its highest level since
February 2001.  Among national indexes, Britain's FTSE 100 .FTSE,
Germany's DAX .GDAXI and France's CAC 40 .FCHI all hovered
around the unchanged mark. "When Wall Street comes in, it will be interesting to see if
European shares can hold on to their gains," said Mike Lenhoff,
chief strategist at Brewin Dolphin. "We've had four really good years on the trot and some sort
of consolidation could be due, though it may not come until
after the first quarter." Japanese markets were closed for the New Year break and U.S.
stock markets were shut on Tuesday to mark the death of former
president Gerald Ford.  U.S. manufacturing data was scheduled for release at 1500
GMT with the minutes from the Federal Reserve's Open Markets
Committee December meeting due at 1900 GMT.
 MINERS DROP  Mining stocks capped the European market's gains, with
Antofagasta (ANTO.L) down 2.7 percent, while Rio Tinto (RIO.L)
fell 2.1 percent and BHP Billiton (BLT.L) dropped 1.8 percent
after copper prices tumbled. On the downside, shares in British bluetooth specialist CSR
(CSR.L) fell 5.5 percent after it was named at the centre of a
patent infringement case brought against Nokia (NOK1V.HE),
Samsung Electronics (000830.KS) and Matsushita (6752.T). Elsewhere, Husqvarna added 2.8 percent after Investor AB
(INVEb.ST) rejected a bid approach for the lawnmower and
chainsaw maker.






</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-europe-shares-open-idUSL0311214520070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>european shares hover near six - yr high , miners fall</title></story></items>