<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>06:00 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>NEW YORK Jan 3 Confidence among U.S. workers
decreased in December on lower job satisfaction and heightened
job loss concerns, a survey released on Wednesday showed. The Hudson Employment Index, a measure of U.S. work force
confidence in the labor market, fell to 102.7 in December from
105.3 in November, recruiting firm Hudson said in a statement.
The reading in December 2005 was 103.4 and the 2006 average was
103.7. "Despite the decline, hiring expectations held steady and
December's index was generally in line with readings throughout
the second half of the year," the firm said. The survey showed the proportion of workers who are happy
with their jobs fell two percentage points to 73, and those
worried about losing their jobs were up 1 percent to 18. Thirty percent of those surveyed expect hiring in their
workplace and 15 percent say they expect layoffs. "Finding a new job tops many workers' new year's
resolutions," Steve Wolfe, senior vice president at Hudson,
said in the statement. "Increased job dissatisfaction, coupled with extremely low
unemployment, suggests many workers are poised to explore new
career options in 2007," he added. The results were based on a national telephone survey of
9,288 working Americans during December and has a margin of
error of plus or minus 1 percentage point. The data in the
survey is compiled each month by Rasmussen Reports, LLC, an
independent research firm. The employment index comes before the government's monthly
labor market report on Friday, which is expected to show the
U.S. economy added 110,000 new jobs in December, down from
132,000 in November, according to a Reuters survey. The
unemployment rate is expected to hold at 4.5 percent.



</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/usa-economy-workforce-idUSN0234308920070103</link><sectors><value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>u . s . work force sentiment falls in december - hudson</title></story></items>