<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>17:31 02 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>MIAMI Estranged business partners of the 
Seminole Tribe of Florida claim in a lawsuit that the $965 
million takeover of the Hard Rock Cafe International USA agreed 
last month with Britain's Rank Group Plc (RNK.L) was rigged. The Cordish Co., a prominent Baltimore developer that 
helped build the tribe's two Seminole Hard Rock casinos in 
Florida, and an affiliate said in a lawsuit that the tribe and 
Hard Rock had colluded to ensure the Seminoles won an auction 
for the international chain of music-themed restaurants. The lawsuit filed on Friday in a Fort Lauderdale, Florida, 
court alleges that leaders of the Seminole's gambling business 
met with Hard Rock executives to prepare offers months before 
Rank last July announced it wanted to sell the Hard Rock Cafe 
International restaurants, hotels and entertainment venues. "Defendants participated in collusion and bid rigging with 
respect to offers to purchase Hard Rock from Rank," the lawsuit 
said. Lawyers for Cordish said their executives and bankers had 
been repeatedly refused offering documents for the auction and 
been barred from participating in the deal. The lawsuit also said Cordish had made an all-cash offer to 
Rank for Hard Rock in 2005 and that the Hard Rock's managers 
had been fearful of dismissal during any Cordish takeover. 
Senior managers will remain after the Seminole transaction. The lawsuit named as defendants Hard Rock Cafe 
International (USA) Inc., the unit's chief executive, Hamish 
Dodds, and Seminole Hard Rock Entertainment Inc., and also 
asked for unspecified financial damages. A spokesman for the Seminole tribe in Hollywood, Florida, 
was not immediately available to comment on the allegations and 
the lawsuit. A spokesman for Hard Rock declined to comment. Rank's shareholders were expected to vote on Monday on the 
Hard Rock deal, which will leave Rank as a pure gambling group 
and give the native American Seminoles an extensive, global 
platform for adding casinos and hotels outside Florida. The Seminoles, who number about 3,300 and live in Florida 
reservations, said on December 7 in announcing the deal that 
they had beat out 70 other bidders for the Hard Rock 
properties. Some analysts criticized the $965 million (490 million 
pound) purchase price as too low. Rank shares have fallen 
sharply since the Hard Rock deal was announced and now trade 
around 236 pence, in comparison to a year's high of 304 pence. Cordish and the Seminole Tribe are already locked in rival 
lawsuits arising from their partnership in the highly 
profitable Seminole Hard Rock casinos opened in Florida's Tampa 
and Hollywood in 2004.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/businesspro-hardrock-seminole-dc-idUSN0233814920070103</link><sectors><value><value>M&amp;A, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>florida tribe sued over hard rock takeover</title></story></items>