<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>05:04 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>   (Changes dateline, byline, adds quotes, updates prices) By Veronica Brown LONDON, Jan 3 The euro hit a record peak against
the yen for the fourth time in a week on Wednesday as the hunt
for yield dominated sentiment, while dollar watchers awaited
data that could give further insight on the direction of
interest rates. Carry plays, using low-yielding currencies such as the yen
to fund purchases of units with more attractive interest rates,
were the major factor behind the euro's pulse higher, analysts
said. "What we're seeing on euro/yen is pretty much a continuation
of the themes from the end of last year -- the theme of carry is
still very much in place," BNP Paribas senior currency
strategist Ian Stannard said. By 0851 GMT, the euro EURJPY= had hit a record peak of 158
according to Reuters data, with technical analysts looking for
the pair to break 160/161 yen in coming weeks. The single European currency was a touch lower on the day
against the dollar at $1.3262 EUR=, having hit a peak of
$1.3290 earlier. It also rose to 1.6141 Swiss francs EURCHF= -- the
strongest level in almost seven years. The number of unemployed people in Germany fell by a much
bigger than expected 108,000 in seasonally adjusted terms in
December, Federal Labour Office figures showed. The dollar firmed against the yen due to pressure from the
euro on the Japanese currency, rising 0.2 percent to 119.14 yen
JPY=, with a holiday in Tokyo keeping liquidity thin.
 FOMC MINUTES, U.S. DATA DUE Looking ahead, minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's
latest rate-setting meeting were seen casting light on current
thinking for the rate outlook, with analysts widely expecting
that the next move in U.S. borrowing costs will be a cut. Fed officials have been talking tough on inflation even as
the market wagered on rate cuts and dollar bears will be looking
for any hint of a softer tone. The Institute for Supply Management's December reading on
the U.S. manufacturing sector is also due, while Friday brings
the non-farm payrolls report for December. A reading below 50 in the ISM index, which dipped below the
boom-or-bust level for the first time in three-and-a-half years
in November, would reinforce concerns about an economic
slowdown. "The ISM is going to be really key at this stage. Last month
it dipped below 50 -- the market seems to be expecting it to
bounce back but we're quite sceptical. A print below 50 will put
the dollar back under pressure," BNP's Stannard said. Other U.S. data due on Wednesday includes the ADP December
employment report, often seen as a precursor to Friday's
payrolls data. 
 CARRY STILL KING Sterling and the Australian dollar benefited alongside the
euro, extending recent gains as carry trades targeting
high-yielders dominated activity. "Arguably the market enters 2007 very long the carry trade,
with risk appetite strong and little incentive to fight the low
volatility rallies in many high yielding currencies. We are not
brave enough to recommend going against the carry trade just
yet," ING analyst Chris Turner said in a note to clients. The European Central Bank is expected to raise borrowing
costs to 3.75 percent in coming months from the current 3.5. By
contrast, the next move on U.S. interest rates is likely to be a
cut from 5.25 percent after a steady policy in recent months. Japanese rates are seen rising at a very gradual pace from
0.25 percent -- maintaining the euro's yield advantage. The Australian dollar firmed to $0.7983 AUD=, its
strongest level since March 2005. A move above $0.7989 would
take the Aussie dollar to its highest since Feb. 2004. It rose
to 94.86 yen AUDJPY=, its highest in more than nine years. Sterling hit a one-month high of $1.9751 GBP=, with talk
of another rise in British interest rates to 5.25 percent early
this year helping it outperform in recent months. The pound also
set an eight-year peak 234.77 GBPJPY=. 


</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/markets-forex-idUSL039802620070103</link><sectors></sectors><title>forex - hunt for yield lifts euro to fresh peak vs yen</title></story></items>