<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>06:16 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>PARIS Wall Street looked set to start 2007 on an upbeat note on Wednesday as a new dip in oil quelled inflation worries, but investors awaited a batch of economic reports for clues on the health of the world's biggest economy.The macroeconomic picture will probably drive sentiment, with data on construction spending and manufacturing activity due at 1500 GMT, followed by the publication of the minutes of the last Federal Reserve's interest rate setting meeting at 1900 GMT.This, and a keenly awaited report on non-farm payrolls on Friday, will help investors assess the scope of an economic slowdown and its likely impact on corporate earnings growth."Even though the U.S. economic slowdown is not blatant, it shows mainly in the property and manufacturing sectors," said Valerie Plagnol, economist at French broker CM-CIC Securities.At 1045 GMT, U.S. stock futures pointed to opening gains of 0.6 percent to 0.9 percent for the three main indexes SPc1 DJc1 NDc1. Markets were closed on Tuesday to observe a national day of mourning for former U.S. President Gerald Ford.U.S. shares may get an additional fillip from their European counterparts, which on Tuesday shrugged off weaker mining stocks to hover near six-year highs.On Friday, the Dow Jones industrial average .DJI closed 0.3 percent lower but finished 2006 near its lifetime high, while the broad S&amp;P Index .SPX shed 0.5 percent.Lower oil prices will likely support sentiment, though they may put pressure on some energy stocks. Oil fell toward $60 a barrel as mild weather in the U.S. Northeast undermined demand for fuel in the world's biggest heating oil market.Corporate news was scarce as many market players were still on holiday, while the earnings reporting season is not due to start until the second half of the month.Standard &amp; Poor's estimated on Friday that fourth-quarter S&amp;P 500 operating earnings will be up 9.4 percent from the fourth quarter 2005, breaking a long streak of double-digit increases.Wal-Mart Stores (WMT.N) shares may be in focus, after The Wall Street Journal reported it would start moving many of its 1.3 million workers from predictable shifts to a system based on how many customers are in stores at a given time.</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/03/us-markets-stocks-us-europe-idUSL0312770120070103</link><sectors><value><value>Asian Markets, </value><value>Bonds</value></value></sectors><title>wall street seen opening the year higher</title></story></items>