<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items><story><date>21:24 03 January 2007 (UTC)</date><text>SYDNEY Australian energy retailer AGL Energy Ltd. AGK.AX said it has approached Origin Energy Ltd. (ORG.AX) about a potential A$13 billion ($10 billion) tie-up to create the country's biggest gas and electricity supplier.AGL said on Thursday that the merger was based on a "nil premium scrip" basis, which meant neither company would pay a premium to gain control of the combined entity.The news sent AGL's shares up over 4.6 percent to A$16.57 by 0129 GMT. But Origin, whose shares have risen over 10 percent in the past month as takeover speculation grew, fell as much as 3.5 percent on disappointment that there would be no higher offer.Analysts said a merger of the two companies would create significant cost savings and scale benefits, but stringent requirements laid down by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) could scuttle the deal."They could try to satisfy the ACCC by selling off some of their business in some states but they would have to divest a significant amount of assets and one would have to ask how they are going to achieve the synergies with these sizeable divestments," said Paul Johnston, an analyst at Commsec Ltd.A combined entity would have a 49 percent market share of retail customers on Australia's east coast, with a significant overlap in Victoria state, where AGL and Origin would control more than two-thirds of the market.Analysts said other factors that could also break the deal included whether AGL's chief Paul Anthony or his Origin counterpart Grant King, would head the new group.Origin confirmed the merger approach, which it said was unsolicited and that it was still evaluating the proposal. The Melbourne-based company added that the proposal was only indicative and preliminary, and that it was not at present in any talks with AGL."Essentially what they are trying to say is AGL could launch a hostile bid, if they want to. There is no conversation between parties. That means they are still long way off before it (the deal) happens," said Albert Hung, chief investment officer with Alleron Investment Management.The plan maintains the pace of merger and acquisition activity in Australia, which jumped to a record US$171 billion in announced deals in 2006, according to Thomson Financial, aided by a surge in private equity takeovers.COMPLEMENTARY PROFILESThe Australian power sector has seen a flurry of takeover activity in the past year as companies compete to grow their infrastructure portfolios in the increasingly competitive market and as the Victorian state government embarks on a privatization policy for its energy assets.A combined AGL-Origin group would have more than 6 million customers, a controlling interest in New Zealand's largest power generator and retailer Contact Energy (CEN.NZ), and a collection of power plants and oil and gas fields across Australia.AGL's Managing Director Paul Anthony said in a statement that AGL has for some months assessed the benefits of combining the two entities, adding there was a "compelling case" to merge due to the complementary business profiles of each company.Combining the two businesses would unlock significant economic and financial benefits, including advancing the monetization of Origin's gas reserves, reducing AGL's need to acquire gas reserves and allow for a significant reduction in duplicated operating costs.In October last year, AGL sold A$6 billion worth of its infrastructure assets to Alinta AAN.AX, while maintaining its retailing and generating assets, in exchange for one-third of Alinta's Western Australian retail and co-generation business.The Australian Stock Exchange queried Origin last month about its rising share price after media reports that the company could face a bid.Origin said then it was not aware of any information that had not been announced which, if known, could explain trading in its shares.($1=1.26 Australian Dollar)</text><link>http://www.reuters.com/article/2007/01/04/us-origin-agl-idUSSYD13949520070104</link><sectors></sectors><title>agl proposes a $ 13 billion tie - up with origin</title></story></items>